When you love someone, you've gotta trust them.
وقتي کسي رو دوست داري . بايد بهش اعتماد کني
There's no other way.
. راه ديه اي نيست
You've got to give them the key to everything that's yours.
بايد کليد هر يزي رو که متعلق به توست بهش بدي
Otherwise, what's the point?
ورنه، ه امتيازي داره؟
And, for a while, I believed that's the kind of love I had.
و، براي مدتي، باور داشتم که نين عشقي رو دارم
Before I ever ran a casino, or got myself blown up...
،قبل ازاينکه کازينو رو راه بندازم ... يا خودم رو نابود کنم
Ace Rothstein was a hell of a handicapper, I can tell you that.
ايس راستين بهترين بود . ميتونم اينو بهتون بم
I was so good that whenever I bet, I could change the odds...
من اونقدر در شرط بندي خوب بودم که از هر فرصتي استفاده ميکردم
for every bookmaker in the country.
روبروي هر شرط بندي در سرتاسر کشور
I'm serious, I had it down so cold...
،جدي ميم ... من اين کار رو اونقدر خونسرد انجام مي دادم که
that I was given paradise on earth.
بهشت روي زمين رو . به من دادن
I was given one of the biggest casinos in Las Vegas to run, the Tangiers...
اداره يکي از بزر ترين کازينو هايي ... لاس واس رو به من دادن، تو تنجير
by the only kind of guys that can actually get you that kind of money...
فقط با وجود يک سري افراد ميشه ... نين ولي رو درآورد
$62,700,000.
$62, 700,000.
I don't know all the details.
من تمام جزييات رو نمي دونم
Nobody knew all the details, but it should've been perfect.
،هي کسي از تموم جزييات خبر نداره . ولي بايد کامل بوده باشه
I mean, he had me, Nicky Santoro, his best friend, watching his ass...
منظورم اينه که، اون منو داشت، نيکي سانتورو ... بهترين دوستش، که مواظب کونش بود
and he had, Ginger, the woman he loved, on his arm.
و اون، جينجر رو داشت زني که تو آغوشش بود
But in the end, we fucked it all up.
ولي درآخر از بين برديمش
It should've been so sweet too.
. بايد خيلي شيرين هم بوده باشه
But it turned out to be the last time that street guys like us...
ولي اين باعث شد که آخرين باري باشه ... که افراد خيابوني مثل ما
were ever given anything that fuckin' valuable again.
. ول اين نين زافي رو بدست بياورند
At that time, Vegas was a place where millions of suckers...
در اون زمان، لاس واس جايي بود که ... ميليون ها احمق
flew in every year on their own nickel...
هر سال به اونجا مي اومدن ... با ول هاي فراوون
and left behind about a billion dollars.
و شت سرشون بيليون ها دلار جا ميذاشتن
But at night, you couldn't see the desert that surrounds Las Vegas.
ولي در شب، نميتونيد ببينيد بياباني رو که لاس واس رو احاطه کرده
But it's in the desert where lots of the town's problems are solved.
ولي در همين بيابانه که بسياري از مشکلات شهرها حل مي شه
Got a lot of holes in the desert...
سوراخ هاي زيادي ... در اين بيابان وجود داره
and a lot of problems are buried in those holes.
و مشکلات زيادي که در اين سوراخ ها به خاک سرده ميشه
Except you gotta do it right.
. اين کارو بايد درست انجام بدي
I mean, you gotta have the hole already dug...
منظورم اينه که بايد ودال رو کنده باشي
before you show up with a package in the trunk.
قبل از اينکه با يه مدون تو صندوق عقب يدات بشه
Otherwise, you're talking about a half hour or 45 minutes of diggin'.
تو داري راجع به نيم ساعت يا 45 دقيقه حفر کردن صحبت ميکني
And who knows who's gonna be comin' along in that time?
و ه کسي ميدونه که کي ميخواد تو اين زمان وارد بشه؟
Before you know it, you gotta dig a few more holes.
قبل از اينکه بفهمي . بايد ال هاي بيشتري رو کنده باشي
You could be there all fuckin' night.
تا بتوني تمام شب رو بموني
Who could resist?
ه کسي مي تونه مقاومت کنه؟
Anywhere else in the country I was a bookie, a gambler...
هر جاي ديه اي تو اين کشور من از اعضاي، قمارباز بودم
always lookin' over my shoulder, hassled by cops, day and night.
هميشه ناهم به شت سرم بود تا توسط ليس دستير بشم، روز و شب
But here, I'm Mr. Rothstein.
ولي اينجا، من آقاي، راستين بودم
I'm not only legitimate, but running a casino.
من قانوناً کاره اي نبودم ولي کازينو رو اداره مي کردم
And that's like selling people dreams for cash.
و اين مثل فروش رويا به ازاي ول به مردم بود
I hired an old casino pal, Billy Sherbert, as my manager, and I went to work.
رفيقم در کازينوي قديمي، بيلي شربرت رو . به عنوان مدير استخدام کردم و کار رو شروع کردم
...the casino manager. And this is Ronnie, who takes care of the card room.
مدير کازينو، و اين... . رونيه کسي که مراقب اتاق کارتهاست
For guys like me, Las Vegas washes away your sins.
براي به هايي مثل من لاس واس جايي بود که ناهانم رو ميشوره
It's like a morality car wash.
. اينجا مثل يه کارواش معنويه
It does for us what Lourdes does for humpbacks and cripples.
همون کاري رو براي ما کرد که مسيح براي وژشت ها و لاق ها انجام داد
And along with making us legit...
... براي ما ول قانوني مي آورد
comes cash, tons of it.
. تن ها ول نقد
I mean, what do you think we're doing out here in the middle of the desert?
منظورم اينه که، فکر ميکني يکار ميکرديم تو اين صحرا؟
It's all this money.
. با اين همه ول
This is the end result of all the bright lights...
نتيجه نهاييه ... اين همه درخششه
and the comp trips, of all the champagne...
و ردش کاميوتري ... اين همه شاماين
and free hotel suites, and all the broads and all the booze.
و سوييت هاي مجاني هتل . و اين همه زن و اين همه مشروب
It's all been arranged just for us to get your money.
اينا همه براي رفتن ول شما طراحي شده
That's the truth about Las Vegas.
اين واقعيت لاس واسه
We're the only winners.
ما تنها برنده ها هستيم
The players don't stand a chance.
بازيکن ها هي شانسي ندارن
And their cash flows from the tables...
و ول نقد اونا از روي ميزها به صندوق
to our boxes through the cage...
و قفس هاي ما سرازير
and into the most sacred room in the casino.
و به طرف مخفي ترين اتاق کازينو ميرفت
The place where they add up all the money...
جايي که همه ول ها، روي هم ميريختن
the holy of holies, the count room.
به طرف مقدس ترين مقدس ها اتاق شمارش
- Now, this place was off-limits. - Verify 3,000.
اين محل ممنوع بود
Even I couldn't get inside.
حتي من هم نمي تونستم اون تو برم
But it was my job to keep it filled with cash. That's for sure.
ولي کار من ر نهداشتن اون با ول نقد بود، از اين بابت مطمئنم
They had so much fuckin' money in there...
اونا مقدار زيادي ... ول لعنتي اون تو داشتن
you could build a house out of stacks of hundred-dollar bills.
ميتونستي ساختمان و خونه با بسته هاي 100 دلاري بسازي
And the best part was that upstairs...
و بهترين قسمتش . طبقه بالا بود
- the board of directors didn't know what the fuck was going on. - Five thousand.
که اداره کنندان نمي دونستن ه خبره
I mean, to them everything looked on the up-and-up.
منظورم اينه که، همه يز از نظر اونها بالا و بالا تر بود
Right? Wrong.
. درسته؟ غلطه
Verify 5,000.
$ تاييد شد 5000
- The guys inside the counting room... - Five thousand.
... آدم هاي تو اتاق شمارش
Were all slipped in there to skim the joint dry.
مواظب بودن تا اک باشن
They'd do short counts, they'd lose fill slips.
اونا شمارش ها رو کوتاه انجام ميدادن بره ها رو ر ميکردن
They'd even take cash right out of the drop boxes.
حتي ول نقد رو از يه دستاه قراضه بيرون ميکشيدن
And it was up to this guy right here...
و اين به خاطر وجود اين مرده
standin' in front of about two million dollars...
که در مقابل ... دو ميليون دلار ايستاده
to skim the cash off the top without anybody gettin' wise...
که ول هاي نقد رو ... بدون دخالت کسي بر ميداره
- the IRS or anybody. - Verify 200.
سهامدار يا هر کس ديه اي
Now, notice how in the count room nobody ever seems to see anything.
حالا، توجه کنيد که طور تو اتاق شمارش هي کسي نميتونه همه يز رو ببينه
Somehow, somebody's always lookin' the other way.
به نوعي هر کسي هميشه از يه ديداه ديه اي بهش ناه ميکنه
Now, look at these guys. They look busy, right?
اين آقايون رو ببينيد اونا مشغول به نظر ميان، درسته؟
They're countin' money. Who wants to bother them?
اونا ول ها رو ميشمارن ه کسي مي خواد مزاحم اونها بشه؟
I mean, God forbid they should make a mistake and forget to steal.
منظورم اينه که، خدايي نکرده اونا بايد مطمئن باشن که مرتکب اشتباه و دزدي نشن
Meanwhile, you're in and you're out.
در همين حال . شما ميريد تو و ميايد بيرون
Past the jag-off guard who gets an extra C-note a week...
از اردهاي حفاظتي که دستمزدهاي زيادي
just to watch the door.
فقط براي محافظت از در مييرن، رد ميشيد
It's routine. Business as usual: In, out, hello, good-bye.
اين روال معموله، کسب و کاره تو رفتن، خارج شدن، سلام، ود باي
And that's all there is to it.
و اين همه يزه
Just another fat fuck walkin' out of the casino with a suitcase.
فقط يه اق لعنتي ديه خارج ميشه از کازينو با يه مدان
Now that suitcase was goin' straight to one place:
حالا اين مدان کجا ميره مستقيم ميره يه جا
Right to Kansas City, which was as close...
به کانزاس سيتي ... که اونقدر نزديک
to Las Vegas as the Midwest bosses could go...
به لاس واس تو غرب ميانه ست که رئيس ها ميتونن برن
without gettin' themselves arrested.
. بدون اينکه نران دستير شدن باشن
That suitcase was all...
... اون مدان تنها يزيه که
the bosses ever wanted.
. اون رئيس ها احتياج دارن
- And they wanted it every month. - Hey, John, how was your ride?
و اونا هر ماه اونو ميخوان - سلام، جان، سفر طور بود؟
Now this old Mormon fuck here...
... اين مورمون ير لعنتي که اينجاست
he had to fly in with suitcases once a month, nice and easy.
بايد هر ماه يه بار با مدان رواز کنه زيبا و آسون
- Somethin' smells good. - Yeah, they made us somethin' to eat.
بعضي يزها بوي خوبي ميده - آره، اونا اين يزا رو براي خوردن درست ميکنن -
The bosses would come from all over the place:
رئيس ها هم ميان از تمام نقاط
Detroit, Cleveland, Milwaukee...
... ديترويت، کليولند، ميلواکي
all over the Midwest.
از تمام غرب ميانه
And they would meet in the back of this produce market in Kansas City.
و همديه رو شت اين فروشاه غذايي در کانزاس سيتي ملاقات ميکنن
I mean, nobody even knew it.
يعني اينکه، هي کسي نميدونه
One of the guys made his mother do all the cookin'.
يکي از به ها اونجا رو اداره ميکنه مادرش آشزي ميکنه
- Do you ever see that guy Jerry Steriano? - Jerry Steriano?
هي وقت جري استريانو رو ديدين؟ - جري استريانو؟ -
Now, these old greaseballs might not look it...
حالا، اين الوس هاي قديمي ... نبايد اونو تا حالا ديده باشند
but believe me...
... ولي باور کنيد که
these are the guys who secretly control Las Vegas.
اين ها کساني هستن که مخفيانه لاس واس رو کنترل ميکنن
Mama, that man's here again.
مامان، اين آدم ها دوباره اومدن اينجا
Because they control the Teamsters Union.
براي اينکه اونا مديران اتحاديه رو کنترل ميکنن
And that's where you had to go if you wanted to borrow money to buy a casino.
و اونجا جاييه که اه بخواي براي خريد کازينو ول قرض بيري بايد بري
- Would you put in shrimp? - I would.
برام ميو مي کشي؟ - حتما -
Here you are, gentlemen.
بفرماييد، آقايان
Nobody got a Teamsters' loan unless the guys in this room...
هي کسي اينجا مدير نمي شه ... مر آدم هاي تو اين اتاق بخوان
knew they were gonna get their little suitcases.
بدونن که مدان کوکشون بهشون ميرسه
Guys like this antique over here, out of Detroit.
همشون مثل اين عتيقه اي که اينجاست خارج از ديترويت هستن
Or especially guys like Remo Gaggi, the outfit's top boss.
يا آدم هاي به خصوصي مثل ريمو اي که رئيس سطح بالاتريه
You got a round figure on it?
ميخواي اين اطراف برخي؟
- Definitely the most important guy in this room. - About 20 pounds.
قطعا مهمترين آدم اين اتاقه - بيست ونده -
- That's around 700,000. - Uh-huh, good.
حول و حوش 700،000 تا - خوبه -
I know it's a little early for Las Vegas...
ميدونم اين ... براي لاس واس يکم زوده
But I do want to welcome the ladies and gentlemen of the gaming industry.
ولي ميخوام بهتون خوش آمد بم خانم ها و آقايون براي صنعت سررمي
As far as the world was concerned...
از موقعي که دنيا رو ديد ... نران بود
Andy Stone, the head of the Teamsters' Pension Fund...
اندي استون، رئيس و مدير صندوق بازنشستي
- was a legitimate guy. - This is a very auspicious occasion.
مرد فوق العاده اي بود
- A powerful man. - Philip, if you would rise.
يه مرد قدرتمند
He even played golf with the president.
اون حتي همبازي لف رئيس جمهوره
- it is my pleasure to present to you... - But Andy also took orders.
... ولي به اندي سفارشي شده بود
And when he was told to give a pension fund loan to Philip Green...
که براي صندوق بازنشستي فيلي رين قرض جور کنه
this check for $62,700,000...
$62, 700,000...
for the new Tangiers.
براي تنجير جديد
He did what he was told.
آنه رو که بهش فته بودن انجام داد
Now, here was the perfect front man.
اون ظاهرا مرد کاملي بود
What the fuck else could he be? He didn't know too much.
ه يزي مي تونست باشه؟ يز زيادي نمي دونست
He didn't want to know too much...
... نمي خواست که يز زيادي بدونه
especially that the bosses made the Teamsters lend him the money.
رئيس ها مسئولين اتحاديه رو مجبورکرده بودن بهش ول قرض بدن
He wanted to believe the Teamsters...
اون ميخواست به مديران باور داشته باشه
gave him all that fuckin' money 'cause he was smart.
اونا هم ول بهش دادن ون باهوش بود
I know full well how much competition we have in this great city.
به خوبي ميدونم قدر رقابت تو اين شهر بزر وجود داره
And where they got Green from?
و اونا رين رو از کجا آوردن؟
Who the fuck knows?
کي ميدونه
All I know is that Green was an Arizona real estate hustler...
يزي که ميدونم اينه که رين ... يه کلاهبردار املاک تو آريزونا بود
who barely had enough gas money...
که به سختي ... ول کافي جور کرد
to come and pick up his own fuckin' check.
و اومد و ک رو مال خودش کرد
And of course it was the bosses' man...
... و البته دست نشانده رئيس ها بود
Andy Stone, who gave all the orders.
اندي استون تمام دستور ها رو ميداد
Not the chairman of the fuckin' board, Philip Green.
نه رييس احمق و ظاهري فيلي رين
I understand.
فهميدم
Now all they needed was...
... تمام يزي که اونها احتياج داشتن
somebody they could trust to run the casino.
کسي بود که براي اداره کازينو بهش اعتماد داشته باشن
And who better than Ace? I mean, he was already in Vegas a couple years...
و ه کسي بهتر از آيس؟ منظورم اينه که اون مدتهاست که تو لاس واسه
and he had the fuckin' place clocked.
و جاي محکمي داره
But typical Ace, give him a shot at runnin' a casino...
ولي اه به آدمي مثل آيس يشنهاد ... اداره يه کازينو رو بدي
and he tries to talk you out of it.
سعي ميکنه شونه خالي کنه
I don't know if I could do this even if I wanted to.
نميدونم حتي اه بخوام بتونم اين کارو انجام بدم
The Gaming Commission would never give me a license.
کميسيون سررمي هي وقت بهم مجوز نميده
I have at least two dozen gambling and bookmaking pinches on me.
حداقل دوازده مورد خلاف قمار دارم
You don't have to have a license to work in a casino.
احتياجي به مدرک براي کار تو کازينو نداري
All you gotta do is apply for one.
فقط احتياج داري براي يکي از اونها اقدام کني
The state law says that you can work in a casino...
قانون ايالتي ميه ... ميتوني تو يه کازينو کار کني
while they're processing your application.
تا وقتي که در حال بررسي درخواستت هستن
They got a ten-year backlog.
اونا 10 سالي کار انباشته شده دارن
What happens when they do find out?
ه اتفاقي ميفته وقتي که اونا يدات کن؟
Why would they want to find out?
براي ي بايد يدات کنن؟
We're puttin' a hundred million into this desert. Why would they want to lock us out?
ما صدها ميليون رو به اين صحرا مياريم براي ي اونا مزاحم ما بشن
They'll never find out. All you gotta do is keep changing your job title.
اونا هرز نميفهمن. همه کاري که بايد انجام بدي اينه که عنوان کاريت رو عوض کني
Like, uh, from Casino Executive to Food and Beverage Chairman.
مثلا، اه، از مدير اجرايي به مسئول غذا و نوشيدني
They take your application, they put it at the bottom of the pile.
اونا درخواستت رو زير يه شته درخواست قرار ميدن
I know guys been workin' there for 30 years, don't have a license.
آدم هايي رو ميشناسم که سي ساله اونجا کار ميکنن، و مجوز ندارن
It's a tough proposition, Andy.
اين يه کار دشواره، اندي
You know if I did it, I'd have to run it my way.
ميدوني اه انجامش بدم بايد به شيوه خودم عمل کنم
You got it.
انجامش بده
I'm serious, no interference.
جدي ميم، بدون هي دخالتي
Nobody's gonna interfere with your running the casino.
هي کسي تو کار کازينو دخالتي نميکنه
I guarantee it.
تضمين ميکنم
And that's how they got Ace to take over.
و اينطوري شد که اونا آيس رو بردن اونطرف
They wanted him because Ace ate, slept and breathed gambling.
اونا ميخواستنش به خاطر اينکه آيس خواب و خوراکش قمار بود
They worked out a real cute job title too...
اونا مشغول به کارش کردن ... تحت عنوان
Tangiers Public Relations Director.
مدير روابط عمومي تنجير
But the only thing he ever directed was the casino.
ولي تنها يزي که اون اداره نکرد، کازينو بود
He made his first bet when he was 15 years old, and he always made money.
اون اولين شرط بنديش رو تو سن ونزده سالي انجام داد و هميشه هم کلي ول ميبرد
But he didn't bet like you or me.
ولي مثل من و تو شرط بندي نمي کرد
You know, havin' some fun with it, shit like that.
ميدوني، براش يه جور تفريح بود
Where the hell did you learn how to deal?
کدوم جهنمي اين کارو ياد رفتي؟
He bet like a fuckin' brain surgeon.
اون مثل يه جراح مغز کوفتي شرط بندي ميکرد
Place the checks properly.
جکها رو جاي مناسب قرار بده
- That's the way you do it. - Yes, sir.
اينطوري اين کارو بکن - بله قربان -
He had to know everything, this guy.
اون همه ي رو ميدونست
He'd find out the kind of inside stuff nobody else knew...
اون يزي رو ميدونست که هي کس ديه اي نمي دونست
and that's what he'd put his money on.
و اون يزي بود که ولشو روي اون قرار ميداد
Even back home, years ago...
حتي وقتي که به خونه برشت، سال ها قبل
when we were first hangin' out...
... موقعي که براي اولين بار دستير شديم
he'd know if the quarterback was on coke...
ميدونست که کارفرماش ... کوکائين ميزنه
I'll take Columbia for 20.
روي کلمبيا 20 تا
- If his girlfriend was knocked up. - Twenty dimes on Columbia.
اه دوست دخترش در ميزد ميفهميد بيست تا 10 سنتي رو کلمبيا
He'd get the wind velocity so he could judge the field goals.
شدت باد رو ميدونست بنابراين ميتونست به درستي قضاوت کنه
He even figured out the different bounce...
اون حتي مي تونست افتادن هاي مختلف رو به
you got off the different kinds of wood they used...
بايد اين رو تغيير بدي
on college basketball courts, you know?
از رقابت هاي بسکتبال کالج هم استفاده ميبرد ميدوني؟
He'd be workin' on this shit day and night.
اون روي اين وه روز و شب کار کرد
There was nothing about a game he was gonna bet that he didn't know.
هي يز در مورد بازي که شرط ببنده و ندونه وجود نداره
Ace got down at six. Get me down at six.
آيس رو 6 نشست يه 6 بهم بده
Season after season...
... فصل بعد از فصل
the prick was the only guaranteed winner I ever knew.
اون تنها آدم برنده تضمين شده اي بود که ميشناختم
But he was so serious about it all...
ولي اون در مورد همه ي ... انقدر جدي بود
that I don't think he ever enjoyed himself.
که فکر نميکنم ازش لذتي برده باشه
But that's just the way he was.
ولي اون همينطوري بود
But back then, the bosses didn't give a fuck...
ولي بعدا، رئيس ها ... اهميتي ندادن
about whether he enjoyed himself or not.
در مورد اينکه آيا ازش لذتي ميبره يا نه
To them, he was a cash register.
براي اونها، اون نماد ول نقد بود
All they had to do was ring the bell and take money.
تمام کاري که اونا انجام ميدادن جمع شدن و برداشتن ول بود
Especially Remo...
مخصوصا ريمو
who was a fuckin' degenerate gambler who always lost...
اون يه قمار باز فاسد لعنتي بود ... که هميشه مي باخت
Cazzo!
!کازو
All those fuckin' sweeps.
همه شون جارو شدن
- Unless Ace made his bets. - Enough now!
مر در زماني که آيس شرط ميبست - کافيه -
Ace made more money for them on a weekend...
آيس ول زيادي براي اونا تو آخر هفته مياورد
than I could do heisting joints for a month.
که بيشتر از دزدي حشيشي بود که تو يه ماه به دست مياوردم
Whatever Ace picked up on the street, he told Remo.
هر ي که آيس تو خيابون ها به دست مياورد، به ريمو ميفت
I mean, fixed fights, doped horses...
منظورم، دعواي ... اسب هاي دويني
crooked fuckin' zebras, locked-in point spreads.
وره خرهاي لاق و يزهاي ديست
He told fuckin' Remo everything.
اون به ريموي لعنتي همه يز رو ميفت
And to tell you the truth, I don't blame him.
سرزنشش نميکنم
- Hey! - Keepin' Remo happy with money...
!سلام - ... خوشحال نه داشتن ريمو با ول -
was the greatest insurance policy in the world.
بزرترين بيمه تو دنيا بود
Son of a bitch!
!حرومزاده
How the hell did you get Oklahoma-Michigan?
طور يرش آوردي اوکلاهاما- ميشيان
Nobody ever had Oklahoma-Mi... How the hell'd you do it?
هي کسي نتونسته اوکلاهاما- مي طوري اين کارو کردي؟
Well, that's why they paid so well.
خب، به همين دليله که اونا به خوبي رداخت کردن
You see? Never tells me nothin'.
ميبيني؟ هرز هيي بهم نميه
What do we got on for next week?
آيس، ي يرمون مياد تو هفته بعد؟
Well, it's a little too early. I'd say Thursday would be good. Is that all right?
خب، يه کم زوده، من ميم نج شنبه خوبه، اشکالي نداره که؟
- Okay, you'll come by the house? - I'll come by.
باشه، مياي بريم خونه؟ - ميام -
7:00. Good job, my boy. Keep it up? Okay, Ace?
هفت خوبه ادامه بده، باشه آيس
Hey, Nick. Vien acca.
هي، نيک
- I'll be right out. - T'aggia parla.
ميرم بيرون
Nicky, see that guy? Keep a good eye on him.
نيکي، اون مرد رو ميبيني خوب مراقبش باش
He's makin' a lot of money for us.
اون برامون خيلي ولسازه
And he's gonna continue makin' a lot of money for us, so keep a good eye on him.
و باز هم برامون ول زيادي ميسازه س خوب مراقبش باش
Not like your fuckin' friends out there that... without brains.
نه مثل دوستان بي مغزت اون بيرون
- Okay? - All right.
خب؟ - باشه -
- Mi raccomando. - Yeah. Want me to take this for you?
سفارش من - باشه، ميخواي اين رو بردارم؟
So now, on top of everything else...
بنابراين الان بيشتر از هر يز ديه اي
I gotta make sure nobody fucks around with the golden Jew.
ميخوام مطمئن شم هي احمقي اطراف اون يهودي طلايي نيست
Chase, couple of shooters for the ladies.
ند تا يلاس براي خانم ها
Yeah, we made a great pair.
ما زوج خوبي رو تشکيل داديم
I made book and Nicky made sure we always collected.
من به خاطر سردم و نيکي مطمئن بود که هميشه بايد با هم باشيم
The old men loved us, and why not?
يرمرد دوستمون داشت را که نه؟
- They all made money with us. - They payin'?
اونا از طريق ما ول زيادي در مي آوردن
- How did Nicky collect? - They pay every week, like they're supposed to.
نيکي قدر جمع آوري کرده؟
- Don't ask. - And where the fuck is the money? I don't see any money.
سوال نکن - ول لعنتي کدوم وريه؟ من هي ولي نديدم -
- Hi, Melissa, Heidi. - Hi, Sam.
. سلام، مليسا، هايدي سلام، سام -
Who's this guy?
اين يارو کيه؟
- Get the fuck out of here. It was nine. I laid nine. - It was eight.
ورتو از اينجا م کن، اون 9 بود، يه 9 ذاشتم - اون 8 بود -
Ace, tell him the line on the Bear game.
آيس بهش خط برنده رو بو
- Eight. - If he don't know, nobody knows.
هشت - اه اون ندونه، هي کسي نميدونه -
- Told you it was eight. - How come I laid nine?
بهت فتم که 8 بود طوري رو 9 شرط بستم
'Cause you're a jag-off.
ون يه احمقي
- Excuse me. - What?
ببخشيد - يه؟ -
- Is this yours? Your pen? - Yeah, that's my pen. Why?
اين خودکار مال شماست؟ آره، خودکار مال منه، طور؟
No, it's a nice pen. I just didn't know whose it was.
نه، خودکار قشنيه فقط ميخواستم بدونم مال کيه
I thought it was yours. I didn't want it to get lost.
فکر کردم بايد مال شما باشه نميخواستم که م بشه
Well, thank you. Why don't you take that fuckin' pen...
خب، متشکرم را اون خودکار لعنتي رو بر نمي داري
and shove it up your ass, you fuckin' jag-off.
و نميزاريش در کونت احمق لعنتي
Look out, Joe. Look out.
مراقب باش، جو. مراقب باش
What's that? You hear a little girl, Frankie?
ي شد؟ يه دختر کوولو ديدي، فرانکي
Hear a little girl, Ace? Is that a little fuckin' girl?
اينجا يه دختر کوولو هست، آيس؟ يه دختر به لعنتي بوده؟
What happened to the fuckin' tough guy...
ه بلايي سر اون مرد خشن لعنتي اومد
- told my friend to stick it up his fuckin' ass?
به دوستام فتم بزارن در کونش
Nicky, take it easy. Nicky, Nicky.
نيکي، آروم باش، نيکي، نيکي
While I was trying to figure out why the guy was saying...
زماني که تلاش کردم ... بفهممم اون مرد ميخواد ي به
what he was saying, Nicky just hit him.
يا ي ميخواست به نيکي اونو زد
No matter how big a guy might be, Nicky would take him on.
مهم نيست يه نفر قدر بزر باشه نيکي از سش بر مياد
You beat Nicky with fists, he comes back with a bat.
اه نيکي رو با مشت بزني اون با يه خفاش بر ميرده
You beat him with a knife, he comes back with a gun.
اه با اقو بزنيش اون با اسلحه بر ميرده
And if you beat him with a gun, you better kill him...
اه با اسلحه بزنيش ... بهتره بکشيش
because he'll keep coming back and back...
براي اينکه اونقدر ... برميرده و برميرده
until one of you is dead.
تا يکي از شما بميره
Listen, with me protectin' Ace...
وش کن با حمايت من، آيس
he made a fortune for the bosses.
آينده رو براي رئيس ها ميسازه
I mean, that's what got him to Vegas.
يعني براي همين به لاس واس آوردنش
He was a money machine.
اون يه ماشين وله
A tremendous earner for these guys.
يه نان آور فوق العاده براي اين آدم ها
As soon as he took over, he doubled the fuckin' drop.
به محض اينکه اوضاع رو دست رفت درآمد لعنتي دو برابر شد
With Ace, the casino never saw so much money.
بدون آيس، کازينو هرز همين ولي رو نميديد
And the bosses, they couldn't be happier.
و رئيس ها خوشحال تر از اين نميتونستن باشن
# I got $700 #
# I got $700 #
# Don't you mess with me #
# Don't you mess with me #
# But you know I'm down #
# But you know I'm down #
# Everybody knows I'm down ##
# Everybody knows I'm down ##
In Vegas, I had to keep a few juiced-in local cowboys working.
تو واس، من بايد ند تا کابوي محلي رو استخدام ميکردم
They were close to the, you know, good old boys.
اونا خيلي به به هاي خوب قديم شبيه ان
I mean, without us, these guys, they'd still be shoveling mule shit.
منظورم اينه که بدون ما، اين آقايون بايد هن ارو ميکردن
Ward, you've got to keep a cleaner space.
وارد، بايد محيط رو تميز نه داري
If you need Mr. Clean, page him, all right?
اه آقاي تميز رو ميخواي خبرش کن، باشه
Won't happen again, Sam.
ديه تکرار نميشه سام
- Mr. Rothstein. - Mr. Rothstein. Won't happen again, Mr. Rothstein.
آقاي راستين - آقاي راستين، ديه تکرار نميشه، آقاي راستين
Is this guy just another dumb fucking white man, or what? What's the story?
اين هم يکي از اون کودن هاست سر سفيد يا ي؟ داستان يه؟
- You need this guy. - Can't get rid of him?
بهش احتياج داري - نميشه ازش خلاص شد؟
He's juiced in. He's the County Commissioner's cousin.
اون احمق سر عموي نماينده مجلسه
I wouldn't give the bum a mop job.
نميخوام به آدم تنبل يه کار نايز هم بدم
But still, I had no choice. I had to take care of them.
ولي هنوزم، اره اي ندارم بايد مراقبش باشم
These yokels ran the state.
اين دهاتي ها ايالتو ميرخونن
Thank you very much, Senator.
ازتون ممنونم سناتور
- They passed the laws, they owned the courts. - Hi, Ace. Hey, I need a room.
اونا قانون ها رو ميزارن، داداه ها تو دستشونه سلام آيس، يه اتاق احتياج دارم
- I had dozens of politicians and state officials... - The Cedar Room.
تعداد زيادي از سياست مدارها و مقامات دولتي اتاق مخصوص داشتن
Coming through that place every week.
و هر هفته اونجا بودن
- Help the Senator, get him whatever he wants. - Certainly.
به سناتور کمک کن هر ي ميخواد بهش بده - حتما -
Why not make him happy?
براي ي خوشحال نشه؟
...the Presidential Suite.
سوييت رييس جمهوري...
For politicians like our State Senator up there, everything was on the house.
براي سياستمدارهايي مثل سناتورهاي ايالت ما همه ي تو خونه شون بود
These guys won their comp life when they got elected...
وقتي که اتنخاب ميشن ... زندي متفاوتشون رو بدست ميارن
so, hey, why not take advantage of it.
س را از مزاياش استفاده نکنن
Still, the politicians came cheap. We could handle them.
با اين حال، سياست مدارها سطح ايين بودن ميتونستيم کنترلشون بکنيم
It's a whale like K.K. Ichikawa...
يه نهن ... مثل کي. کي. اييکاوا
who plays $30,000 a hand in baccarat...
سيسصد هزار تو يه دست ... باکارات بازي ميکرد
that's the one you really gotta watch.
اون کسيه که بايد واقعا ببينيدش
He plays fast and big and he has the cash and the credit...
اون سريع و بزر بازي ميکنه ... و اونقدر ول نقد و اعتبار داره
to turn out your lights.
که هوش از سرتون ميره
About a year ago he cleaned out a couple of casinos in the Cayman Islands.
سال يش ند تا از کازينو ها رو تو جزاير کايمن خالي کرد
Downstairs he takes us for two million...
طبقه ايين 2 ميليون از ما برداشت
and upstairs he takes free soap, shampoo and towels.
و طبقه بالا مجاني از صابون، شامو و حوله استفاده ميکرد
Another billionaire cheapskate who loved his free rooms...
يکي ديه از اون آدم هايي خر ول ... که عاشق اتاق مجاني
free private jets and two million of our money.
جت خصوصي مجاني و دو ميليون دلار وله
But we got him back.
ولي ما برش ردونديم
I had our pilot tell him the plane was on the fritz.
به خلبان فتيم، بهش به که هوايما خرابه
I don't know what the hell went wrong. I'm awfully sorry.
نميدونم ه اتفاقي افتاد من عميقا متاسفم
I can't understand it. These mechanical things, you know they happen.
اين وسايل مکانيکي رو درک نميکنم اين يزها اتفاق ميفته
Hey, but better here than up there, you know what I mean.
اينجا از بالا بهتره منظورم رو که ميفهميد
Then he missed the commercial flights connecting with Japan.
بعدش هم سفر تجاريش به ژان رو از دست داد
I can't believe that there's a convention; there's no room.
باورم نميشه رزرو شده، هي اتاقي وجود نداره
We got him back with a whole floor of rooms to himself.
ما اونو به طبقه اختصاصي و اتاق مخصوصش برردونديم
- I'm sorry you missed your plane. - Glad to get to know you.
متاسفم که روازتون رو از دست داديد - ازآشنايي با شما خوشبختم -
Oh, no. No gambling.
اه، نه، قمار ديه نه
And once he was back, he played small.
و يک بار که برشت با مقدار ايين بازي کرد
He bet 1,000 a hand, instead of his usual 30,000 a hand.
اون به جاي 1000 تا روي 30000 تا شرط بست
...to the bank with a natural lead over a five.
روي بانک... با 5 هميشي
But I knew the trick with whales like Ichikawa...
ولي من ترفند آدم هايي مثل اييکاوا رو بلد بودم
was that they can't bet small for long.
اونا نميتونن براي مدت زيادي کويک بازي کنن
He didn't think of it as winning 10,000...
نميخواست به بردن ... ده هزار تا فکر کنه
he thought of it as losing 90,000.
با ختن 0 0 0 0 9 براش مهم بود
So, he upped his bets.
س مقدارشرط بنديش رو بالا برد
Until he dropped his winnings back and gave up a million of his own cash.
و براي اينکه باختش رو جبران کنه يه ميليون از ولش رو شرط بست
In the casino, the cardinal rule is to keep them playing...
تو کازينو، قانون اصلي ... نهداشتن بازيکن ها براي بازي بيشتر
and keep them coming back.
و برردوندن اونها به بازيه
The longer they play, the more they lose.
هر ه بيشتر بازي کنن بيشتر ميبازن
In the end, we get it all.
در آخر، همش رو س رفتيم
# Goddamn it Trying to make it real #
# Goddamn it Trying to make it real #
# Compared to what #
# Compared to what #
# Sock it to me #
# Sock it to me #
In Vegas, everybody's gotta watch everybody else.
تو واس، هر کسي بايد مراقب ديري باشه
Six. All right, who's gonna give me that?
شش، باشه ه کسي اونو به من ميده
Since the players are looking to beat the casino...
از اونجايي که بازيکن ها دنبال شرط بندي تو کازينو هستن
- The dealers are watching the players... - Six.
... دلال ها مراقب بازيکن ها هستن
- Fake a six. - The boxmen are watching the dealers.
... صندوق دار مراقب دلال
The floormen are watching the boxmen...
مسئول اجرايي ... مراقب صندوق داره
the pit bosses are watching the floormen...
رؤساي ميز مراقب ... مسئول اجرايي
the shift bosses are watching the pit bosses...
روساي شيفت مراقب ... روساي ميز
the casino manager is watching the shift bosses...
مدير کازينو مراقب ... روساي شيفت
I'm watching the casino manager...
... منم مراقب مدير کازينو
and the eye in the sky is watching us all.
و شمي در آسمان مراقب همه ما
Plus, we had a dozen guys up there...
بعلاوه، ما يه دو جين به اونجا داريم
most of them ex-cheats, who knew every trick in the house.
بسياري از اونا هر نوع تقلبي رو تشخيص ميدن
# Tryin' to make it real compared to what #
# Tryin' to make it real compared to what #
Yes!
!درسته
- Very nice. - I told you I was hot tonight.
خيلي جالبه - بهت فتم امشب جذاب شدم -
Lookin' good.
خوب به نظر مياي
Let's go. This is for Ginger. Come on.
بزن بريم اين براي جينجر ، زود باش
Let me have a hundred on your hard ten.
اجازه بده صد تا روي 10 بزارم
Hundred on your hard ten. Thank you.
صد تا روي 10 متشکرم
Here we go now. Yeeeow!
بزن که رفت !يوهو
- Oh, I'm sorry. - The dice...
اوه، متاسفم - تاس -
Thank you very much.
خيلي متشکرم
- Thank you, sir. I appreciate it. - You were great.
متشکرم قربان، قدرداني ميکنم - عالي بودي -
Thanks. Take care, Steve. Take chances, drive fast.
تشکر، مراقب خودت باش، استيو از شانست استفاده کن، سريع رانندي کن
This hundred is for you, love. Thanks for your time.
اين 100 تا مال تو براي وقتت متشکرم
- Come on. - What's the matter?
زود باش - ي شده؟
What do you mean? I made a lot of money for you, I want my cut.
منظورت يه من يه عالمه ول برات بردم، سهمم رو ميخوام
What money? I've seen you stealing from me.
ه ولي؟ داري از من ميدزدي
What money? Look at the stack of chips.
ژتون ها رو ناه کن
- I want my half. - I've been watching you all night.
سهمم رو ميخوام - تمام شب رو مراقبت بودم -
- I want my money. - Your bag is full of fucking chips.
ولم رو ميخوام - کيفت ر از ژتون هاي لعنتيه -
- I didn't steal anything from you. - Get lost!
من يزي ازت ندزديدم - !م شو -
Get lost? Get lost? Yes! Yes!
م شو؟ م شو؟ !آره! آره
- Well, how about that? - Come on!
خب، اين طوره !زود باش
# Slippin' and a-slidin' # Changin' and a-hidin' #
# Slippin' and a-slidin' # Changin' and a-hidin' #
# Been told a long time ago #
# Been told a long time ago #
# I been told Baby, you've been born #
# I been told Baby, you've been born #
# I won't be your fool no more Oww #
# I won't be your fool no more Oww #
# Baby, oh, baby #
# Baby, oh, baby #
# My sweet baby #
# My sweet baby #
# You're the one #
# You're the one #
What a move.
ه حرکتي
I fell in love right there.
درست همون جا عشق رو حس کردم
But in Vegas, for a girl like Ginger, love costs money.
ولي در واس، براي دختري مثل جينجر، عشق هزينه زيادي داره
# What's different about him #
# What's different about him #
# I don't really know #
# I don't really know #
I'm gonna go powder my nose.
ميرم ودري به بيني بزنم
# No matter how I try #
# No matter how I try #
# I just can't make him cry #
# I just can't make him cry #
- Ginger's mission in life was money. - I'll be right back.
ماموريت زندي جينجر ول بود - بر ميردم -
- See you, Ginger. - Okay, thank you for asking.
ميبينمت، جينجر ممنون که رسيدي
She was a queen around the casino.
اون ملکه اي بود در اطراف کازينو
She brought in high rollers...
... تعادل رو نه ميداشت
and helped them spread around a lot of money.
و کمک ميکرد ول هاي زيادي خش بشه
- Hello. - Hey, Ginger. How you doing?
سلام - سلام، جينجر طوري؟
Great, and I have something for you. You got me covered?
عالي و يه يزي برات دارم ازم شتيباني ميکني؟
- And you do. Thank you very much. - Take care of yourself.
و تو انجامش بده، ازت متشکرم - مراقب خودت باش -
- I got some lucky pills for you, Andy. - Oh, yeah.
برات ند تا قرص آوردم، اندي باشه
Who didn't want Ginger? She was one of the best known...
ه کسي جينجر رو نميخواست؟ اون يکي از بهترين ها بود
best liked and most respected hustlers in town.
دوست داشتني ترين و قابل احترام ترين کلاهبردار شهر بود
Smart hustlers like her could keep a guy awake...
کلاهبردارهاي باهوشي مثل اون ... ميتونن يه مرد رو بيدار نه دارن
for two or three days before sending him home broke...
اونم براي دو يا سه روز قبل از اينکه ورشکسته به خونه برردن
to the little woman and his bank examiners.
از نظر زن و بازرسان بانک
# You only make me glad #
# You only make me glad #
# Better listen, little girl #
# Better listen, little girl #
# You're goin' walkin' down the street #
# You're goin' walkin' down the street #
# I ain't got no love #
# I ain't got no love #
Any change?
هي تغييري رخ نداده؟
Oh, I hit a few games on the way back.
من ند بازي رو هنام برشتن انجام دادم
But that was all bullshit. She just pocketed the cash.
ولي همش مزخرف بود اون فقط ول جمع ميکرد
# This heart of stone #
# This heart of stone #
- How you doin' tonight? - Good.
امشب طوري؟ - خوب -
- How are you? - Uh, beat.
تو طوري؟ آه، باختم
- Ginger had the hustlers code. - Take one for you.
جينجر کد کلاهبرداري رو داشت يکي رو بردار
- Thank you. - She knew how to take care of people.
متشکر - اون ميدونست طوري به مردم برسه
And that's what Vegas is all about.
و اين همه يز در مورد لاس واسه
- Sixty-eight hundred. - Thanks.
متشکر -
- It's kickback city. - Have a good night.
اين شهر س زننده ايه - شب خوبي داشته باشي -
Thank you. You too.
متشکرم، همنين تو
- She took care of the dealers... - Hey, Mitch.
اون هواي دلال ها رو داشت - هي، مايک -
Pit bosses, floor managers...
روساي ميز، روساي اجرايي
but, mostly, she took care of the valet parkers...
ولي، بيشتر از همه، هواي مراقب هاي ماشين رو داشت
the guys who could get you anything and take care of anything.
آدمهايي که همه يز رو بهت ميدن و مراقب همه ي هستن
Ginger took care of the parkers...
... جينجر هم هواي ارکبان ها رو داشت
because they took care of the security guards...
براي اينکه اونها هم هواي ... محافظين شخصي رو داشتند
- who took care of the metro cops, who let her operate. - I need that stuff tonight.
اونا هم هواي ليس شهري رو داشتن، تا اجازه يدا کنن امشب به اينا احتياج دارم
- No problem. - You are a doll.
مشکلي نيست - مثل يه عروسکي -
The valet parking job was such a money-maker...
... ارکباني انقدر شغل ردرآمديه که
they had to pay off the hotel manager just to get the concession.
بايد به مدير هتل ول بدي تا فقط امتياز اين کار به شما داده بشه
But one thing I just could never understand...
ولي يه يز رو ... هيوقت نفهميدم
was that she could have everything under control...
... اون همه يز رو در کنترل داشت
except for her old pimp boyfriend, Lester Diamond.
به جز عشق قديمش دوست سرش، لستر دايموند
Gin, you know I got other people in this, they got partners.
جين، ميدوني آدم هاي ديري رو آوردم تو اين کار که شريک دارن
I want you to understand that I am looking out for you...
ميخوام متوجه باشي که ... مراقبت هستم
in this thing, okay?
باشه؟
You're gonna get yours back, and you're gonna get back first, okay?
مال خودتو برردون و اول تو بررد، باشه؟
- All right, yeah. - Where you going?
باشه - کجا رفتي؟ -
Where are you? You're in that place. Where are you?
کجايي؟ تو اونجايي، کجايي؟
- I'm here. - No, you're not.
اينجام - نه، نيستي -
Where are you?
کجايي؟
I'm always here for you.
من هميشه براي تو اينجام
- You're my woman. - I know.
تو زن من هستي - مي دونم -
The Ginger I knew wouldn't even look at this creep.
جينجري که مي شناختم حتي به اين خزنده ناه هم نميکرد
- Good luck. - Yeah.
موفق باشي - آره -
He was a moocher, a card cheat...
اون يه ولرد بود ... يه متقلب کارت
a country club golf hustler, a scumbag.
کلاهبردار کلوب لف يه جيب بر
- Chasing dentists for a few bucks. - Careful.
دندون زشک ها رو براي ند دلار شکار ميکرد - مراقب باش -
The guy was always broke. He always had a story.
اين يارو هميشه ورشکسته بود هميشه هم يه داستاني داشت
And somehow she could never turn him down.
و يه جوري اون زن نميتونست هرز ازش بذره
The way Ginger saw it, I guess, was that Lester was just an unlucky guy.
از نظر جينجر لستر فقط يه بدشانس بود
Somebody had to take care of him.
يکي بايد مراقبش مي بود
But nobody had to take care of Nicky.
ولي هي کس مراقب نيکي نبود
If you find any cash in there, we'll whack it up with you.
اه ولي اونجا يدا کردي باهات شريک مي شيم
I mean, he took care of himself only too well.
يعني، اون به خوبي مراقب خودش بود
- That's why every badge... - I folded these things beautifully.
به همين دليل علامت ذاشته بوديم
- Back home wanted to nail him. - I would appreciate a little respect.
اينا رو خوب بسته بندي کردم - انتظار يه کم احترام دارم -
- Look at me, pal, I gotta live with her. - Jesus Christ.
به من ناه کن، رفيق، من بايد با اون زندي کنم
# Volare #
# Volare #
Even after a little vacation, they hassled him at the airport.
حتي بعد از يه تعطيلي کوولو اونا تو فروداه باهاش درير شدن
I mean, Frank Marino was there to meet him, but so were the cops.
منظورم اينه، فرانک مارينو اونجا بود تا ملاقاتش کنه، ولي ليس ها هم بودن
This time they wanted to pinch him...
اين بار ميخواستن به دام بندازنش
- for some diamond burglary in Antwerp. - Will you help me fold these?
براي سرقت الماس از آنتور - ميشه کمکم کني اينا رو ببندم؟ -
They were ready to blame him for anything, no matter where it happened.
اونا اومده بودن تا براي هر يزي دستيرش کنن
- Put your things away. - And they were usually right.
يزهات رو بذار کنار - و معمولا درست حدس ميزدن -
- Hold it, hold it. Here. - Because Nicky enjoyed being a gangster.
نهش دار، نهش دار - ون نيکي از نستر بودن لذت ميبرد -
- And he didn't give a damn who knew it. - Come on, there we go.
و اهميتي نميداد کسي اينو بدونه - زود باشيد، بريم
Look at this. Beautiful!
ناش کن، زيباست
I mean, that's what worried me. 'Cause it turns out, Nicky was about to be sent to Vegas.
منظورم اينه که، منو نران کرده بود، ون بيرون اومده بود، نيکي به واس فرستاده شد
- All right, we're clear. - There's more.
خب ، خاليش کن - بايد بيشتر باشه -
There's a couple stuck in there. I know there's more.
يه ند تا ديه اونجاست ميدونم که بايد بيشتر باشه
- I'm telling you, they're out! - Come on.
!بهت ميم، بيارشون بيرون زود باش -
Don't get so defensive, it could be stuck in your hair.
حالت دفاعي نير ممکنه تو موهات ير کرده باشه
What's that? Huh, what's that?
اون يه؟ ها، اون يه؟
There's no more. Thanks, hon.
ديه يزي نيست متشکر، عزيزم
I couldn't wait to get my hands on Vegas.
نميتونستم، منتظر شم تو واس به جايي برسم
But the bosses didn't send me out there to have a good time.
ولي رئيس ها منو اونجا نفرستاده بودن تا خوش ذروني کنم
They sent me out there to make sure that nobody fucked with Ace.
اونا منو اونجا فرستاده بودن تا مطمئن شن کسي مزاحم ايس نشه
And nobody interfered with the fuckin' skim.
و هي کس دخالتي نميکنه
- Hey. - Hey, how you doin'?
هي - هي، طوري؟
Hey, Sammy.
هي، سامي
- Boy, look at this place, huh? - Incredible.
سر، اينجا رو ناه کن، ها؟ شفت انيزه -
Welcome to Vegas.
به واس خوش اومدي
- Okay, Sammy. - Something, huh?
خب، سامي يزي احتياج داري، ها؟ -
Ginger.
جينجر
Holy shit. What've you been doing out here?
تو اينجا يکار ميکني؟
Honey, come here.
عسلم، بيا اينجا
This is Jennifer and Nick, they're dear friends of mine.
اينا جنيفر و نيکي هستن از دوستان خوبم هستن
- Hi, Jennifer. - A pleasure.
سلام جنيفر - خوشبختم -
Okay, Sammy.
خب، سامي
After we ate, we left Jennifer and Ginger alone...
بعد از غذا جنيفر و جينجر رو تنها ذاشتيم
and we took a ride to talk.
و ما هنام سواري صحبت کرديم
And then, he hit me with it.
و بعدش منو در جريان ذاشت
What do you think about me moving out here?
نظرت راجع به اومدن من به اينجا يه؟
What's the matter? You got a problem with that?
ي شده؟ مشکلي باهاش داري؟
- No, of course not. - You mean, I have your permission?
نه، البته که نه - منظورم اينه که حمايت مي کني -
Sure, you have my permission. But I just gotta tell you...
البته، که حمايت مي کنم - ولي فقط بايد بهت بم که -
it's no joke out here, it's no joke.
اينجا شوخي وجود نداره شوخي نيست
You gotta keep a low profile.
بايد رونده ات تميز باشه
It's not like back home. Right off the bat, they don't like guys like us.
اين مثل بازشت به خونه نيست اونا از آدم هايي مثل ما خوششون نمياد
And this sheriff's a real cowboy.
و کلانترهاي اينجا يه کابوي واقعي هستن
Even the coppers aren't afraid to bury people out in the desert here.
اينجا حتي ليس ها ميترسن مردم رو تو صحرا دفن کنن
I don't care. I wanna get away from back home for a while.
اهميتي نميدم، ميخوام يه مدتي از خونه دور باشم
I'm tired of that shit back there.
من از اونجا خسته شدم
Look at this place. It's made of money.
به اينجا ناه کن از ول ساخته شده
You know what the best part is? Nobody's gonna know what we're doing.
ميدوني نکته جالبش يه؟ هي کس نمي دونه اينجا يکار مي کنيم
There's nobody here to see us. Everybody's back home.
هي کس اينجا نيست که ما رو ببينه همه برشتن خونه هاشون
Nick, I gotta tell you. I got pinched twice for no reason.
نيک بايد يه يزي بهت بم دو بار بدون هي دليلي دستير شدم
I really gotta be careful.
واقعا بايد مواظب باشم
I'm running a licensed place, everything's legit.
يه محل مجوز دار رو اداره ميکنم همه يز قانونيه
Don't worry about it. I'm not gonna do anything.
درباره اش نران نباش من هي کاري نمي کنم
I'm especially not gonna involve you in anything.
مخصوصا تو رو درير هي کاري نميکنم
Ace saw Vegas one way...
آيس به واس ناه تک بُعدي داشت
- You call this guy and tell him I'm comin'? - Of course.
به اين يارو تلفن کردي و بهش فتي دارم ميام؟ - البته -
But I saw it another.
ولي من اون بعد ديه رو ميديدم
I saw it as untouched.
من اونو دست نخورده ميديدم
I mean, they had bookies, pimps...
... منظورم اينه که، اونا هر جور آدمي رو داشتن
and drug dealers I could shake down.
و دلالان مواد رو که ميتونستم بردمشون
Who the fuck were they gonna run to?
اونا کين به کجا فرار ميکنن؟
So I started gettin' everybody in line.
بنابراين شروع به آوردن همه تو يه خط کردم
Best of all, for the first time in my life...
بهتر از همه براي اولين بار تو زنديم
I figured out a way not to lose.
راهم رو انتخاب کردم ديه بازنده نبودم
Yeah, he had a foolproof scheme, all right.
آره اون يه آدم رک و روراسته، درسته
It wasn't very scientific, but it worked.
اون علمي نبود ولي صادق بود
When he won, he collected;
وقتي به دست مياوردشون، جمعشون ميکرد
when he lost, he told the bookies to go fuck themselves.
وقتي مي باخت به همه فحش ميداد
What were they gonna do, muscle Nicky?
اونا ميخواستن يکارش کنن نيکي رو درست کنن؟
- Hey, how you doin'? - How you doin'?
سلام، طوري؟ - طوري؟ -
- You got that thing for me? - What thing?
اون يز رو برام آوردي؟ - ه يز رو؟
Oh, Nicky. I thought you was layin'.
اوه، نيکي، فکر کردم شوخي ميکني
No, no, I'm takin'. I was takin'.
نه، نه، ميرفتمش ميرفتمش
- You sure? - I'm positive.
مطمئني؟ مطمئن بودم -
- I'm a little confused. - You're a little confused?
يه کم يج شدم - يه کم يج شدي؟ -
Maybe if I stick your fuckin' face through this window...
ممکنه صورت لعنتيت رو ... تو شيشه بکوبم
you'll get unconfused.
تا از يجي در بياي
- Gimme the fuckin' money. - I'm sorry, Nick.
ول لعنتي رو رد کن بياد - متاسفم، نيک -
I didn't mean anything by it.
نمي خواستم باهاش کاري کنم
That's why you had it ready. You thought I was fuckin' layin' it?
س به اين علته که حاضر بودي فکر ميکردي شوخي ميکنم؟
- My fuckin' head. - Smarten up.
سر لعنتيم - به خودت برس -
And now Nicholas Santoro will come up and tell us about our first president.
و حالا نيکلاس سانتورو مياد و برامون از اولين رئيس جمهور صحبت ميکنه
George Washington was born...
... جورج واشنتون متولد
But still, it was nice and quiet for a while.
اما مدتيه که خوب و آروم به نظر مياد
Ginger and I presented Nicky and Jennifer all over town...
جينجر و من ... نيکي و جنيفر رو به تمام شهر معرفي کرديم
like regular Ozzie and Harriets.
مثل اوزي و هريت
Beautiful, you got a beautiful swing.
زيبا بود ضربه زيبايي بود
Ace got my son, little Nicky, involved in Little League.
آيس سرم نيکي کوولو رو عضو کوولوهاي لي کرد
Turned out to be one of the other coaches...
مربيش
was a fuckin' metro intelligence cop.
يکي ازليس هاي باهوش شهر بود
But it didn't matter. It was all about the kids.
ولي مهم نبود موضوع فقط به ها بودن
He's gotta realize that everything can't be a home run that he does.
اون بايد بفهمه همه يز مثل خونه نيست
That's exactly what I keep tellin' him...
اين دقيقا همون يزيه ... که بهش فتم
but that's the kind of kid he is.
ولي اون اينطور به ايه
And Nicky being Nicky, he made his presence known.
و نيکي مثل نيکي بود تجسم کامل خودش
Especially at the casino, where he definitely did not work...
مخصوصا تو کازينو نبايد به هي وجه کار ميکرد
people got the message.
مردم براش يام ميفرستادن
Me, that's why the bosses sent me out here.
من، به همين دليل بود که رئيس ها منو به اينجا فرستادن
They wanted me to make sure none of the other crews robbed the joint.
ميخواستن مطمئن شن که هيکي ازشون دزدي نميکنه
Like these two fuckin' balloon heads over here.
مثل اون دو تا کله وک که اونجا هستن
They were gonna try to bang us out of 200 fuckin' grand...
اونا دارن سعي ميکنن از ما دويست تا بلند کنن
- yeah, right, I'm sure. - Hey! How are you?
آره، درسته، مطمئنم سلام، طوري؟
How are you? What are you doing here?
طوري؟ - اينجا يکار ميکني؟ -
I'm over here now.
همين اطرافم
- You're over here? - Yeah, I'm over here with them.
تو اينجايي؟ آره، من با اونهام
We're waiting on Carmine.
منتظر کارمين هستيم
Yeah, we're looking for Carmine.
آره، دنبال کارمين مي رديم
He was here before. He had a suitcase and then he left.
قبلا اينجا بود، همراه يه مدان رفت
- Carmine left?
کارمين رفته؟ - کارمين رفته؟
He's gone?
اون رفته؟
He's not here?
اينجا نيست؟
Carmine's out?
کارمين رفته؟
I think maybe he went across the street...
فکر کنم شايد ميخواسته تو تقاطع خيابون باشه
or somewhere else or somethin'.
يا يه يزي شبيه اين
Well, listen, good luck with the joint.
خب، وش کن، موفق باشي ازش لذت ببر
- Ah, thanks, Eddie. - Yeah, lots of luck.
اه، متشکر، ادي آره، موفق باشي
- Yeah, good luck to you too. - Hey, they forgot to sign their papers.
آره، تو هم موفق باشي هي، اونا فراموش کردن اينا رو امضا کنن
Yeah, they don't need those anymore.
ديه به اونا احتياجي نيست
Guys from other crews got away with a warning.
اعضاي روه ديه با يغام تهديد رفتن
Everybody else, watch out.
همه مواظب بودن
Like these yokels here...
... مثل اين دو تا دهاتي اينجا
who never heard of Nicky or the bosses back home.
که راجع به نيکي يا روسا که به خونه برشتن، نشنيده بودن
'Cause they're the morons who give you the most trouble.
ون اونا احمق هايي بودن که بيشترين مشکل رو درست ميکردن
Even after we'd catch them, they'd try sneaking back...
بعد از اينکه يه بار رفتيمشون دزدکي برشته بودن
with beards and wigs and fake noses.
با ريش و کلاه يس و بيني قلابي
You can spot these assholes by watching the way they bet.
ميتوني اون کون شاد ها رو از رو شرط بنديشون بشناسي
Like this guy, he's bettin' lavender chips...
مثل اين يارو که با ژتون بنفش بازي ميکنه
at 500 each with only one little problem...
با 500 تا با يه مشکل کوولو
he's always guessed right.
اون هميشه درست حدس ميزنه
If he wasn't so fuckin' greedy, he'd have been tougher to spot.
اه اين همه حرص نميزد تابلو نميشد
But in the end, they're all greedy.
ولي در نهايت همشون حريصن
# I got a feelin' about the future #
# I got a feelin' about the future #
# And it ain't too good I know that #
# And it ain't too good I know that #
I saw that the dealer was weak, but he wasn't in on it.
ديدم که مدير ميز ضعيفه حواسش هم نيست
He just wasn't protecting his hand.
مواظب دستش نيست
He was lifting his hole card way too high.
ته کارت ها رو خيلي بالا ميبره
Now, here's this guy reading the dealer's hole card...
حالا، اين يارو اينجا ... ته همه کارت ها رو ميبينه
and signaling his buddy at this table.
و به دوستش تو اين ميز سينال ميده
And that's just what these hustlers look for.
و اين کلاهبردار ها فقط منتظر همينن
They cruise from casino to casino looking for weak dealers...
اونها کازينو به کازينو دنبال مدير ميزهاي ضعيف ميردن
the way lions look for weak antelope.
همونطور که شيرها دنبال بز کوهي ضعيف ميردن
Operator, this is Mr. R.
اوراتور، آقاي راستينم
Get me Armstrong and Friday over at pit two right away.
آرمستران و فردي بفرست اينطرف
BJ 19, second base, the beard.
شماره 19 رديف دوم، ريشو
Operator, I need Mr. Happy. Loud.
اراتور، مامور تبريک فتن با سر و صدا بياد
# Happy birthday to you #
تولدت مبارک
# Happy birthday, dear Jeff #
تولدت مبارک جف عزيز
Man down!
!افتاد زمين
Go get medical. We got a cardiac arrest here.
کمک زشکي بيارين اين جا يه حمله قلبي داريم
He's fine, folks. Just give us some room, please.
اون حالش، خوبه فقط يه اتاق به ما بديد، لطفا
They never know what hit them.
هرز نفهميدن ي اونها رو زد
And if and when they do find out...
... و ار هم فهميدن
that they just got zapped by a cattle prod...
اونقدر کتک خورده بودن
they wish they really did have a heart attack.
که آرزو ميکردن کاش واقعا سکته قلبي کرده بودن
Turns out this guy and his fuckin' pals...
اين يارو و رفقاي لعنتيش رو ببريد بيرون
they were knocking this place dead for years.
اونها به مدت ند سال اينجا رو خراب کرده بودن
- He's got a wire on him. - Hey, hey, what are you doing?
اون يه فرستنده با خودش داره - هي، هي، يکار ميکني؟
There it is. That's it.
اينجاست همينه
- Cheater's justice. - Oh, God!
مجازات متقلب ها - !اوه، خداي من
No, no, no!
!نه، نه، نه
I wanted everybody to know...
... ميخوام همه بدونن که
that things were changed around here.
اين جا اوضاع عوض شده
We had to make an example of these pricks...
بايد اين کله خرها رو نمونه اي براي بقيه کرد
that the party was over.
مهموني ديه تموم شده
I'm just curious. I saw you shuffling your checks...
فقط کنجکاوم بدونم ... طور علامت ميدادي
with your right hand.
با دست راستت
- Can you do that with both hands? - No.
ميتوني اين کارو با هر دوتا دست انجام بدي؟ - نه -
- You can't do it with both hands? - No, sir.
نميتوني اين کارو با هر دوتا دست انجام بدي؟ - نه، قربان
Can you do it with your left hand?
ميتوني اين کارو با دست  انجام بدي؟
Well, I never tried.
خب، هرز امتحان نکردم
- So, you're a righty. - Yeah.
س، تو راست دستي - آره -
Now you're gonna have to learn with your left hand.
س بايد کار با دست و ياد بيري
- It's 100, 110, I think. - Yes, it is.
فکر کنم 100 تا 110 تا باشه - بله درسته -
Okay.
باشه
Hiya. That's a lot of money to be counting out in public.
سلام، اون همه ول رو جلوي مردم نميشمارن
Why don't I take him...
... براي ي باهام نمياي
over to the office and verify it?
به دفتر و نميشماريش
A little privacy. And by the way...
يه کمي خصوصي تر ... و در ضمن
send over a nice bottle of champagne on ice.
يه شيشه شاماين با يخ بفرستيد
- Sure will. - Real special.
البته - مخصوصشو -
- By the way, I'm Billy Sherbert, casino manager. - Hi.
من بيلي شلبرت مدير کازينو هستم - سلام -
- Having a good time? - Yes.
همه ي خوبه - بله -
You want to count the money in privacy.
ميخواهي ولتو در امنيت بشمري
I have a plane to catch to Cleveland. Can I get my winnings?
يه هوايما به مقصد کليولند رفتم مي تونم ولامو بيرم؟
Look what they did to my hand, man.
ببين با دستم يکار کردن
All right, I'm gonna give you a choice:
خب من به تو حق انتخاب ميدم
You can either have the money and the hammer or you can walk out of here.
ميتوني ول و کش رو انتخاب کني و يا بري بيرون، انتخاب ديه اي نداري
- What do you want? - I just wanna get out of here.
کدومو ميخواي؟ - فقط ميخوام برم بيرون -
And don't forget to tell your friends what happens if they fuck around here.
و يادت نره به دوستات بي اين دور و بر ه اتفاقي افتاده
- I'm sorry, I made a bad mistake. - You're fuckin' right you made a bad mistake.
فهميدي، متاسفم، اشتباه بدي کردم - درست فتي، اشتباه بدي کردي -
'Cause if you come back here, and we catch either one of you...
ون اه بررديد اين طرف ها ... و يکي از شما رو بيريم
we're gonna break your heads, and you won't walk out of here.
سرتون رو ميشکنيم
You see that fuckin' saw? We're gonna use it. You got it?
اون اره لعنتي رو ميبيني؟ ازش استفاده ميکنيم، فهميدي؟
- Get out of here. - Thank you.
م شو بيرون - متشکرم -
Throw him in the alley and tell the cops he got hit by a car.
بندازينش تو کوه و به ليس ها بين ماشين بهش زده
Within no time, everything was set in place.
همه ي دوباره درست شد
We got rid of the freelance scamsters...
از شر اونا خلاص شديم
the per was way up, the gods were happy.
دوباره درست شد خدايان خشنود شدن
And I decided to complicate my life.
و من تصميم رفتم به زنديم سر و ساماني بدم
For a guy who likes sure things...
... براي کسي که ميخواد از همه يز مطمئن باشه
I was about to bet the rest of my life on a real long shot.
داشتم سر بقيه زنديم قمار بزري ميکردم
We're not gettin' any younger.
ما جوونتر نميشيم
Don't you think it's time?
فکر نميکني که موقعشه؟
Aren't you gettin' tired of all this shit?
خسته نشدي از اين همه مزخرفات؟
What, are you trying to handicap me?
سعي ميکني منو دستبند بزني؟
I'm gonna do you one better.
ميخوام کار بهتري برات بکنم
I'm tryin' to marry you.
باهات ازدواج کنم
You wanna marry me?
ميخواي باهام ازدواج کني؟
I'm serious.
جدي ميم
I wanna settle down. I want a family.
ميخوام سامان بيرم يه خانواده ميخوام
You got the wrong girl, Sam.
يه دختر اشتباهي رو رفتي، سام
I know I'd be a good father, you'd be a good mother.
ميدونم که در خوبي ميشم تو هم مادر خوبي ميشي
You don't know me.
منو هنوز نميشناسي
You've known me two, three months.
منو دو، سه ماهه که ميشناسي
I'm 43 years old. I don't want to wait.
من 43 سالمه ديه نميتونم صبر کنم
I know you well enough to know that I really love you.
اونقدر خوب ميشناسمت که واقعا عاشقت شدم
And I can't think of anybody better to be with.
و فکر کنم کسي بهتر از تو رو سراغ ندارم
And I don't feel like waiting anymore.
و ديه بيشتر از اين نميتونم صبر کنم
You know a lot of happily married people, Sam?
ميدوني، شادي زيادي تو ازدواج مردم هست، سام؟
'Cause I don't.
ولي من نديدم
Yeah, I know all that.
آره، همه اينا رو ميدونم
I care about you, okay.
تو برام اهميت داري، باشه
But I just don't have those kind of feelings for you.
ولي من اين حس رو درباره تو ندارم
I'm sorry. I'm not in love with you.
متاسفم من عاشقت نيستم
- All right, all right. - Understand?
خيله خب، خيله خب - متوجه شدم -
Sam, I'm sorry.
سام، متاسفم
No, I... I...
نه، من... من
I mean... I can grow.
يعني... ميتونم رشد کنم
As long as there's a mutual respect, that kind of thing can grow.
تا وقتي احترام مشترک وجود داره اين يزها ميتونه رشد کنه
I'm realistic. I can accept that.
من واقع را هستم ميتونم اينو قبول کنم
What is love anyway?
مه عشق يه؟
It's a mutual respect. It's a devotion.
اون احترام مشترکه اون از خود ذشتيه
It's a caring from one person to another.
مراقبت کردن از يه نفر در مقابل ديران
And if we could set up some kind of foundation...
و اه ما بتونيم ... بر اساس اين
based on that mutual respect...
احترام متقابل رفتارکنيم
I feel eventually you would care enough about me...
در نتيجه احساس ميکنم به اندازه کافي بهم توجه ميکني
that I could live with that.
تا بتونم باهاش زندي کنم
If it doesn't work out, doesn't play out...
اه کار نکرد ي اه خوب يش نرفت
then what happens to me?
ه اتفاقي برام ميفته؟
You know I'm doing well now, and I'm gonna do even better.
ميدوني که من ه طوريم و حتي بهترم ميشم
And so whatever happens...
... و هر اتفاقي هم بيفته
if it doesn't work out between us...
... اه بين ما خوب يش نرفت
I'm gonna make sure you're okay for the rest of your life.
بهت اطمينان ميدم که بقيه زنديت رو راحت بذروني
And if there are kids, especially...
... و مخصوصا اه به هايي داشتيم
I'll take care of you better than you'd ever imagine.
بهتر از تو از اونها مراقبت خواهم کرد
What are you pitching me?
طوري خيالمو راحت ميکني؟
Just what I said, you'll be set up...
فقط همونطور که فتم ... ميتونم ترتيبشو
for the rest of your life, that I can promise you.
براي بقيه زنديت بدم بهت قول ميدم
Want to take a chance?
ميخواي شانستو امتحان کني؟
When I married Ginger, I knew all the stories.
وقتي با جينجر ازدواج کردم تمام داستانش رو ميدونستم
But I didn't give a fuck. I'm Sam Rothstein, I said.
ولي کوک ترين اهميتي نميدادم من سام راستينم، فتم که
I can change her.
ميتونم عوضش کنم
It was typical Ace.
اين همون آيسه
He invited the biggest people in town, and he knew they'd show.
اون مهمترين آدم هاي شهر رو دعوت کرد، و ميدونست که ميان
Because he knew they all wanted somethin' from him.
ون ميدونست همشون بهش احتياج دارن
With Ace, nobody ever got a free ride, even Ginger.
بدون وجود آيس، هي کسي نميتونه کاري يش ببره، حتي جينجر
With her, he still covered his bets.
با اون، هنوز هم شرط بندي ميکنه
They had to have the baby before they could get married.
اونا به دار شدن قبل از اينکه ازدواج کنن
He even made Jenny and me watch Amy for a few days...
حتي جني و من رو مجبور کرد ... ند روزي مراقب امي باشيم
when they went on their honeymoon.
وقتي به ماه عسل رفتن
But I didn't mind, we loved the kid.
ولي اهميتي ندادم ما به ها رو دوست داشتيم
Can you feel my eyes on you?
ميتوني ناهمو رو خودت احساس کني؟
Can you feel me look into your heart?
احساس مي کني که دارم به قلبت ناه مي کنم؟
in the pit of your stomach?
منو تو وجودت احساس مي کني؟
Can you feel me in you?
منو درونت احساس مي کني؟
In your heart?
در قلبت؟
Don't make me come there.
منو سردم نکن
Answer me.
جوابمو بده
I love you.
دوست دارم
But, baby, do you know that I love you too?
ولي، عزيزم، ميدوني که منم دوست دارم؟
- No, Lester. - Do you know that?
نه، لستر - تو اينو نميفهمي؟ -
This is the best thing I can do for my life right now.
اين بهترين يزيه که ميتونم الان براي زنديم انجام بدم
That's right. So it's going to be okay.
درسته س درست ميشه
Promise?
قول ميدي؟
I wish you all the luck in the world.
برات در هر جاي دنيا آرزوي خوشبختي ميکنم
You do?
اين کارو مي کني؟
Yeah, I do. It's the best thing you can do right now.
آره، اين بهترين کاريه که الان ميتوني انجام بدي
I mean this.
منظورم اينه که
You have real security.
تو درامنيت واقعي هستي
Sweetheart, you're gonna be situated just right, in Vegas.
عزيزم به لاس واس عادت ميکني
Come on. This is great for us.
بجنب، اين براي ما عاليه
I'm always gonna be here for you.
من هميشه اينجا منتظرت ميمونم
I ain't going no place.
هي جايي نميرم
I'm lookin' at you right now.
همين الانم دارم ميبينمت
I'm seein' you for the very first time, right this minute.
اولين باري که ديدمت رو مي بينم درست در همين لحظه
I can feel my heart click.
قلبم رو حس ميکنم که ميزنه
I see you 14 years old.
تو رو 14 ساله ميبينم
I see you the first second I ever saw you.
اولين ثانيه اي رو که تو رو ديدم مي بينم
I see you, long-legged little colt...
ميبينمت ... کره اسب ا بلند
stupid braces on your teeth.
سيم ي احمقانه روي دندونهاتو
- Okay, then. - Every time I ever see you, that's what I see.
خب، بعدش - هر موقعي که ميبينمت، اين يزها رو ميبينم
Talk to you later.
بعدا باهات تماس مييرم
Bye.
Bye.
You all right?
حالت خوبه؟
Yeah.
آره
Why are you crying?
را ريه مي کني؟
I'm not crying.
ريه نمي کنم
Maybe you shouldn't drink so much.
شايد تو مشروب خوردن زياده روي کردي
I'm okay, I just...
... خوبم، فقط
You just have to understand.
فقط بايد درک کني که
I've been with Lester since I was a kid.
از موقعي که به بودم با لستر بودم
I just wanted to say good-bye.
فقط ميخواستم باهاش خداحافظي کنم
I just... I don't...
... فقط... نميخوام که
I think I have a right to do that.
فکر ميکنم حق اين کارو دارم
Okay?
باشه؟
It's all right.
مشکلي نيست
That part of your life is over with.
اون قسمت از زنديت ديه تموم شد
- Right? - Yeah.
درسته؟ - آره -
You're with me now.
الان با مني
- Right?
درسته
Uh-huh.
اه- ها
- You're sure? - Yeah.
مطمئني - آره -
Yeah.
باشه -
- Let's go. Let's go back in. - Okay.
بيا بريم، بيا بررديم تو -
Oh!
!اه
Tsk. It's great.
عاليه
It's all my stuff. Oh, my God.
تمام اينا مال منه اوه، خداي من
You brought all my stuff!
!تمام اينا مال منه
I can't...
... نميتونم
Try it on. It's yours.
امتحانش کن، مال خودته
You're kidding.
شوخي مي کني
Oh, my God. What is it?
اوه، خداي من اين يه؟
It's chinchilla.
سمور
Oh, it's so soft.
اوه، قدر نرمه
Nice, isn't it?
قشنه، اينطور نيست؟
No one's ever been so nice to me.
هيکي با من اينقدر خوب نبوده
Oh!
!اوه
Oh, my God!
اوه ، خداي من
So, do you think it's too much...
فکر نميکني ... زياده رويه
if I wear these all on the same day?
اه همه اينا رو با هم استفاده کنم؟
You do whatever you want.
هر کاري که ميخواي بکن
Do I keep my promises or do I keep my promises?
به قولم عمل کردم؟
So wonderful. The jewelry's not so bad either.
فوق العاده اس، جواهرها هم بد نيستن
We shouldn't keep this in the house. We gotta put it in the bank.
نبايد اونا رو تو خونه نه داريم بايد اونا رو تو بانک بذاريم
Come on. Can I keep this one in the house?
زود باش، ميتونم اين يکي رو تو خونه نه دارم؟
Pay attention to me.
به من توجه کن
- What I'm gonna tell you is very important. - Okay.
يزي که ميخوام بهت بم خيلي مهمه - باشه -
All this stuff doesn't mean anything.
تمام اينا هي معنايي نداره
Money, this doesn't mean anything without trust.
ول بدون اعتماد معنايي نداره
I have to be able to trust you with my life.
بايد بتونم تو زنديم بهت اعتماد کنم
With over a million in cash and jewels...
با يه ميليون ... ول نقد و جواهر
tucked in a bank in Vegas, only for Ginger, she was secure and happy.
که در يه بانک تو واس به اسم جينجر بود، اون احساس امنيت و خوشحالي ميکرد
She loved that shit.
اون عاشق اون لعنتي بود
But a guy in my line of work has to have a lot of payoff cash around.
ولي آدمي مثل من ول نقد زيادي اطرافش داره
Crooked cops and kidnappers, they don't take checks.
ليس هاي منحرف و آدم دزدها ک قبول نميکنن
Need any help with that, Mr. Collins?
ه کمکي مي تونم بهتون بکنم آقاي کالينز؟
So I put two million in cash in a Los Angeles bank...
بنابراين 2 ميليون دلار نقد ... تو بانکي در لس آنجلس ذاشتم
under the name of Mr. And Mrs. Tom Collins.
به اسم آقا و خانم، تام کالينز
This was strictly my shakedown and kidnapping money.
اين ول براي موقعيت هاي اضطراري بود
And since I'd either be in jail or locked in a closet...
براي هر موقع که تو زندان ... يا کمد حبس بشم
when I needed the money the most...
وقتي که احتياج زيادي به ول يدا کنم
I gave Ginger the only key to the cash that could get me back alive.
کليد ول نقد رو به جينجر دادم تا منو زنده بيرون بياره
- # I'll take you there # - # I'm callin', callin' #
- # I'll take you there # - # I'm callin', callin' #
# Callin' for mercy #
# Callin' for mercy #
- # I'll take you there # - # Mercy, mercy #
- # I'll take you there # - # Mercy, mercy #
# I'll take you there #
# I'll take you there #
This is a signature card.
اين کارت نمونه امضاست
So once she signs those papers, she'll be the only person...
بنابراين اه اون، کاغذها رو امضا کنه ... تنها شخصي هستش که
to have total access to the box, no one else, including myself?
ميتونه به اون جعبه دسترسي داشته باشه نه هي کس ديه، حتي من؟
That's right. That's the way you wanted it.
درسته همينطوره که ميخوايد
Sam, let me ask you a question.
سام، يه سوالي ازت داشتم
You must really trust your wife.
واقعا به همسرت اعتماد داري؟
Yeah, sure I do. Why?
آره، البته که دارم، طور؟
It's good. It's just unusual.
خوبه فقط غيرعاديه
Tell you the truth, so many of my clients don't.
واقعيتش رو بخواي اکثر مشتريانم ندارن
- # Let me take you there # - # I'll take you there #
- # Let me take you there # - # I'll take you there #
- # Ain't no smilin' faces # - # I'll take you there ##
- # Ain't no smilin' faces # - # I'll take you there ##
# Never will I know happiness #
# Never will I know happiness #
With Ginger and the money in place, I felt covered.
با وجود جينجر و ول در اينجا احساس امنيت ميکردم
And to play it safe, I switched job titles again...
و براي امنيت کاري ... دوباره عنوان شغليم رو عوض کردم
and made myself Food and Beverage Director.
و خودم رو مسوول غذا و نوشيدني ها کردم
This way nobody would bother me about a license.
اينطوري هي کسي نميتونه منو ... براي جواز کارم اذيت کنه
I mean Vegas was like a dream for me.
يعني واس برام مثل يه رويا بود
Trouble was, Nicky was dreaming his own kind of Vegas.
مشکل اينه که، نيکي روياي خودش رو در مورد واس داشت
I put money out on the street chargin' three points a week.
ول ها رو از تو خيابون بر ميداشتم براي 3 بار تو هفته
- Don't make us come lookin' for you. - Juice to the fuckin' dealers.
کاري نکن مجبورشيم دنبالت بيايم
You won't have to look for me.
مجبور نيستيد دنبالم بيايد
I appreciate it. Thanks, Nicky.
قدرداني ميکنم ممنون، نيکي
They were degenerate gamblers, coke freaks.
اونا قمارباز هاي فاسدي بودن احمق هاي کوکائيني
In no time I had half the dealers in the Tangiers in my pocket.
وقت نداشتم با مدير ميزها باشم در تنجير تو جيبم بودن
Then, I started bustin' out high-stakes poker players.
بعدش، استارتو زدم با وکر باز هاي رده بالا بازي کردم
It was so obvious.
واضح بود که
- All of Nicky's half-assed mechanics were signal-happy. - I'm gonna open for 500.
تمام کمک نيکي سينال ماشيني بود
Signaling back and forth.
سينال عقب و هار
Nicky thought nobody was watching him. But he was wrong.
نيکي فکر ميکرد هيکي مواظبش نيست ولي اشتباه ميکرد
And I didn't want any of those agents near my place.
و من نميخواستم هيکدوم از بازرس ها اين اطراف باشن
- Four aces. - I can't believe this.
هار تا تک - باورم نميشه -
If I didn't have bad luck, I wouldn't have any luck.
ار بدشانس نبودم هي شانسي هم نداشتم
I wished to God Nicky and his whole crew would just get lost.
از خدا آرزو ميکردم کاش نيکي و روهش فقط م ميشدن
What am I gonna do? Go back home and start a war?
يکار ميتونم بکنم؟ برردم خونه و جن راه بندازم
Nicky's a made guy, and I'm not. I can't do that.
نيکي نفر داره، و من ندارم نمي تونم اين کارو بکنم
Be careful. Gaming agents are all over the place.
مواظب باش، بازرس بازي ها همه جا هستن
So I'm lucky. I'm not allowed to get lucky in this place?
س خوش شانسم، اجازه ندارم خوش شانس باشم
You've been lucky all week. They're looking to nail you.
تمام هفته رو خوش شانس بودي اونا مراقبتن
Ace was so fuckin' worried about his casino...
آيس خيلي نران کازينوي لعنتيش بود
he forgot what we were doin' out here in the first place.
فراموش کرده بود اولش يکاره بوديم
A million times I wanted to yell in his fuckin' ear...
ميليون ها بار ميخواستم ... تو وش اين احمق فرياد بزنم
"This is Las Vegas.
که اينجا لاس واسه
We're supposed to be out here robbin'...
ما اينجاييم که دزدي کنيم
you dumb fuckin' hebe. "
احمق دهاتي
I don't give a shit who he's connected to.
اهميتي نميدم که اون با ه کسي در ارتباطه
Tell him to take his fuckin' feet off the table.
بهش بو اي لعنتيش رو از رو ميز برداره
What's he think this is, a goddamned sawdust joint?
ي فکر کرده مرتيکه خاک اره جو؟
Sir, would you mind taking your feet off the table?
آقا، اه اشکالي نداره اتون رو از رو ميز برداريد
Yeah, I would mind. I'm having a bad night.
اهميتي نميدم شب بدي رو ميذرونم
Fuckin' asshole won't budge.
احمق کون شاد توجهي نميکنه
Call security.
حراست رو خبر کن
- How are you? - Good. How are you?
حالتون طوره؟ - خوب، حال شما طوره؟
Wanna do me a favor? Take your feet off the table and put your shoes back on.
يه لطفي بهم ميکني؟ اهاتو بردار از رو ميز و کفش هاتو بوش
Fuck you!
!م شو
I want you to exit this guy off the premises...
ميخوام اين يارو رو بندازيد بيرون ... خارج از محل
and use his head to open the fucking door.
و از سرش براي باز کردن در کوفتي استفاده کنيد
Sir, you're gonna have to leave. Wanna come with us outside?
آقا، شما بايد اينجا رو ترک کنيد ميشه با ما بيرون بيايد
Bullshit. I ain't goin' anywhere with you.
مزخرفه، من با تو هي جايي نميام
- Bullshit. You're outta here. - Fuck you!
مزخرفه، از اينجا م شو - - Fuck you!
You know who you're fucking with? Do you?
ميدوني با کي حرف ميزني کوني؟ ميدوني؟
You fucking faggot! Do you know who you're fucking with?
تو احمق کوني! ميدوني با کي حرف ميزني؟
Leave me alone!
تنهام بزاريد
- Come on! - You guys are killing me!
!داريد منو ميکشيد
Sure enough, an hour later, I get the call.
کافيه، يک ساعت بعدش بهم تلفن شد
Ace, what happened over there? Did you know that guy was with me?
آيس، اونجا ه اتفافي افتاده؟ ميدوني اون يارو از طرف من بوده؟
No, I didn't know that. But you know what he did?
نه، اينو نميدونستم ولي ميدوني اون يکار کرده؟
I walked over to him politely, and he tells me to fuck myself.
من باهاش مودبانه صحبت کردم ولي اون در عوض بهم فت خودمو بکنم
- Then he called me a faggot. - What?
بعدش بهم فت کوني - ي؟ -
- I threw that cocksucker out. - Hey, come here.
منم اون کله کيري رو انداختم بيرون - هي، بيا اينجا -
You called my friend a faggot? You tell him to fuck himself?
به رفيقم فتي کوني؟ بهش فتي خودش رو بکنه؟
- Is that what you did? Tell him to go fuck himself?
اين کارو کردي؟ -
Come here. Come here.
بيا اينجا، بيا اينجا
You go over there. You apologize.
برو اونجا عذرخواهي کن
You better hope he lets you back in.
بهتره اميدوار باشي اجازه بدن برردي
If you get outta line again, I'll smash your head so hard...
اه دوباره از خط خارج شي ... اونقدر محکم تو سرت مي کوبم
you won't be able to get that cowboy hat on.
که ديه نتوني اون کلاه کابويي روسرت کني، ميشنوي
Fuckin' hick. Sammy, listen.
احمق، دهاتي سامي، وش کن
This guy obviously doesn't know who he was talking to.
معلومه که اين يارو نميدونسته با ه کسي صحبت ميکنه
He doesn't know that we're dear friends.
نميدونسته که ما دوست هاي صميمي هستيم
I mean, he's already very sorry.
منظورم اينه که، اون واقعا خيلي متاسفه
But if you could do me a favor and let him back in...
ولي اين لطف رو در حقم بکن ... و بذار بررده
I swear he'll never get out of line again.
قسم ميخورم که ديه هرز دوباره از خط خارج نشه
If he does it again, he's out for good.
اهميتي برام نداره
I don't care what it is, I'll never let him in the place again.
اهميتي بهش نميدم ديه هرز بهش اجازه کار نميدم
I'm sorry about this, really.
واقعا بابت اين جريان متاسفم
All right, Ace? Thanks, pal.
باشه، آيس متشکر، رفيق
You took your boots off? You put your feet on the table?
که کفشاتو در آوردي؟ اهاتو روي ميز ذاشتي؟
You shit-kickin', stinky-horse-manure-smellin' motherfucker, you!
وه کثافت اسب بدبو مادر جنده کودن
You fuck me up over there, I'll stick you in the desert.
منو اونجا خراب ميکني توي صحرا دفنت ميکنم
- Go over and apologize. - Nicky, I'm sorry.
برو اونجا و عذر خواهي کن - نيکي، متاسفم -
# You're dear to me Yes, sirree #
# You're dear to me Yes, sirree #
You know, Ace could be a very touchy guy.
ميدوني آيس ميتونست خيلي دوست داشتني باشه
Especially when he got bigger in town.
مخصوصا وقتي که تو شهر قوي شد
Like when he hired that Jonathan and David and their tigers away from the Palace...
مثل وقتي که به جاناتان و ديويد و ببرهاشون
by building them a new stage and giving them a Rolls-Royce.
يه ساختمان با يه طبقه مخصوص و يه رولز رويس هديه داد
But I'll tell you, he knew how to bring in the crowds.
ولي بهتون بم، اون بلد بود طور مردمو جذب کنه
He knew all the fuckin' angles.
اون همه فرشته هاي لعنتي رو ميشناخت
He brought over the whole "Femme Fatale" show from Paris...
اون کلي از ... زنان افسونر نمايش رو از اريس آورده بود
but he forgot how lazy them European dancing broads can get.
اما فراموش کرده بود که اين رقصنده هاي اروايي قدر ممکنه اق بشن
He had to weigh 'em in once a week to make sure they didn't blow up like balloons.
اون مجبور بود يه بار در هفته اونا رو وزن کنه تا مطمئن شه مثل بالون منفجر نشن
She's still eight pounds over.
اون هنوز 8وند اقه
- What's the reason for this? - Mr. Rothstein, sir.
علتش ي ميتونه باشه؟ - آقاي راستين، قربان -
Never mind the "sir. " Why is she eight pounds over?
نميدونم را قربان را اون 8 وند اضافه داره؟
I'm trying to use respect.
سعي ميکنم با احترام برخورد کنم
Mr. Rothstein is good enough for you.
آقاي راستين به اندازه کافي خوبه براتون
Well, sometimes when you put that pressure point on them...
خب، بعضي وقت ها وقتي ... بهشون فشار مياد
All you do is give me answers. Just give me the right answer.
ميخوام همتون بهم جواب بديد فقط بهم جواب صحيح بديد
I guess she's frightened. If she doesn't lose weight she may get fired.
حدس ميزنم ترسيده باشه اه 8 وند رو کم نکنه اخراج بشه
That's right, she will get fired. Send her back to Paris...
درسته، اخراج ميشه ... برش ردونيد اريس
- It's been our policy... - Just stop everything!
اين سياست ماست - فقط همه يز رو متوقف کنيد -
- This woman's an institution. - That's the problem. She's lazy.
اين يه رسم معمول زنانه ست - مشکل اينجاست که اون تنبله -
Hey, I gotta give the guy credit.
هي بايد بهش اعتبار بدم
I mean, he does the most obvious thing.
منظورم اينه که، اون واضح ترين کارو انجام داد
This is the only town in the country where a bookie joint is legit.
اينجا تنها شهري تو کشوره که فحشا توش قانونيه
So why not take advantage, right?
س را نبايد از مزاياش استفاده کرد؟
So, he took bookie joints off the street...
... بنابراين اون اونا رو از تو خيابون جمع ميکرد
and then opened them up inside the casino.
و بعدش تو کازينو ازشون استفاده ميکرد
Within a few years by doing all of this...
براي ندين سال اين کارو انجام داد
he had every casino on the strip trying to copy off of him.
همه کازينو ها رو مجبورکرد اين کارو ازش تقليد کنن
Between my innovations...
... براي نو آوري هام
# Look like they're taking some cat to jail #
# Look like they're taking some cat to jail #
and Nicky's dedication to his job...
و نيکي رو به ... اين شغل اختصاص دادم
# Steamboats are comin' and they're splashing and goin' #
# Steamboats are comin' and they're splashing and goin' #
I soon had the best operation on the strip.
به زودي تو اين کار بهترين شدم
# Moon is shinin' on friends below #
# Moon is shinin' on friends below #
You gotta watch yourself. There's a lot of heat on you already.
بايد مراقب خودت باشي تله هاي زيادي اطرافته
Why? Somebody's complainin'?
طور؟ کسي شاکيه؟
I'm hearing things from security.
يزهايي رو از بخش حفاظت شنيدم
The sheriff's lookin' to put you in the Black Book.
کلانتر ميخواد تو رو تو ليست سياه بذاره
That Black Book is a bunch of bullshit.
ليست سياه يه ليست رته
They got two names from the whole country...
اونا 2 تا اسمو ... از سرتاسر کشور دارن
and one of 'em is still Al Capone.
و هنوز يکي از ... اونا آل کاونه
If they put you in that book, you're gonna be in trouble.
اه اسمت بره تو ليست تو مشکل ميفتي
You will not be able to walk into a casino.
ديه نميتوني قدم داخل کازينو بزاري، دارم بهت ميم
I'm trying to make a living, that's all.
تنهايي يکار ميتونم بکنم همين
I'm just tellin' you. Don't say I didn't warn you.
دارم بهت بم ني بهت نفتم
All right.
باشه
Mrs. Rothstein, straight ahead. Very nice.
خانم راستين مستقيم به جلو، عاليه
Thank you.
مرسي
For his hard work and dedication...
به علت کار زيادش ... و تعهدش
and the new life blood he has instilled in Las Vegas...
و خون جديد زندي ... که در لاس واس دميده
Sam has established himself as an indispensable member...
سام خودش رو اثبات کرده ... به عنوان عضوي افتخاري
of the gaming community.
از جامعه سررمي
As the head of the Tangiers Gaming Corporation...
به عنوان رئيس شرکت سررمي تنجير
it's my pleasure to welcome Sam Rothstein...
باعث افتخاره که ... خوش آمد بم به سام راستين
to the Vegas Valley Country Club.
به دره واس در شهر سررمي
Back home, they would've put me in jail for what I'm doing.
تو شهر خودم به خاطر اين کار منو مينداختن زندان
But out here, they're giving me awards.
ولي اينجا جايزه هم بهم ميدادن
It is with great pleasure that I accept this certificate of appreciation...
بسيار افتخار ميکنم که اين ... واهينامه تقدير رو مييرم
for charitable donations to greater Las Vegas.
براي کمک هاي خيريه براي لاس واس بزر تر
Congratulations, sweetheart.
تبريک ميم، عزيز قلبم
Sam raised more than we've ever raised before.
سام بيشتر از هر کس ديه اي باعث يشرفتمون شد
But my greatest pleasure was watching my wife, Ginger, work the room.
ولي من بيشتر افتخام رو از شم همسرم جينجر مي بينم که تو اتاق کار ميکرد
- They all loved her. How could you not love her?
همه دوستش دارن - طور ميتونيد دوستش نداشته باشيد؟
She could be the most charming woman you ever saw.
جذاب ترين زنيه که به عمرتون ديدين
People loved to be around her.
مردم دوست دارن دور و برش باشن
You've got to bring Amy to Sasha's birthday party.
بايد امي رو به جشن تولد ساشا بياري
We'd love to have you there.
دوست داريم کنارت باشيم
- Yes, okay. - Great.
باشه، خوبه - عاليه -
She made everybody feel good.
اون در همه حس خوبي ايجاد مي کرد
# That's Stella by starlight #
# That's Stella by starlight #
Congratulations, Sam.
تبريک ميم، سام
Oh, thanks.
آه، متشکر
- Hello, Mrs. Rothstein. How are you? - Hi.
سلام، آقاي راستين حالتون طوره؟ - سلام -
You're one of the most gorgeous women I've ever seen.
شما يکي از زيباترين خانم هايي هستين که تا حالا ديدم
You're a lucky man, Mr. Rothstein.
شما مرد خوش شانسي هستين آقاي راستين
Thank you. Thanks for that compliment.
متشکرم براي تعريفي که کردي
He was a young kid from the casino.
يکي از اعضاي جوان کازينوه
Nice kid. Bright boy.
به خوبيه سر فهميده ايه
What balls on this fuckin' kid! The next day I fired him.
عجب تخمي داشت که اين حرفو زد روز بعد اخراجش کردم
Ginger had that effect on people. I think she even encouraged them.
جينجر اين تاثيرو رو مردم داره حتي فکر ميکنم تشويقشون هم ميکنه
Do you wanna see this one? Ahhhh!
ميخواي اينو ببيني؟ آه- ها
Daddy gave me all this jewelry because he loves me so much.
بابا همه اينا رو بهم داده ون خيلي دوستم داره
- But as much as they loved her... - Oh, fabulous!
ولي همونقدرکه اونها دوستش داشتن - !محشره -
They didn't know what really moved her.
نميدونستن واقعا ي اون رو به جلو ميبره
Look at this. Look at this. Daddy gave me this...
اينو ناه کن، اينو ناه کن بابا اينو بهم داد
And with Ginger happy, I was able to concentrate on what I knew best.
و با يه جينجر شاد ميتونستم تو کارم بهترين باشم
Loose machines are right back over there.
دستاه ها اون شت هستن
What are they doin' back there? You can't even see 'em there.
اون شت يکار ميکنن؟ حتي نميشه اونا رو ديد
- Okay, I'll... - What about the progressives with the high jackpots?
باشه - طوره ماشين هاي جک اتو عوض کنيم -
- Well... - These are our best machines. They bring all the action.
... خب - اونا بهترين ماشين هامون هستن، اونا هر کاري ميکنن
- No wonder the drop is off. - Yeah, okay.
نميخوام اينو از دست بدم - باشه، خب -
- The action is in the front. Bring 'em up front. - All right, I will.
اونا رو بيار جلو، بذار جلو باشن باشه، اين کارو ميکنم
Listen to me very carefully. There are three ways of doing things around here:
بهم وش کن، خيلي مراقب باش کارهاي اين اطراف بر مبناي سه نوعه
The right way, the wrong way and the way that I do it.
درست، غلط و اونطور که من انجامش ميدم
- You understand? - I do understand that. I'll get right on it.
متوجه شدي؟ - فهميدم، همين کارو ميکنم
- And thank you. - Don't thank me. Just do it.
و متشکرم - ازم تشکر نکن، فقط انجامشون بده -
You're the slots manager. I shouldn't have to tell you this.
تو مدير بخشي من نبايد اينو بهت بم
Dang, you are right, Mr. Rothstein. I am so sorry.
شما درست مييد آقاي راستين، من شرمندم
So I ended up working... what, 18-hour days.
بنابراين 18 ساعت در روز کار ميکردم
Ginger was the one who wound up enjoying the best of Vegas.
جينجر بهترين کسي بود که مي شد تو واس باهاش لذت برد
Come with me, please. I have a better table for you.
باهام بيا، لطفا ميز بهتري برات دارم
What did you say to that fucking jerk, anyway?
به اون لعنتي ي فتي؟
I told him I was Mrs. Sam Rothstein.
بهش فتم خانم سام راستين هستم
Well, you might as well get something out of it.
خب، زورت زياده تو يزهايي مثل اين
Well, it wasn't long...
... خب، خيلي طول نکشيد
before what I was afraid was gonna happen happened.
از يزي که ميترسيدم اتفاق بيفته، اتفاق افتاد
Nicky managed to get himself banned from every casino in Las Vegas.
نيکي کاري کرد که خودشو از هر کازينويي تو لاس واس محروم کرد
And from then on, I couldn't be seen talking to him anywhere in Vegas or near it.
و از اون به بعد، نتونستم در هر جايي تو لاس واس باهاش حرف بزنم
What the fuck is that supposed to mean?
منظور از اين مسخره بازي يه؟
"He will be ejected from any casino in Las Vegas.
اون از هر کازينويي تو لاس واس رانده شده
And the casinos can be fined as much as $100,000...
و تو کازينوهايي هم که يداش بشه ... صد هزار جريمه ميشن
every time he shows up. "
هر وقت که اراده کنه
- You believe this shit? - Yeah, I believe it. You got banned.
اين مزخرفات رو باور ميکني - آره، باور ميکنم، ممنوع شدي
"Because of notorious and unsavory reputation... "
به خاطر بدنامي و بي آبرويي
Motherfucker!
Motherfucker!
Is there any way around this?
راهي وجود داره؟
No, there's no way.
نه، هي راهي وجود نداره
Let's say, for instance...
... بهتره واضح تر بهت بم که
I wanna go in a restaurant, which happens to be in the casino...
ميخوام به رستوراني برم که اتفاقا تو يه کازينو قرار داره
to get one of those sandwiches I like?
و ساندويي رو که دوست دارم بيرم
Forget it. You can't even set foot in the parking lot.
فراموشش کن، حتي نميتوني اتو از ارکين بزاري اونورتر
That's how serious it is.
اينقدر جديه
In other words, I'm fucked?
به عبارت ديه بدبخت شدم؟
In so many words, yes.
از جهات مختلف، آره
It just didn't sink into his head about the Black Book and what it meant.
فقط آخرش تو کلم نرفت منظورشون از ليست سياه يه
Not being able to go into a casino is one thing...
رفتن به کازينو يه يزه
but being in this book etched your name into the brains of every cop and FBI agent.
و بودن تو ليست سياه طوري که تو کله هر مامور و بازرس اف بي آي باشي يه يز ديه ست
I mean, you're listed in there with Al Capone. But Nicky didn't care.
يعني، تو ليست با آل کاون هم رديفي ولي نيکي اهميتي نداد
I gotta do something. They ain't gettin' rid of me.
بايد يه کاري کنم اونا دست از سرم بر نميدارن
They're not gettin' rid of me. I'm stayin' here.
اينجا ميمونم
Fuck 'em. Fuck 'em.
Fuck 'em. Fuck 'em.
So, once they pulled that shit...
... بنابراين ، يه بار که اين کارو بکنن
I started doin' my own things nobody ever thought of doin'.
منم کارهاي مخصوص خودم رو انجام ميدم طوري که هيکس نفهمه يکار ميکنم
To keep an eye on things, I brought in my kid brother, Dominick, and some desperados...
براي اينکه مواظب همه يز باشم، به برادرم ... دومينيک و برخي از جنايت کارها رو آوردم
and started knockin' over high-rollers, casino bosses...
و شروع به فهموندن قوانين ... به بازيکن ها و روساي کازينوها
bookmakers... anybody right here in town.
... دلال ها و هر کسي که تو شهر بود کرديم
I had a good fuckin' crew goin' for me, I'll tell you that.
ميخواستم يه روه خوب تشکيل بدم
I had Sal Fusco, a great second-story guy.
من سال فوسکو رو داشتم سر دوم داستان بزر
Jack Hardy. He worked for a safe company before he did a six-year bit.
جک هاردي، اون براي يه کماني کار ميکرد قبل از محکوميت 6 سالش
And then there was Bernie Blue. This guy can bypass any alarm for me.
و بعد اونجا باني بلو بود اين شخص هر نوع دزد يري رو برام از کار مينداخت
It was like old times.
مثل زمانهاي قديم شده بود
And I opened up my own jewelry store too, the "Gold Rush. "
و من جواهر فروشي خودم رو به اسم ولد راش باز کردم
Sometimes I used to go along on a heist, just for the fun of it.
بعضي وقت ها تنهايي دزدي ميکردم، فقط براي سررمي
But I didn't like the people I was rippin' off looking at me...
ولي مردمي رو که موقع سرقت ... نام کنن دوست ندارم
so I used to turn their fuckin' pictures around.
براي همين عکس کوفتي شون رو بر ميردونم
- What's takin' so long? - This is a motherfucker!
را اينقدر طولش دادي؟ - !اين مادرجنده -
- It's working. - Learn how to open these things so you don't have to take 'em.
باز نميشه - ياد بير طوري بازشون کني تا مجبور نشي حملشون کني -
Some of these stones got a lot of niggers in them.
بعضي از اين سن هاي اين يارو کاکاسياهه شفاف نيستن
Tell Pepe if he's switching stones on us, he better take a camel back to Nigeria.
بهش بو، اه عوضش کرده باشه بهتره با شتر بررده نيجريه
Yeah?
متشکر -
- They're in Penthouse K. - Check in alone?
بله، اونا تو نت هاوس هستن - تنها؟
- They checked in alone. - Are they out now?
تنهايي اونجا هستن - الان بيرونن؟ -
- Yes. Don't worry. - All right. Thanks.
آره، نران نباش - باشه، متشکر -
He had tipsters all over town. Bellmen.
اونا مزد بيرهاي تو تمام شهر داشتن، جار زن
- But you got to hurry. - Yeah, okay.
ولي بايد عجله بکني - آره، باشه -
- Valet parkers. - They're just checking in now.
ارکبان ها - الان دارن ک ميکنن -
Okay, I'll tell him.
باشه بهش ميم
- Pit bosses. - Room 1230 at the Scirocco.
روساي بخش - اتاق 1230 تو سيريکو -
- Mint condition coins. - Mint condition? All right.
وزراي امور، وضعيت سبزه وضعيت سبزه؟ باشه
And they all got a piece of the score.
هر کدومشون قسمتي از کارو انجام ميدادن
Car's coming.
ماشين ها اومدن
They were very careful.
اونها خيلي مراقب بودن
They always bypassed the alarms, or else...
هميشه آژيرها رو ... خنثي ميکردن، يا
if not, they'd drill enough holes to knock through the walls with a sledgehammer.
با دريل و تک سوراخ هايي در ديوار ايجاد ميکردن
Nicky was grabbing everything he could.
نيکي هريزي رو که مي تونست ميبرد
Nobody out there was expecting a guy like him.
تو اون اطراف هيکس ديه اي شبيه به اون نبود
For Nicky, Las Vegas was the fucking wild west.
براي نيکي، لاس واس همون غرب وحشي بود
I just got a shipment of diamonds from Israel.
تازه يه محموله الماس از اسرائيل آورده بودم
What the fuck they expect from me? I had to earn, didn't I?
اونها ه انتظاري از من داشتن؟ بايد کسب درآمد ميکردم، اينطور نيست؟
You know, this diamond has flaws in it.
ميدوني اين الماس خدشه داره
- There's no flaws. - I'm doing this for 25 years.
هي خدشه اي نداره - به من نو، 25 ساله تو اين کارم -
You better clean your loupe, because there's no flaws.
بهتره ذره بينت رو اک کني ون خدشه اي نداره
Whenever we got local merch...
... هر موقع تجارت داخلي مي کرديم
we'd usually send it to Palm Springs or Arizona, L.A.
اجناس رو به الم اسرينز يا آريزونا و لس آنجلس ميفرستاديم
I had a couple of sand niggers out there. You know, Arabs.
براي ند تا کاکاسياه در اونطرف، ميدوني، عرب ها
What, are you gonna have a fucking meeting here?
ي، اينجا يه جلسه تشکيل دادين؟
I know his language.
اين زبان رو ميفهمم
Forty thousand dollars. The whole package.
هل هزار دلار همشو
Twenty thousand. That's my final offer.
بيست هزار يشنهاد نهايي
He suddenly talks English. Let's talk Turkey here. Twenty-five thousand.
ناهان انليسي صحبت کرد، بيا ترکي حرف بزنيم، بيست و نج هزار تا
I actually turned my bedroom into a bank vault...
اتاق خوابم رو به اتاق بانک تبديل کرده بودم
where I kept the choice stuff.
يزهاي تک رو اونجا نه ميداشتم
I couldn't leave it at the Gold Rush...
نميتونستم اونها رو تو ولد راش بذارم
in case we got raided by the cops...
... در صورت حمله ليس ها
or if my crew got cute.
يا اه يکي از اعضاي روهم خواست کاري کنه
I had the only key. Jennifer didn't give a fuck.
تنها کليد يش من بود جنيفر که هي اهميتي نميداد
She used to fall asleep on the couch watching TV.
اون فقط بلد بود جلوي تلويزيون رت بزنه
This stuff was all mine. I didn't send any of this back home.
تمام اينها مال خودم بود هيکدوم از اينها رو نفرستادم خونه
Actually, I couldn't, because I wasn't even supposed to be doin' it.
راستش، نميتونستم، براي اينکه اصلا قرار نبود اين کارو بکنم
The bosses were making so much fucking money with the casinos...
رييس ها اونقدر از اون کازينوي لعنتي ... ول در مي آوردن که
that they didn't want anybody makin' any waves for them.
نميخواستن کسي هي مشکلي براشون درست کنه
You gave all the guys in your crew a piece of that?
از اين يزها به اعضاي روهت ميدي؟
- I took care of everybody. - Yeah?
هواي همشونو دارم - آره؟ -
That's why there was no real organized street stuff in Vegas before I came here.
هي روه سازمان يافته خياباني تو واس نبود قبل از اينکه بيام اينجا
But how much cash could I bury in my closet?
ولي مه قدر ول نقد ميتونستم تو کمد قايم کنم؟
You have to understand, and I'm sure you do...
بايد درکم کني ... و مطمئنم که تو هم
that in a venture of this kind...
در سرمايه ذاري هايي ... از اين نوع
you have to be prepared to take some kind of loss.
بايد آماده بعضي از ضررها باشي
So I put some of the money into legitimate deals with Charlie Clark, Ace's banker.
س اين ول ها رو مشروع کرده و با ارلي کلارک مدير بانک آيس معامله کردم
You will try to push it through, won't you, Mr. Clark?
شما موافقيد مه نه، آقاي کلارک؟
- Yes. - I'm giving you 50,000 cash.
بله نجاه هزار نقد بهت ميدم
Then I put some more money into legitimate places, like my restaurant.
بعدش مقدار بيشتري از ول رو در جاهايي، مثل رستوران سرمايه ذاري کردم
- Is that the last one? - Yeah.
آخريش بود؟ - آره -
I had my kid brother, Dominick, run it for me.
به برادرم دومينيک رو اونجا ذاشتم تا برام اداره اش کنه
Fuckers.
Fuckers.
- Here you go, guys. - All right.
تشريف ميبرين، آقايون - درسته -
- Thanks a lot. - Yeah. Enjoy. Have a good time.
خيلي متشکر - آره، خوش بذرونيد -
Choke on it, motherfucker.
خفه تون کنه، مادرجنده ها
- Hey, Dom. - How ya doin'?
هي، دومينيک - طوري؟ -
Yeah, Nicky loved restaurants. He was a real restaurant buff.
آره، نيکي رستوران ها رو دوست داشت اون يه رستوران دار واقعي بود
And over the years, he always made money with it.
و سال هاي زيادي از اونجا ول در آورد
In Vegas, he had the Leaning Tower. It was a very popular spot.
در واس، اون يه برج زده بود که بسيار محبوب بود
He had politicians, showgirls and movie stars hanging out all over the place.
سياست مدارها، دختران نمايش و ستاره هاي سينما همه جا ديده ميشدن
That show over at the Flamingo gets better and better.
نمايشتون به اسم فلامينو همينطور بهتر و بهتر ميشه
By the way, Sammy said, whenever you have a minute, give him a call.
سامي فت هر موقع وقت کردي باهاش تماس بير
- Made a messenger out of you too, huh? - Anything for a buck.
از تو هم به عنوان يغام رسون استفاده کرد، ها؟ - همه يز براي وله -
- He does it to everybody. Enjoy your dinner. - Thanks.
اين کارو با همه ميکنه، از غذاتون لذت ببرين - متشکر -
But I gotta tell you, the thing Nicky liked most was the showgirls, naturally.
ولي بايد بهتون بم، نيکي از نمايش دخترها لذت ميبرد، به طور طبيعي
I mean, to them, Nicky was the movie star.
منظورم اينه که، از نظر نيکي، اونها ستاره سينما بودن
- You walk past me? - Hey, this is Shelly.
ميخواي تو ذشته ام قدم بزني؟ - سلام، اين شرليه -
- Hey, Shelly. How are you? - Hi.
سلام، شرلي، حالت طوره؟ - سلام -
- And this is Stacy. - Stacy.
و اينم استيسيه - استيسي -
- This is Nick. Wanna have dinner? - Pleasure.
منم نيکم، ميخواي يه شام با هم باشيم - باعث افتخاره -
Let's check the kitchen first. Excuse us one second.
اول به آشزخونه سر بزنيم - يه لحظه ما رو ببخشيد -
Come on. I'll show you. I fly stuff in fresh every day.
زود باش، ميخوام نشونت بدم يزهاي تميز رو هر روز مييرم
I get bread from back home. I get fish from California.
نون رو ازشهر خودمون مي يرم ماهي رو از کاليفرنيا
And you can always tell a great kitchen like ours because of the milk-fed veal.
و ميدوني آشزخونه بزري مثل اين ميتونه هميشه شير و وشت وساله داشته باشه
That's the secret. See, milk-fed veal is pure white.
اين يه رازه ميبيني شير و وشت وساله قدر خالصه
Out here they got that pink veal. Slide over, honey.
خارج از اينجا، همه از وشت صورتي استفاده ميکنن علاوه بر اين، عزيزم
Now, pink veal, you can pound that shit for two days.
وشت صورتي رو بايد 2 روز بکوبي
It'll never, ever get tender. You know what I mean?
زود تر از اين نميشه منظورمو ميفهمي؟
I left here with the money. Got muscled on the street.
تو اين جا ول ريختم تو کوه و خيابون با زور بازو کار کردم
A couple guys, I owe them. So I gave them the money.
به ند تا از اين آقايون مديونم بنابراين ميخوام بهشون ول بدم
- That's what I did. - Yeah?
اين کارو کردم - آره؟ -
- Yeah. - You call yourself a man?
آره - تو به خودت ميي مرد؟ -
You know you're a lyin' lowlife, motherfuckin' gamblin' degenerate prick?
ميدوني يه دروغ و، مادرجنده متقلب، فاسد، ابله هستي؟
You know that's what you are? Two small kids at home.
ميدوني شبيه به ي هستي؟ دو به کويک تو خونه داري
I gave you money to pay the fuckin' rent...
ول رو براي رداخت ... اجاره خونه لعنتي
and buy groceries, put the heat on.
و خريد مواد غذايي سيستم رمايشي دادم
Your wife called Frankie and told him the fuckin' heat's off.
زنت به فرانکي زن زده و بهش فتته سيستم رمايشي خاموشه
And you didn't gamble that fuckin' money?
و اونوقت با اون ول لعنتي قمار کردي؟
- No? You didn't? - I didn't...
نه؟ نکردي؟ - نه نکردم -
Don't fuck with me, Al! Don't make a fuck outta me.
منو مسخره نکن، آل فکر نکن احمقم
You wanna embarrass me and make a fool outta me? You didn't gamble?
ميخواي منو خر کني؟ تو قمار نکردي؟
Tell me you gambled the fuckin' money...
بهم بو که با اون ول کوفتي قمارکردي
I'll give you the fuckin' money to put the fuckin' heat on!
تا بهت ول بدم که باهاش !سيستم رمايي رو درست کني
Did you gamble? Huh?
قمار کردي؟ ها؟
Fuckin' degenerate.
فاسد به درد نخور
Fuckin' kids at home.
با وجود اون به ها تو خونه
Here. Get the fuck outta here.
بيا، م شو بيرون
- Thanks, Nick. - Yeah, thanks.
متشکرم، نيک - آره، تشکر کن -
Let me find out you fucked up. I'll leave you where I find you.
اه دوباره بفهمم ند زدي همون جا که يدات کردم ولت مي کنم
How many of these you gonna eat?
ند تا از اينا ميخوري؟
- Two. - Two?
دو - دو تا؟ -
But around 6:30 in the morning, when he finished his day...
ولي وقتي شش و نيم صبح ... کارش تموم ميشد
no matter where he was or what he was doing...
فرقي براش نداشت کجاست ... يا مشغول به ه کاريه
he always went home to make breakfast for his son, Nicky boy.
هميشه بر ميشت خونه تا براي سرش نيکي صبحونه درست کنه
I know you like this. A little butter, right?
ميدونم که اينو دوست داري کمي کره، درسته؟
- Not a lot. You know why, right? - Yeah.
نه خيلي زياد، ميدوني را؟ - آره -
- Why? - 'Cause it clogs up your heart.
را؟ - ون به قلب آسيب ميرسونه -
What a smart kid you are. Okay, eat.
ه سر با هوشي هستي تو خيله خب، بخور
Every couple of weeks, I used to send Marino...
هر ند هفته يه بار ... مارينو رو ميفرستادم
back to the bosses with a piece of what I made.
يش رئيس ها با قطعه اي که ساخته بودم
Not a bit piece, but what did they know?
نه خيلي کم ولي اونها ه ميدونستن؟
They were 1,500 miles away, and I don't know anybody who can see that far.
يک و نيم مايل دورتر بودن و نميتونستن مسافت به اين دوري رو ببينن
Their drop was a truck stop garage...
محل تجمعشون ... يه اراژ کاميون بود
where Remo and the guys used to hang out and count their millions.
که ريمو و رفقاش ول هاي ميليوني شون رو شمارش ميکردن
- Remo. - Hey, Frankie.
ريمو - سلام، فرانکي
The cops knew, but they didn't give a fuck.
ليس ها اينو مي دونستن ولي به تخمشون نبود
Nicky sends his warmest regards.
نيکي رمترين سلام ها رو فرستاد
I knew how to keep the bosses happy.
ميدونستم طوري رييس ها رو خوشحال نه دارم
Whenever they gave me little jobs to do...
... هر وقت کار کويکي رو بهم ميسردن
I would carry things out to a "T."
به بهترين شکل انجامش ميدادم
Like the time Tony Dogs, who's supposed to be the new maniac tough guy in town...
مثل موقعي که توني سه ... ديوانه وار ميخواست شهر رو کنترل کنه
shot up one of Remo's bars.
به يکي از افراد ريمو شليک کرده بود
Here's a fuckin' guy kills two of Remo's guys...
اين يارويي که اينجاست ... دو تا از آدم هاي ريمو رو کشته بود
and a poor fuckin' waitress who was just workin' on her night off, of all things.
و دو تا از يشخدمت هاي بدبختي رو که فقط اونجا تمام شب رو کار ميکردن
I mean, this guy's just beggin' to be made an example of.
منظورم اينه که، اين يارو فقط التماس ميکنه تا نمونه ازش درست نکنيم
Frankie, I want the names of all the other people he had with him.
فرانکي، اسم تمام کساني که باهاش کار ميکنن رو ميخوام
And I don't care what you have to do to 'em to get 'em, understand?
و برام فرقي نميکنه باهاشون يکار ميکني، فهميدي؟
- I'll take care of it, Remo. - And mow 'em down.
مراقب اونها هستم، ريمو رسواشون کن
To be truthful with you, I had to admire this guy.
حقيقتو بخواين اين آدمو تحسين ميکنم
He was one of the toughest Irishmen I ever met.
اون يکي از سرسخت ترين ايرلندي هايي بود که تا حالا ملاقات کرده بودم
This son of a bitch was tough.
اون حرومزاده خيلي مقاومت کرد
For two days and two fuckin' nights we beat the shit outta this guy.
براي 2 روز و 2 شبانه روز اين يارو رو کتک زديم
We even stuck ice picks in his balls.
حتي تخم هاشو انداختيم تو يخ
- Better give me a name soon, or I'm gonna give him yours, Frank. - Thanks a lot.
بهتره زودتر يه اسم بهم بي، يا تو رو بهشون ميدم، فرانکي - مرحمت زياد -
- But he never talked. - I know you would've ratted by now.
ولي اون حرفي نزد - ميدونم که ميتوني حرف بزني -
In the end, I had to put his fuckin' head in a vise.
آخر سر، مجبور شدم سر لعنتيش رو لاي يره بذارم
Dogs, Dogs, can you hear me, Dogs?
سه، سه صدامو ميشنوي، سه؟
Listen to me, Anthony. I got your head in a vise.
بهم وش بده، آنتوني سرتو لاي يره ميندازم
I'll squash your fuckin' head like a grapefruit if you don't give me a name.
سر لعنتيت رو مثل ري فورت له ميکنم اه يه اسم بهم ندي
Don't make me have to do this. Please. Come on!
منو مجبور به اين کار نکن خواهش ميکنم، زود باش
Don't make me be a bad guy. Come on.
منو آدم بده نکن زود باش
Fuck you!
Fuck you!
This motherfucker. You believe this? Two fuckin' days and nights.
مادرجنده، باورت ميشه؟ دو روز و دو شب لعنتيه
Fuck me? Fuck me? You motherfucker!
Fuck me? Fuck me? تو مادرجنده
Fuck my mother? Is that what you're tellin' me?
بهم فحش ميدي، مادر جنده؟ داري اينو بهم ميي؟
You motherfucker, you! Huh?
تو مادرجنده، ها؟
- Oh, God! - Give me the fuckin' name!
!خدايا !اسم لعنتي رو بهم بو -
Charlie M.
ارلي. ام
- Charlie M.? - Charlie M.
ارلي. ام؟ - ارلي. ام -
You make me pop your fuckin' eye outta your head...
منو مجبور ميکني شم هاتو از سرت بکشم بيرون
to protect that piece of shit, Charlie M.?
از اين تکه وه محافظت ميکني؟ ارلي ام؟
You dumb motherfucker!
!تو احمق مادرجنده
Kill me, you fuck! Kill me!
!منو بکش! کوني !منو بکش
You motherfucker, you!
!تو مادرجنده
Frankie, do him a fuckin' favor.
فرانکي يه لطفي در حقم بکن
The word got around that finally...
آخر کاري که مي خواست انجام شد
there was a real gangster in town.
يه نستر واقعي تو شهر بود
Nicky was the new boss of Las Vegas.
نيکي رييس جديد لاس واس بود
Charlie M.
ارلي. ام
Four reels, sevens, across three $15,000 jackpots.
هار قرقره، هفت حالت انزده هزار جک ات بايد انجام بشه
Do you have any idea what the odds are?
هي ايده اي در مورد جفت اومدنشون داري؟
It's gotta be in the millions, maybe more.
يک در ميليون، شايدم بيشتر
Three fuckin' jackpots in 20 minutes! Why didn't you call me?
سه تا از جک ات ها در 20دقيقه؟ را باهام تماس نرفتي؟
It happened so quick. Three guys won. I didn't have a chance.
خيلي سريع اتفاق افتاد، سه نفر بردن هي شانسي نداشتم
- You didn't see the scam? - There's no way to determine that.
اين کلاهبرداري رو نديدي؟ - هي راهي براش وجود نداشت -
Yes, there is. They won!
بله، وجود داره !اونا بردن
It's a casino. People gotta win sometimes.
اينجا کازينوه بعضي وقت ها هم مردم ميبرن
Ward, you're pissing me off. Now you're insulting my intelligence.
وارد، حسابي ريدي بهم حالا هم هوشم رو زير سوال ميبري؟
You know goddamn well somebody had to get into those machines and set those fuckin' reels.
حتما کسي رو که ميآد و اون ماشينها رو سرويس ميکنه ميشناسي
The probability on one machine is a million and a half to one.
امکان بردن تو اين ماشين يک ميليون و نيم در يکه
On three machines in a row, it's in the billions.
براي سه تا ماشين با هم يک در ميليارده
What's the matter with you?
مشکلت با اين يه؟
Didn't you see you were being set up on the second win?
نديدي که باعث بردن دومي شدي
I think you're overreacting.
فکر ميکنم خيلي زياده روي ميکنيد
Listen, you fuckin' yokel. I've been carrying your ass ever since I got here.
وش کن، دهاتي از موقعي که اينجا اومدي مواظبت بودم
- Get your ass outta here. - You're firing me?
کونت رو بردار، ورتو از اينجا م کن - منو اخراج ميکني؟ -
I'm firing you. No, I'm not firing...
اخراجت ميکنم نه، من اخراجت ميکنم
- You might regret this. - I'll regret it if I keep you.
ممکنه بابتش شيمان بشي آقاي راستين - اه نهت دارم شيمان ميشم
This is not the way to treat people.
اين راه رفتار با مردم نيست
If you didn't know, you're too fuckin' dumb.
وش کن اه نميدوني بدون که احمقي
If you did know, you were in on it.
ار هم ميدوني باز هم هموني
Either way, you're out. Get out. Come on. Let's go.
به هر صورت، برو بيرون زود باش، بزن بريم
The guy's history as far as I'm concerned.
تاريخ مصرف مردم تا وقتيه که من بخوام
But you can't fire him. His brother-in-law is County Commissioner.
ولي تو نمي توني اخراجش کني اون برادر ناتني کميسارياي شهره
Everybody with cowboy boots is a fuckin' county commissioner or related to a commissioner.
که ي، هر کسي با کمه کابوي، تو اين کشور تو کميسيون، يا بخشي از کميسيونه، حالم بهم ميخوره
This is his state. His uncle's chief judge.
اين ايالت اونه عموش رئيس قضاته
His brother-in-law runs the county commission.
برادر ناتنيش تو کميسيون شهره
You're in the finances, you're upstairs.
تو در امور مالي هستي طبقه بالا هستي
But you are not on the floor. You don't see what's going on.
ولي تو که ايين نيستي نميدوني اينجا ه خبره
I've got thousands of players. I've got 500 dealers.
من 1000 تا بازيکن و 500 تا مدير بازي دارم
They're all looking to rob me blind 24 hours a day.
اونا 24 ساعت روز ازم ميدزدن
I have to let them know I'm watching all the details all the time.
بايد بدونن که همه يز رو زير نظر مييرم تمام جزئيات رو تو تمام مدت
There is not one single thing I will not catch.
تنها يه مورد نيست که بم
- Look at yours. Look at that. - Huh?
مال خودتو ناه کن، ناش کن - ها؟ -
Look at this. There's nothing.
اينو ناه کن هيي نيست
Look how many blueberries your muffin has.
ببين قدر تو بلوبريت کشمش ريختن
What are you talking about?
راجع به ي صحبت ميکني؟
If you don't do it yourself, it never gets done.
اه خودت کاري رو انجام ندي هي وقت انجام نميشه
- Where are you going? - # How long can this go on #
کجا ميري؟ - # How long can this go on #
From now on, I want you to put an equal amount of blueberries in each muffin.
از الان، ازتون ميخوام به طور مساوي کشمش تو بلوبري بريزين
An equal amount of blueberries in each muffin.
به مقدار مساوي کشمش تو بلوبري
Do you know how long that's going to take?
هي ميدوني قدر اين کار طول ميکشه؟
I don't care how long it takes. Put an equal amount in each muffin.
برام مهم نيست قدر طول ميکشه مقدار مساوي کشمش بريزين
Just a little. That a girl.
به اين مين دختر
Oh, boy, look. You wanna go to Mommy?
اوه، ببين ميخواي بري يش مامان؟
Wanna come to Mommy? It's all right, sweetheart.
ميخواهي هلوي مامان بياي؟ باشه، عزيز دلم
I need to talk to you. I need some money.
بايد باهات صحبت کنم يه مقدار ول احتياج دارم
- What do you need? - Got her?
قدر ميخواي؟ - ببرش -
Well, I need a lot. I need more than usual.
خب، مقدار زيادي ميخوام بيشتراز مقدار هميشي
Why don't you take it out of your account?
را از حساب بيرون نميکشي؟
I would, you know, Sam, it's just that...
ميخوام، ميدوني، سام ... موضوع اينه که
Well, I need more than that. I need $25,000.
خب، بيشتر از اون هم ميخوام احتياج به 25000 تا دارم
Twenty-five thousand? For yourself?
براي خودت؟
- Yeah. - Why do you need that much?
آره - براي ي اونقدر زياد -
What's the difference? I just need it.
ه فرقي داره؟ فقط احتياج دارم
Well, I gotta ask you. That's a lot of money.
خب، بايد ازت برسم ول زياديه
You're not asking for a box of popcorn.
تو که نميخواي يه جعبه ا کورن بخري؟
We don't have to turn this into a big deal.
لازم نيست زياد بزرش کنيم بابتش قول داديم
Okay? We don't have to have a fight.
باشه؟ احتياجي به دعوا نيست
It's important to me. Just something I wanted to do.
برام مهمه فقط بعضي وقت ها لازمش دارم
Who's fighting? I mean, tell me what it's for.
کي دعوا ميکنه؟ منظورم اينه که، بهم بو براي يه
Why can't you tell me what it's for? Huh?
را نميتوني بهم بي؟ ها؟
Well, you know what? Now I want you to tell me.
خب، ميدوني يه؟ حالا ميخوام بهم بي
My wife comes to me and asks me for 25,000. What do you want, a coat?
همسرم مياد يشم و ازم ميرسه که بيست و نج هزار تا دارم، براي ي ميخواي، يه کت؟
- No. - If you want a coat, you got it.
نه - اه يه کت ميخواي، بيرش -
It's not the money. It's just, why do you want it? Am I not entitled to ask that?
موضوع ول نيست، فقط، براي ي لازمش داري؟ حقم نيست که بدونم؟
Sam, I've been independent my whole life. I never had to ask anybody for anything.
سام، تو تمام زنديم مستقل بودم هي وقت براي هي يز به کسي جواب ندادم
- Now you're making me beg. - What are you talking about?
حالا منو مجبور ميکني دايي کنم - راجع به ي صحبت مي کني -
And you're embarrassing me. Why do you want to make me feel so bad?
و تو منو تو فشار ميذاري را يه کاري ميکني که احساس بدي کنم
You're asking me for 25,000. I'm not out to make you feel bad.
تو از من 25000دلار ميخواي منم نميخوام در تو احساس بدي ايجاد کنم
I want to just be able to trust you.
فقط ميخوام بهت اطمينان يدا کنم
You know, it's about trust.
ميدوني در مورد اعتماده
I have to be able to trust you with my life.
بايد بتونم به تو در زنديم اعتماد يدا کنم
Do you understand?
متوجه ميشي؟
Can I trust you?
ميتونم بهت اعتماد کنم؟
Answer me. Can I trust you?
جوابمو بده، ميتونم بهت اعتماد کنم؟
You can trust me.
ميتوني بهم اعتماد کني
Good. So then you could tell me what the money is for.
خوبه، س ميتوني بهم بي اون ولو براي ي ميخواهي
# You've got to #
# You've got to #
# Give a little #
# Give a little #
# Take a little #
# Take a little #
# And let your poor heart #
# And let your poor heart #
# Break a little #
# Break a little #
Yeah, she's leaving the bank now.
آره، همين الان بانک رو ترک کرد
All right, I'm gonna follow her.
باشه خودم دنبالش ميکنم
What is that?
اون يه؟
I know that look. What does that look mean?
اين ناهو ميشناسم اين ناه ه معني داره؟
It means I got the money.
يعني که ولو رفتم
# You've got to #
# You've got to #
- # Give a little # - Yes, you're way up on top now.
- # Give a little # - Yes, you're way up on top now.
# Take a little ##
# Take a little ##
How are you doin', Les? It's Lester, right?
حالت طوره، لس؟ لستر، درسته؟
Sam.
سام
From my recollection, aren't you the card shark...
تو سعي نکردي
the golf hustler, the pimp from Beverly Hills?
از لف دزدي و جيب بري کني تو بورلي هيلز؟
If I'm wrong, please correct me.
اه اشتباه ميکنم لطفا دقيق تر بهم بو
'Cause I never knew you to be a heist man.
ون هرز نميدونستم که دزد هم هستي
But if you are, you know what?
ولي اه هستي ميدوني يه؟
Here, take mine too.
بيا مال منم بردار
Go ahead. Take it. 'Cause you already have hers.
زود باش، برش دار ون مال اون رو هم برداشتي
She's my wife. Look at me.
اون زن منه به من ناه کن
You did know that, didn't you? You knew that she's my wife?
اينو ميدونستي؟ ميدونستي؟ ميدونستي که اون همسرمه؟
- Hey, look at me. - Yeah, I know that.
ها؟ هي، منو ناه کن - آره، ميدونستم -
You know, yeah?
که ميدونستي، آره؟
But if you ever come back again, ever...
ولي ار هر موقع ديه ... بر ردي، هر موقع
to take her money, next time bring a pistol.
که ولشو بيري دفعه بعد يه يستول بيار
That way you got a chance.
اونطوري شانس اين کارو داري
Be a man. Don't be a fucking pimp.
مرد باش نه يه بزدل ترسو
Now, you wanna do me a favor? Get outta here.
حالا، يه لطفي در حقم بکن م شو از اينجا
I wanna be alone with my wife. Get up and get outta here.
ميخوام با همسرم تنها باشم بلند شو و م شو از اينجا
- And you want to be free. - # Take a little #
# Take a little #
- Fuckin' piece of shit. - That's fuckin' bullshit.
کثافت تکه وه - همش مزخرفه -
- # That's the story # - Well, darling, I guess it's best...
- # That's the story # - Well, darling, I guess it's best...
- # That's the glory of love # - that we should part.
- # That's the glory of love # - that we should part.
Remember when you called him that night and said good-bye?
يادته وقتي اون شب زن زدي و بهش فتي به اميد ديدار؟
He didn't say, "Don't get married. I'll be right down. "
اون فت، ازدواج نکن الان ميام
- He didn't say that to you, did he? - No, he didn't.
همونو بهت فت، مه نه؟ - نه، نفت -
No. Instead, what did he say?
نه، بر عکس، س ي فت؟
"Fuck him. Take him for everything he's got. "
به ورش هر ي که داره برش دار
Come here. I want to show you something.
بيا اينجا ميخوام يه يزي رو بهت نشون بدم
- # That's the story # - The second letter came right after I gave you your start.
- # That's the story # - The second letter came right after I gave you your start.
No! No! No!
!نه! نه! نه
No! Make 'em stop it!
نه! وادارشون کن بس کنن
No! No!
!نه! نه
It's not his fault! It's my fault!
!تقصير اون نبود !تقصير من بود
No!
!نه
- Fuck! Fuck! - Piece of shit.
- Fuck! Fuck! کثافت وه -
Do it yourself, you chickenshit cocksucker!
خودتي جوجه وه، کير خور
He's such a prick!
احمق نادان
He had some guy from the hotel beat him up.
يکي رو از از هتل وادار کرد تا اونو بزنه
He didn't want to do it himself.
نمي خواست خودش اين کارو بکنه
Oh, no, he didn't want to get his own hands dirty.
اوه، نه، نميخواست دستاشو کثيف کنه
So why did he have to do that, huh?
س را اون کارو کرد، ها؟
Tell me.
بهم بو
- I know it wasn't a nice thing to do... - No shit.
ميدونم که کار جالبي نکرده - به هي وجه -
You gotta understand it. He doesn't know if this guy is shaking you down...
بايد بفهمي، اون هيي درباره اين يارو که باهات بود نميدونست
No. No. I told him all about this guy before we ever got married.
نه، نه، من درباره اون قبل از ازدواجمون فته بودم
- This is no fucking surprise. - Oh, you did? I didn't know that.
اين يه سورايز نبود - اوه، واقعا؟ اينو نميدونستم
He's just a friend of mine I was trying to help. So what?
اون فقط يکي از دوستانمه که ميخوام بهش کمک کنم، که ي؟
You know, the first time I ever saw you guys together...
ميدوني، اولين باري که ... شما دو تا رو با هم ديدم
I never saw him so happy.
هرز اونو اينقدر خوشحال نديده بودم
I mean, I know he's a crazy Jew fuck and everything...
منظورم اينه که، ميدونم ... اون يه يهودي ديوونه از هر لحاظه
but I never seen him act like that with anybody else.
ولي هرز اونو انقدر خوشحال با کسه ديه اي نديده بودم
I think he's crazy about you. I mean, he really loves you.
فکر ميکنم ديوانه وار تو رو ميخواد يعني، واقعا دوست داره
Come on. I went into this with my eyes open, you know.
بس کن، ميخوام شم هاتو باز کني، ميدوني
I knew the bottom could drop out at any time.
ميدونم که هر اتفاقي، تو هر موقعيتي ممکنه بيفته
You don't think I'm gonna go into a situation like this...
فکر نکن خودمو تو نين حالتي قرار دادم
if I don't think I'm gonna get covered on the back end.
فکر نکنم تا آخر کار در امان باشم
- Sure, I can see that. - Right?
البته، ميتونم بفهمم درسته؟ -
So I put aside some jewelry for me. A lot of jewelry.
براي همين مقداري جواهر کنار ذاشتم مقدار زيادي جواهر
You mean like a lot of expensive jewelry? About how much?
منظورت از مقدار زياد جواهر قدره؟ تقريبا قدر؟
You want to steal it?
ميخواي بدزديش؟
No. I'm just curious. I was wondering...
نه، فقط کنجکاوم ... ميخواستم بدونم که
how much he would put into a thing like that.
قدر ميتونه داشته باشه، همين
I'm told it's worth about a million dollars, maybe more.
فتم که حدود يک ميليون شايد هم بيشتر
Well, there you go. What does that tell you?
خب، بفرما ي بهت فتم؟
A million dollars in jewelry.
يک ميليون دلار جواهرات
Does that tell you the guy is crazy about you?
بهت فتم که اون ديوانه وار تو رو ميخواد
I should've never married him. He's a Gemini.
نبايد هيج وقت باهاش ازدواج ميکردم اون دو روئه
Triple Gemini. Duality.
سه شخصيتي، دواني
Gemini is the snake, you know. You can't trust a snake.
مار دو روئه، ميدوني که نبايد به مار اعتماد کرد
I mean it.
اينو باور دارم
I know what you mean. Listen, Ginger.
ميدونم منظورت يه وش کن، جينجر
You know, this is probably not... I don't have the answers anyway.
... ميدوني، احتمال داره که هر سوالي رو اسخ ندي
- This is probably not what you want to hear... - I do.
اونه رو که ميخواي نياز به شنيدن نداره - ميدونم
'Cause you're a little upset, and I understand that.
ون يه ذره غميني و من درکت ميکنم
But I think you should try to make the best of it now. Go slow. See what happens.
ولي فکر ميکنم، بايد بري جلو و بهترين تلاشت رو بکني آروم برو، و ببين ه اتفاقي ميفته
He could've killed him! Okay? He could've killed him. He didn't have to hit him.
ميتونست اونو بکشه! خب؟ ميتونست اونو بکشه، نه اينکه تنبيه اش کنه
It's not like I'm sleeping with the guy.
حتي فکر اينو که با اون بخوابمو ندارم
He makes me sneak around to see my own friends. What is that all about?
اون منو مجبور کرده دزدکي به ديدن دوست هام برم، اين ه معني ميده؟
I guess it's 'cause he loves you so much, he's jealous and worried.
حدس ميزنم خيلي دوست داره براي همين حسود و نرانه
He gives a fuck what I do.
اون ريد به کارهايي که انجام دادم
Look, I'll try to find out what the hell is going on.
ببين، سعي ميکنم بفهمم ه اتفافي داره ميفته
- When I see him, I'll talk to him. - Okay.
وقتي ببينمش، باهاش حرف ميزنم - باشه -
- All right? - Yeah.
باشه؟ -
Thanks. Thanks for putting up with me.
متشکر، متشکر براي همراهيت
Take it easy with this shit. This can only make matters worse.
سخت نير، باهاش کنار بيا سعي کن راحت باشي
You're a beautiful girl. I've seen a lot of girls get shot to hell from this.
تو دختر زيبايي هستي، دخترهاي زيادي رو ديدم که در اثر نين موردي تباه شدن
You're so nice.
تو خيلي خوبي
Come on, now. I don't wanna see you unhappy.
بجنب، نميخوام غمين ببينمت
- # These eyes before us # - Thanks.
- # These eyes before us # - Thanks.
# Just what the truth is #
# Just what the truth is #
- Thank you. - It's all right.
متشکر - همه يز درست ميشه -
# I can't say anymore #
# I can't say anymore #
# 'Cause I love you #
# 'Cause I love you #
# Yes, I love you... ##
# Yes, I love you... ##
Mr. Rothstein, County Commissioner Pat Webb is here to see you.
آقاي راستين، عضو کميسيون شهر ت وب، اينجاست، ميخواد شما رو ببينه
- Give me a minute. - Okay. Just a minute.
يه دقيقه بهم وقت بده - باشه، فقط يک دقيقه ديه -
Mr. Webb, can I get you anything?
آقاي وب، ميتونم کاري براتون بکنم؟
Uh, no. No, thank you, little lady.
اوه، نه، نه، متشکر خانم کوولو
Okay, send him in. Then call me four minutes after.
خوب، بفرستش تو بعد از 4 دقيقه باهام تماس بير
- Mr. Rothstein, I'm Pat Webb. - How do you do?
آقاي راستين، من ت وب هستم - حالتون طوره؟ -
- Hey, it is a pleasure. - I heard a lot about you.
هي، باعث افتخاره - دربارت زياد شنيدم -
Oh, thank you, sir. Hey, house is doin' well.
اوه، متشکرم قربان - هي، همه ي توي خونه مرتبه -
Hey, all that money is rollin' in.
هي، همه اون ول ها در روشه
I appreciate you takin' the time to see a poor civil servant.
از اينکه وقتتون رو براي ديدن يه کارمند فقير ذاشتين، قدرداني ميکنم
- Why don't you have a seat, hmm? - Oh, thank you, sir.
را نمي شينيد؟ - اوه، متشکرم، قربان -
I come here personally to kind of smooth over...
شخصا به اينجا اومدم تا ... مشکلاتي رو
any fracas about a certain matter.
که به وجود اومده، ييري کنم
See, uh, maybe you didn't know it...
شايد، اه، شما خبر نداشته باشيد
but Don Ward is a very well-liked man in this town.
ولي دن وارد مرد خوب و شناخته شده اي تو اين شهره
He's got lots of friends. Nice family and their money go back many, many years.
اون دوستان زيادي داره، خانواده خوب و ول بسيار زيادي براي ندين و ند سال
Now friends vote. Family and money votes.
حالا دوستان راي ميدن خانواده و ول راي ميدن
That's important to me and you.
اين مهمه هم براي من، هم شما
And if you'll think about our little problem along them lines...
و اه شما فکر ميکنيد ... مشکل کوک ما در امتداد خطوطي
and you'll forgive me for sayin' it...
که با شما به وجود اومده منو بابت اين حرف ببخشيد
maybe he did not deserve to be fired.
شايد بهتر بود که اخراج نميشد
I'm sorry, but he knew about our getting hit...
متاسفم، ولي اون ... درباره ضربه اي که به ما خورد اطلاع داشت
on three big machines in a row, and he did nothing about it.
سه دستاه بزر کنار هم و اون هي کاري انجام نداد
That means, either he was in on it or he was too dumb to see what was goin' on.
اين معني رو داره که، يا خودش در قضيه دست داشته يا آنقدر احمق بوده که نفهميده ي شده
Either way, I cannot have a man like that working here.
به هر صورت، نميتونم اجازه بدم نين آدمي اينجا کار کنه
Before we point the dirty end of the stick at old Don...
قبل از اينکه به قسمت کثيف دان ير توجه کنيم
we better be sure we can prove them charges.
بهتره مطمئن شيم که مي تونيد اتهامات رو ثابت کنيم
Believe me, if I could prove it, he would be under arrest.
باور کنيد، اه مي تونستم ثابت کنم الان تو بازداشت بود
Are, uh...
... آيا، اه
Are we certain that you want the Gaming Control Board...
آيا ميتونيم مطمئن شيم که ... هيئت کنترل بازي
eyeballing your record and your gangster pals like Nicky Santoro.
کارهاي شما و دوست هاي نسترتون مثل نيکي سانتورو رو زارش نميکنن
I think you're way out of line talking to me like that.
فکر ميکنم با صحبت کردن در اين مورد از خط خارج شدين
What you're saying is libelous, and you're in no position to challenge my expertise.
هر ه مييد يه تهمته، و شما در موقعيتي نيستين که تخصص من رو به الش بکشين
I went way out of my way to be very helpful to that kid.
هر کاري از دستم بر بياد براي کمک به اون به انجام ميدم
He's weak. He's incompetent. He jeopardizes the whole place.
اون ضعيفه، بي کفايته اون تمام محيط رو به خطر ميندازه
There's not much more I can do for him.
کار بيشتري نمي تونم براش بکنم
You have got me there.
بايد منو اونجا ببري
Old Don is as useless as tits on a boar.
دان ير يک بي مصرفه
But he is my brother-in-law...
... ولي برادر ناتنيمه
and I would look on it as a personal favor...
و من به اين قضيه به عنوان يه مشکل شخصي ناه مي کنم
if you'd think some more on hirin' him back.
اه ميشه درباره برردوندنش فکر کنيد
I can't do that.
نميتونم اين کارو انجام بدم
I appreciate the fact that he's your brother-in-law...
اين واقعيت رو درک ميکنم که ... اون برادر ناتني شماست
and I do want to help you and I like to do favors.
و ميخوام که به شما کمک کنم و تقاضاتون رو انجام بدم
I know who you are, but I cannot do that.
مي دونم شما کي هستين ولي نميتونم کاري کنم
Well, could there be any position...
خب، هر حالتي ميتونه داشته باشه
farther down the trough?
بيشتر از اين نميتونم
I'm sorry. I can't do anything.
متاسفم هي کاري نمي تونم بکنم
He's too incompetent, and the bottom line is, he cannot be trusted.
اون بيش از حد بي کفايته، و تو خط نيست نميشه بهش اعتماد کرد
Okay. Thanks.
خيله خب، متشکر
Well... you know, that's it. I'm sorry.
خب... ميدونين که همين، متاسفم
Mr. Rothstein, your people never will understand...
آقاي راستين، شما مردم ... هرز اينو نميفهميد
the way it works out here.
بيرون از اينجا کارهاي اصلي انجام ميشه
You're all just our guests.
شما فقط مهمان ما هستين
But you act like you're at home.
ولي طوري رفتار ميکنين انار تو خونه خودتون هستين
Let me tell you something, partner. You ain't home.
بذار يه يزي رو بهت بم، همکار تو در خونه نيستي
But that's where we're gonna send you if it harelips the governor.
ولي ميتونيم هر جايي بفرستيمت اه فرماندار بخواد
- Thank you for your time. - No problem.
براي وقتتون متشکرم - مشکلي نيست -
- Sorry. - You bet.
متاسفم - شرط ببند -
What happened to my pills?
ي به سر قرصهام اومده؟
Huh?
ها؟
Isn't it bad enough you're drinking too much? You're taking my pills too?
کافي نيست اينقدر مشروب ميخوري؟ حالا هم قرص هام رو ميخوري؟
I didn't take your pills.
قرص هات رو بر نداشتم
Look, for my ulcer, I take a half a one of these.
ناه کن، براي زخم معده نصف هر کدوم اينها رو مي خورم
And that's when I have extreme pain.
موقعي که درد شديد داشته باشم اين کارو ميکنم
I had a three-month supply. What did you do with 'em?
براي 3 ماه ذخيره داشتم با اونها يکار کردي؟
You didn't have to beat him up.
نبايد اونو کتک ميزدي
What?
ي؟
I was just trying to help him.
فقط سعي داشتم کمکش کنم
Like I'm sleeping with the guy.
جوري رفتار کردي انار باهاش خوابيدم
Yeah, how do I know?
آره، از کجا بدونم؟
You can't make me stop caring about people.
تو نميتوني منو از توجه کردن به مردم منع کني
What? What?
ي؟ ي؟
I said, you can't make me...
فتم که ... نميتوني منو
stop caring about people.
از توجه به مردم منع کني
Listen... Ginger...
وش کن... جينجر
I'm trying to make the best of everything here, you know?
دارم سعي ميکنم بهترين يزها رو اينجا فراهم کنم، ميدوني؟
I mean, you're my wife, for Christ's sakes.
منظورم اينه که تو همسرم هستي for Christ's sakes.
I mean, people look up to you in this town.
مردم تو رو تو اين شهر ناه مي کنن
You know what, Ace? I don't give a shit!
ميدوني يه، آيس؟ يه ذره هم اهميت نميدم
I'm gettin' out of here. I am.
من از اينجا ميرم من
Come over here. You gotta get hold of yourself.
بيا اينجا بايد هواي خودت رو داشته باشي
- Okay. Okay. - If not for me, at least for Amy.
باشه، باشه - اه براي من نه، حداقل براي امي -
Understand? Your drinking's gettin' way out of hand.
فهميدي؟ مشروب ها رو از دستت دور ميکنم
I'm gonna get you into a program. They got plenty of good ones.
بايد تو رو در برنامه ترک کردن بذارم اونها مجموعه اي از بهترين ها رو دارن
- I don't need one. - Yes, you do. It's very discreet.
نيازي بهش ندارم - را، داري، اين کار خيلي محتاطانه ست
There's no names in the papers.
هي اسمي روي ورقه ها ثبت نميشه
That's all you care about. You don't care about me.
تو به يزهاي ديه اهميت ميدي من برات مهم نيستم
- Yes, I do. - No, you don't.
را، مهمي - نه، نيستم -
How could you say that?
طور ميتوني اينو بي؟
You're a beautiful woman. You're destroying yourself.
تو زن خوشلي هستي داري خودت رو از بين ميبري
You don't need that fuckin' leech living off you.
تو به اين کثافت انل احتياج نداري
I know you better than you know yourself.
تو رو بهتر از خودت مي شناسم
You're a tiger. You're stronger than I am.
تو يه لني تو از من قويتري
When you set your mind on doing something, you do it better than anybody.
وقتي بخواي کاري رو انجام بدي هر يزي رو بهتر از هر کسي انجام ميدي
You're gonna do it. Okay? You'll do it.
ميتوني اين کارو انجام بدي باشه؟ تو ميتوني
Oh, God.
خدايا
Okay.
باشه
I'll try. I'll try.
سعي ميکنم، سعي ميکنم
I'll try. I will.
سعي ميکنم، انجامش بدم
Don't be mad at me, okay?
در موردم بد فکر نکن، باشه؟
I will.
باشه
No matter what the problems were outside the count room...
اهميتي نداره ه مشکلاتي ... بيرون از اتاق شمارش وجود داره
it was all worth it.
همه ي ر ارزشه
The cash kept rollin' in...
... ول در حال سرازير شدنه
and the suitcases kept comin' and goin'.
و مدان ها در حال رفت و آمده
And let me tell you, the fuckin' bottom line here is... cash.
و بذاريد بهتون بم، که اينجا ايه هر يزي... ول نقده
The only problem was that after a while...
تنها يک مشکل بعد از مدتي رخ داد
the bosses noticed that the suitcases were gettin' a little light.
رئيس ها متوجه شدن که مدان ها يه کم سبک تر شدن
Wait a minute. You mean to tell me...
يه لحظه صبر کن ... داري بهم ميي
that the money we're robbing is being robbed?
ولي رو که دزديم دزديده شده؟
Somebody's robbing from us?
يکي ازمون دزدي ميکنه؟
We go through all this trouble and somebody's robbing us?
ما تمام سختي ها رو کشيديم و يکي از ما دزدي ميکنه؟
Huh?
ها؟
Like I said, it's part of the business. It's considered leakage.
همونطور که فتم، اين يه قسمت از کاره اين نشت قابل يش بينيه
Leakage my balls. I want the guy who's robbing us.
نشت تخم هام ميخوام بدونم ه کسي ازمون دزدي ميکنه
Even John Nash... that's the guy who ran the scam...
... حتي اه جان نش ... اون آدمي باشه که کلاهبرداري کرده باشه
he knew there wasn't much he could do about it.
اون ميدونه که کار زيادي ازش ساخته نيست
You gotta know that a guy who helps you steal...
بايد بدوني ... ه کسي در سرقت کمکت ميکنه
even if you take care of him real well...
حتي اه حسابي هواشو داشته باشي
he's gonna steal a little extra for himself.
يه مقدار اضافه تر براي خودش بر ميداره
Makes sense, don't it?
حسش ميکني، مه نه؟
Try and make these hardheaded old greaseballs understand that.
سعي کن اينو به اون مفت خورهاي قديمي بفهموني
What's the point of skimming if we're being skimmed? It defeats the purpose.
هدف از دزدي يه، ار قراره از ما دزدي بشه؟ اين مفهوم کار رو از بين ميبره
Huh?
ها؟
They take this money because they're my guys, so give 'em some leeway.
اونا ول رو بر ميدارن ون از افراد من هستن، بنابراين يه کم منحرف ميشن
But the bosses never believed in leeway...
ولي رئيس ها ... هرز اين انحراف رو باور نميکنن
so listen to what they do.
س وش کردن، ببينن يکار ميتونن بکننن
They put Artie Piscano, the underboss of K. C...
اونا آرتي يسکانو رو جانشين مدير کي سي کردن
in charge of making sure nobody skimmed the skim.
تا مطمئن شن که هي کسي اموال مسروقه رو نمي دزده
- What were you doin'? - I was with my cumma.
يکار داري ميکني؟ - با من بيا به اونجا -
- What are you doin' with your cumma? - I gave her a scheff.
ي داري ميي، باهات بيام تا اونجا؟ - I gave her a scheff.
The only trouble was, Piscano was a disaster.
تنها مشکل اين بود که يسکانو يه فاجعه بود
This guy could fuck up a cup of coffee.
اين يارو ميتونست يه فنجان قهوه رو وه مالي کنه
- What you been doin'? - I'm out there more than I'm here.
ه کاري انجام دادي؟ - من بيشتر اونجام تا اينجا
And little did anybody know where this would lead.
و هي کي مسئول اين کار رو نميدونه
If they did, they'd would've been better off makin' fuckin' novena.
اه اونا باشن، خيلي بهتر از اين مقدار ول در ميآرن
You gotta go back there and talk to that guy.
بايد برردي اونجا و با اون آدم صحبت کني
- I never got paid my expenses for the last trip. - What expenses?
هي وقت هزينه هاي سفر آخرم بهم س داده نشد - ه هزينه هايي؟
I'm layin' money outta my own pocket, and I never get anything back.
کلي ول تو جيبم ذاشتم و هرز هيي برنردوندم، مه ه خبره
You gotta go back out there.
بايد به اونجا برردي
From now on, I'm gonna start keepin' records.
از الان بايد تمام مخارج رو ياد داشت کنم
No records, Artie. What are you gonna do with records, pay taxes?
يادداشت نکن، آرتي، يکار داري براي رداخت ماليات ميخوايش؟
I keep layin' out my own fuckin' dough.
دارم از ول لعنتي خودم خرج ميکنم
What the hell are we doin' over here?
کدوم جهنمي بودين؟
You're goin' to Las Vegas at my expense.
ميري به لاس واس با خرج خودم
Oh, fuck. I mean, after all...
Oh, fuck. ... منظورم اينه که، بعد از همه ي
No matter how many novenas you could make...
... مهم نيست قدر ول رشوه ميتوني بدي
nothing was gonna stop what came up next.
هي يز نميتونه جلوي اتفاقي رو که قراره بيفته، بيره
- I can't believe you're doing this. - We made a deal.
نمي تونم باورکنم شما اين کار رو ميکنيد - ما قرارداد بستيم -
It turned out Phil Green, Mr. Integrity...
معلوم شد که فيل رين ... آقاي کامل
had a partner nobody knew about.
شريکي داشته که هي کس راجع به اون نميدونست
And when she showed up and started demanding money...
و وقتي که اون يداش شد و درخواست ول رو شروع کرد
- Why are you doing this? - Because you're wrong.
را اين کار رو باهام ميکني؟ - براي اينکه تو اشتباه مي کني -
- Yes, you are. - No, I am not wrong.
بله، ميکنيد - نه، من اشتباه نميکنم -
Green tried to stonewall her.
رين تلاش کرد مخفيش کنه
I will see to it that you do not get away with this.
مي بينيم که نميتوني از اين موضوع خلاص شي
So, she sued him in court.
بنابراين، در داداه شکايت کرد
The court will now hear the matter of the plaintiff, Anna Scott...
داداه حاضر است حرف هاي ... شاکي، آنا اسکات رو عليه
against Tangiers Corporation and its president, Phil Green.
شرکت تنجير و رئيسش فيل رين رو بشنوه
- Oberon on behalf of Mr. Green. - Logan on behalf of Anna Scott.
اوبرون به نمايندي از آقاي رين - لوان به نمايندي از طرف خانم آنا اسکات -
- Mr. Oberon, you can proceed. - Thank you, Judge.
آقاي اوبرون، ميتونيد ادامه بدين - متشکرم قاضي -
I believe he was fair, and I'm delighted with the decision.
معتقدم منصفانه رفتار کرد و من تصميم اون رو قبول دارم
We got a problem.
ما به مشکل برخورديم
It didn't go too well. Green has to open up the books...
خيلي خوب به نظر نمياد ... رين بايد کتاب ها رو باز کنه
has to show how he got the financing.
و نشون بده، طور تامين مالي ميشه
Hey, that's not good.
هي، اين خوب نيست
She was doin' pretty good with her lawsuit.
اون کارش رو خوب انجام داد با طرح دعواش در داداه
But before she could start countin' her money...
ولي قبل از اينکه شروع کنه به ... شمردن ولش
the boys back home decided to settle the case out of court.
سرها به خونه برشتن تا رونده رو خارج از داداه حل کنن
So they sent me.
بنابراين منو فرستادن
Can you comment on the murder of Anna Scott?
شما با قتل آنا اسکات در ارتباط هستين؟
- What are you talking about? - She was found last night shot in the head.
درباره ي صحبت ميکنين؟ - اون ديشب يداش شد به سرش شليک کردن
Was this just a real estate partnership?
آيا اين فقط مشارکت در املاک و مستغلات بوده؟
Her lawyer said you were partners.
وکيلش فته شما شريک بودين
We were involved in minor real estate deals many years ago.
ما سال ها يش تو قراردادهاي ملکي کوک با هم شريک بوديم
It was never a partnership.
اون هرز يه شراکت نبود
Did you ever hear of the. 22 Caliber Killer?
آيا قاتل صاحب اسلحه کاليبر 22 را ديدين
Now, instead of the cops only looking at Nicky...
حالا، ليس ها فقط مواظب ... نيکي نبودن
they started looking at Green too.
شروع به مواظبت از رين هم کردن
And he was supposed to be our squeaky-clean front man.
و اون در ظاهر قرار بود مرد اصلي افشا شده ما باشه
I had to start giving interviews to make sure everybody knew...
مجبور بودم مصاحبه هايي رو انجام بدم تا مطمئن شن کازينو سازمان يافته ست
the casino was on the up-and-up.
کازينو بالا و بالاتر ميرفت
So how often do you really fill in for him?
بنابراين هر ند يک بار ول ها رو مييره؟
Green's here about two or three times a month...
رين هر ماه دو، سه بار، مياد اينجا
and he's busy with real estate deals.
اون با قراردادهاي ملکي سررمه
So in Green's absence, then, you're the boss?
بنابراين در غياب رين شما رئيس هستين؟
I serve at the pleasure of the chairman of the board.
من افتخار خدمت به عنوان رئيس هيئت مديره رو دارم
My responsibilities are to run the day-to-day operations.
وظيفه من اداره روز به روز اينجاست
So day-to-day, then, you're the boss?
س روز به روز، بعدش شما رئيس هستين؟
Well, in a sense, you could say that I am the boss...
خب، يه جورايي ميشه فت که ... من رئيس هستم
when Mr. Green is away.
وقتي که آقاي رين نباشه
You could say that.
ميتونيد همينو بين
Hmm, have you read this?
همم، شما اينو خونديد؟
About Mr. Rothstein.
درباره، آقاي راستين
It says, "The Midwest bookmaker with mob ties...
ميه، دلال قمار غرب ميانه ... با اراذل و اوباش
says that he is the real boss of the $100 million...
ميه، که اون رئيس واقعيه ... با 100 ميليون سرمايه ست
Tangiers casino empire. "
صاحب امراطوري کازينو تنجيره، باور ميکنيد
Did he really say that?
واقعا اينو فته؟
Why, of course he said that. It's right here.
البته که اينو فته درست همين جا
Has that man even filed for his license yet?
اون مرد براي جوازش هنوز اقدامي نکرده؟
I don't know. We have to check the files.
نميدونم بايد رونده ها رو بررسي کنيم
Without gettin' your shorts in a knot, would you do that?
ميشه اين کارو برام انجام بدي؟
And kinda check closely, 'cause we may have to kick a kike's ass outta town.
و از نزديک بررسيش کني، ون ميتونيم با لد رتش کنيم بيرون
Thank you.
متشکرم
A Gaming Control Board investigation...
انجمن کنترل بازي ... در حال بررسي
of Tangiers executive Sam Rothstein's application...
مدارک مدير تنجير سام راستين
for a gaming license is underway.
براي مجوز بازيه
Rothstein, who heads the Tangiers Casino operation and is a boyhood friend...
راستين کسيه که، کازينو تنجير رو ... اداره ميکنه و دوست دوران کودکيش
of Las Vegas mob boss Nicky Santoro...
تو لاس واس، رئيس اوباش ... نيکي سانتورو
could lose his ability to work in the casino...
ميتونه توانايي اداره کازينو رو از دست بده
Hello?
سلام؟
- I gotta meet Clean Face. What about the Chez Paris? - You can't.
بايد اک هره رو ملاقات کنم، منظورم ز اريسه؟ - ميتوني؟ -
- You gotta make a reservation. It's all booked up. - No, no.
بايد رزرو کرده باشي، همه وقتش رزرو شده - نه، نه -
It's impossible. You gotta make a reservation.
اين غير ممکنه بايد رزرو کني
It's very difficult to get in.
خيلي دشواره برم تو
I'll use the service entrance. I'll see you at 9:00.
از ورودي خدمه استفاده کن ساعت 9/00 مي بينمت
All right.
باشه
The battle between State gaming officials and Tangiers Casino boss...
نبرد بين مسئولين ايالتي سررمي ... و روساي کازينو تنجير
Sam "Ace" Rothstein is heating up.
سام آيس راستين به اوج رسيده
Tonight, an up-to-the-minute look at Ace Rothstein's attempt to get state licensing...
امشب، دقيقه به دقيقه آيس راستين براي رفتن مجوز ايالتي تلاش ميکنه
despite law enforcement allegations of Rothstein's organized crime connections.
با وجود جرائم وارده، اتهام وارد شده به راستين برقراري جرائم سازمان يافته ست
Will Sam Rothstein's friendship with alleged organized crime figure Nicky Santoro...
آيا دوستي سام آستين با اتهامات ... جرم و جنايات سازمان يافته نيکي سانتورو
keep Rothstein from running the Tangiers Casino?
راستين رو از مديريت کازينو تنجير باز ميداره؟
And can the integrity of state gaming laws be jeopardized by a boyhood friendship?
و ميتونه قوانين ايالتي سررمي توسط يه دوستي دوران بي نقض بشه؟
- Why don't you take it easy on that stuff? Huh?
را اين مسائل رو آسون نمييري، ها؟
Come on. Let me help you down.
زود باش بذار کمکت کنم
We're talking about some stuff.
بايد در اين رابطه صحبت کنيم
At 6:00: Will a boyhood friendship unseat Rothstein as the Tangiers Casino boss?
در ساعت 6/00 آيا دوستي دوران بي اونها نابود ميشه
Exclusive on the KBBO special news report.
در اخبار ويژه کي، بي، بي، او زارش خبري ويژه
Go down. Just... go downst-
برو ائين، فقط... برو ايين
You can't let this concern you, Ace. Don't worry.
اجازه نده اين موضوع نرانت کنه، آيس نران نباش
It's just a political witch hunt.
اين فقط سياست شکار ساحره ست
Ace.
آيس
Do you want something to drink?
ي ميخواي با مشروب؟
- Charlie, a refill? - Yeah, great.
ارلي، ميخواي رش کنم؟ - آره، عاليه -
No. Hey, Mr. Clark. I've been tryin' to reach you.
نه، هي، آقاي کلارک سعي کردم شما رو يدا کنم
- You're tougher to get than the president. - Well, I've been busy.
دسترسي به شما از رئيس جمهور سخت تر بود - خب، سرم شلوغ بود -
Yeah? At least you could return my phone calls, though.
آره؟ حداقل مي تونستي جواب تلفن هامو بدي
Listen, Nicky, we talked about this.
وش کن، نيکي ما در اين باره صحبت کرديم
And I explained to you that you might have to take some kind of loss.
و برات توضيح دادم که ممکنه بعضي مواقع ضرر کني
Yeah.
آره
I think I want my money back.
فکر کنم ميخوام ولم رو س بيرم
What are you gonna do, strong-arm me?
يکار ميخواي بکني، زورت رو به رخم بکشي؟
- You know, I think you've gotten the wrong impression about me.
ميدوني، فکر ميکنم درباره من غلط فکر ميکني
I think, in all fairness...
... فکر کنم، با انصافم
I should explain to you exactly what it is that I do.
بايد بهت توضيح بدم دقيقا ه کاري رو انجام ميدم
Tomorrow morning I'll get up nice and early, take a walk to the bank...
فردا اوايل صبح خيلي سرحال بلند ميشم ... و ياده تا بانک ميام
and walk in and see, and, uh, if you don't have my money for me...
و قدم ميزنم و مي بينم، و اه ... اه ول هامو ندي
I'll crack your fuckin' head wide open in front of everybody.
سر لعنتيت رو جلوي همه تو بانک ميشکنم
And just about the time that I'm comin' out of jail...
و هر موقع از زندان بيام بيرون
hopefully you'll be comin' out of your coma.
اميدوارم از کما بيرون اومده باشي
And guess what? I'll split your fuckin' head open again.
و حدس بزن يکار ميکنم؟ کله لعنتيت رو دوباره مي شکافم
'Cause I'm fuckin' stupid. I don't give a fuck about jail.
ون من خيلي احمقم و به زندان کوک ترين اهميتي نميدم
That's my business. That's what I do.
اين شغل منه اين کاريه که مي کنم
We know what you do. You fuck people out of money and get away with it.
ما ميدونيم يکار ميکني، تو مردمو براي ولشون ميکني، و باهاش دور ميشي
- You can't talk to me like that. - Hey, you fat Irish prick! You put my money to sleep!
نميتوني اينطوري با من صحبت کني هي، ايرلندي اق احمق! ول منو تو خواب ببيني
- Get my money, or I'll put your brain to sleep. - Sam!
ولمو بده، يا اينکه مغزتو تو خواب ميريزم بيرون - !سام -
Never mind Sam. This is personal.
دخالت نکن سام اين موضوع خصوصيه
I'll be there in the morning. You can try me, Fatso. You fuckin' try me.
صبح اونجام، ميتوني امتحانم کني، اقالو، تو لعنتي ميتوني امتحانم کني
You think he got the point?
فکر ميکني منظورمو فهميد؟
What're you doin'? He's a square guy, for chrissakes. He's gonna run to the F.B.I.
يکار ميکني؟ اون يه آدم هار وشه ميره يش، اف بي آي
That prick's been dodgin' me for three weeks. You're tryin' to tell me what to do.
اون احمق سه هفته ست من رو سر مي دوونه داري سعي ميکني بهم بي يکار کنم؟
I'm not tryin' to tell you what to do. You're outta line. Where's your head?
نميخوام بهت بم يکار کني از خط خارج شدي نيک، شعورت کجا رفته؟
Where's my head? Where's your fuckin' balls?
شعور من کجاست؟ جرات لعنتي تو کجا رفته؟ ها؟
I'm tryin' to put somethin' big together here. You know what I'm talkin' about.
سعي ميکنم يه کار بزر با هم اينجا انجام بديم ميدوني که راجع به ي حرف ميزنم
If you're actin' like this now, can I depend on you?
اه بخواي اين طور رفتارکني ميتونم باهات ارتباط داشته باشم؟
A lot of things gonna change. If you wanna be there with me, you're gonna have to go my way.
خيلي يزها تغيير کرده، ار بخواي اونجا باهام باشي، بايد به روش من عمل کني
Listen, Nick, understand my situation. I'm responsible for thousands of people.
وش کن نيک، موقعيت منو درک کن من جوابوي هزاران نفر از مردم هستم
I got a hundred million a year goin' through the place.
صدها ميليون بار در سال اون تو رفتم
It's all over if I don't get that license.
همه اينا تموم ميشه اه جواز نيرم
If it goes bad for me, it's bad for a lot of people.
اه اتفاق بدي برام بيفته براي اشخاص زيادي بد ميشه
Forget about your fuckin' license. I plant my own flag, you ain't gonna need a license.
جواز کوفتي رو فراموش کن من کار خودم رو ميکنم، که احتياجي به جواز نداره
You know, I don't know what it is, Sammy, but the more I talk to you...
ميدوني، نميدونم اين يه سامي ... ولي هر ه بيشتر باهات صحبت ميکنم
the more I feel like you just don't want to go along with me.
بيشتر احساس ميکنم که نميخواي با من باشي
- No, I don't want to come along with you. - All right, fine.
نه، نميخوام که باهات نباشم - باشه، خوبه -
I don't want to be involved in anything you're talking about, okay?
نميخوام که خودمو درير هر يزي که داري راجع بهش حرف ميزني، بکنم، مفهومه،؟
I want to run a square joint. I just want my license.
ميخوام اونجا رو بردونم فقط جوازم رو ميخوام
I want everything quiet. That's it!
ميخوام همه يزآروم باشه !همين
Quiet like this? "I'm the boss"? That's quiet?
آروم مثل اين؟ من رئيسم؟ اين آرومه؟
That's taken out of context. I had no control over that.
اون خارج از بحثه کنترلي روي اون نداشتم
- Ronnie and Billy will tell you exactly what happened. - Back home that looks bad.
روني و بيلي بهت مين دقيقا ه اتفافي افتاده - اه کنترلي روش نداشته باشي، بد به نظر ميرسه -
Looks bad? Every time you're on television, I get mentioned. That looks bad.
بد به نظر ميرسه؟ هر وقت تلويزيون، نشونت ميده، بد به نظر ميرسه، اون بده
- What the fuck happened to you? - What happened to me?
ه اتفاقي سر تو اومده؟ - ه اتفاقي سر من اومده؟ -
- What happened to you? You lost control. - I lost control?
ه اتفاقي سر تو اومده؟ تو خارج از کنترلي - من خارج از کنترلم؟ -
Look at you, you're fuckin' walkin' around like John Barrymore.
خودت رو ببين مثل جان باريمور دور خودت ميرخي
A pink robe and a fuckin' cigarette holder? I lost control?
روب دشامبر صورتي و سيار کوفتي؟ من کنترلم رو از دست دادم؟
I don't wanna bring this up, but you been treatin' people with disrespect, even your wife.
نميخواستم به اينجا برسم، ولي تو به مردم توهين ميکني، حتي به همسرت
My wife? What does she have to do with this?
همسرم؟ اون به اين موضوع ه ربطي داره؟
She was upset about a lot of things, especially that whole fuckin' Lester Diamond incident.
اون سر خيلي يزها غمينه، مخصوصا سر قضيه لستر دايموند
You're the shoulder to cry on? Did you her tell about your little role in that situation?
تو شونه اي براي ريه اوني؟ راجع به موقعيت خودت يزي بهش فتي؟
No, that's not the fuckin' point.
نه اين موضوع اهميتي نداره
- The point is, she's upset, and you've got a problem. - I would appreciate it...
موضوع اينه که، اون غمينه، و تو مشکل رو فهميدي ... من متشکر ميشم
if you stay out of my personal life.
اه خودتو از زندي خصوصيم بکشي بيرون
- You wouldn't like it if I did it to you. - She came to talk to me.
خودت دوست نداري اين کارو برات انجام بدم - اون اومد تا با من صحبت کنه -
What was I supposed to do? Throw her out?
يکار بايد مي کردم؟ بيرون مي انداختمش؟
- Stay away from her. It's none of your business. - It's none of my business?
فقط خودتو از اون دور نه دار، اين موضوع به تو ربطي نداره - به من ربطي نداره؟
A week ago it was. Now it's none of my business. When you need me, you need me.
هفته يش ربط داشت، الان ربطي نداره کي بهم احتياج داري، تو بهم احتياج داري
The way you need me to vouch for you as a citizen.
موقعي که بهم احتياج يدا کني مثل يک همشهري بهت کمک ميکنم
I'm gonna have to straighten out what you did with this guy.
ميخوام باهات رو راست باشم درباره کاري که با اين يارو کردي
This guy is gonna run to the F.B.I. Now.
رو در جريان ميذاره FBI اون الان
Your head's bigger than your casino.
حرفهات از کازينوت بزرتره، رفيق
I knew what he wanted. Nicky wanted to take over.
مي دونستم اون ي ميخواست نيکي مي خواست تمومش کنه
He wanted to go after Gaggi, the skim, everything and everybody.
اون ميخواست بعد از اي باشه بهتر از همه يز و همه کس
Plus, he had stopped asking permission from back home for every little thing.
بعلاوه، سوال کردن درباره هر يز کويک از ذشته اش رو متوقف کرد
A casino boss and his wife were killed. The bulls questioned Nicky.
يه مالک کازينو و همسرش کشته شدن ليس ها از نيکي باز جويي کردن
A dealer from the Sirocco. They questioned Nicky.
يه دلال از سريکو اونا از نيکي بازجويي کردن
A bunch of stool pigeons wound up in the trunks of their cars. They questioned Nicky.
يه نفر صندوق عقب ماشين يدا ميشد از نيکي بازجويي ميکردن
A lawyer.
يه وکيل
When some guys that didn't pay their shylocks began disappearing...
هنامي که بعضي از اشخاص ناديد ميشدن
Nicky's name was in every one of those newspapers.
اسم نيکي توي تمام روزنامه ها بود
Nicky was questioned in two dozen murders, but they always had to let him go.
از نيکي در مورد 12 قتل بازجويي شد ولي اونا هميشه مجبور ميشدن ولش کنن
There were never any witnesses.
هي مدرکي وجود نداشت
The coppers blamed me for everything that went wrong.
ليس ها به من مشکوک ميشدن براي هر اتفاق بدي که ميفتاد
Watch yourself. You're gonna get runned over, there.
مواظب خودت باش بايد اونور وايستي
If a guy fuckin' tripped over a banana peel, they'd bring me in for it.
اه يکي روي وست موز ليز ميخورد منو باز خواست ميکردن
Come on, be nice, huh?
زود باش، مودب باش، ها؟
And the bosses were no better. They complained because things don't run smooth.
و رئيس ها هم بهتر از اين نبودن، اونا غر ميزدن، براي اينکه اوضاع آروم نبود
In my line of work, things don't run so smooth. I'm sorry.
تو حيطه کاري من اوضاع آروم نميشد، متاسفم
I'm dealin' with degenerate animals out here.
من اينجا با يک سري حيوان ست طرفم
But the bosses, what do they give a fuck?
ولي رئيس ها به ي اهميت ميدادن؟
They're sittin' on their asses drinkin' anisette.
اونا سر جاشون مي نشستن مي نوشيدن و ميخوردن
I'm the guy in the trenches.
من کسي بودم که تو اه ميفتاد
Fuckin' bosses think it's a fuckin' free lunch out here.
رئيس هاي کوني، فکر ميکردن اينجا اوضاع آرومه
Frankie, they found a guy's head in the desert.
فرانکي اونا سر يه نفر رو تو صحرا يدا کردن
You know about that?
راجع به اون يزي ميدوني؟
- Yeah, I heard. Yeah. - Yeah.
آره، شنيدم، آره - آره -
Everybody's talkin'. They're makin' a big deal out of it. It's in all the papers.
همه راجع به بهش صحبت ميکنن، خيلي نده اش کردن تو تمام روزنامه ها هست
What are you gonna do?
ميخواي يکار کني؟
And I mean, that's no good. You gotta tell him to take care of things a little better.
منظورم اينه که، خوب نيست، بهش بو بهتره بيشتر مراقب جزئيات باشه
I'll tell him, Remo.
بهش ميم، ريمو
Fuckin' bosses; they're smokin' their Di Nobilis...
رئيس هاي کوني اونا سيار برشون رو ميکشيدن
and they're eatin' trippa and fuckin' suffritte, you know, fried pigs' guts.
و بهترين سيرابي و غذا رو کوفت ميکردن ميدوني، دل و روده سرخ شده خوک
If I want to talk private, I gotta go to a bus stop.
اه ميخواستم خصوصي صحبت کنم بايد ميرفتم ايستاه اتوبوس
- What do they care long as I keep sendin' money back? - They're complainin'.
تا وقتي که براشون ول ميفرستم، ه يزي براشون مهمه؟ - اونا فقط غر ميزنن -
Let 'em complain. I'm the one who's here. I do all the work.
بذار غر بزنن، من تنها کسي هستم، که همه کارها رو انجام ميده
- Somebody don't like it, fuck 'em. - It's up to you.
لعنت به کسي که از اين موضوع خوشش نمياد
They want a fuckin' war? I'm ready.
اونا ميخوان جن راه بندازن؟ من آماده ام
All I gotta do is take care of five of those guys. The rest will fall into place.
بايد مواظب 5 تا از اونها باشم بقيه خودشون به دام ميفتن، باور کن
Peekaboo, you fucks, you.
خوک ها، لعنت به شما
I see you, you motherfuckers.
مي بينمتون مادر جنده ها
Nicky was not only bringing heat on himself but on me too.
نيکي نه تنها خودشو تو مخمصه انداخت من رو هم درير کرد
The F.B.I. Watched every move he made, but he didn't care. He just didn't care.
اف. بي. آي. همه حرکاتش رو زير نظر داشت ولي اون اهميتي نميداد، اصلا اهميت نميداد
If they're gonna watch me, I'm gonna watch 'em right back.
اه اونا منو زير نظر دارن، به ورش منم اونا رو زير نظر دارم
I spent a few bucks. Top dollar. Who gives a shit?
مقداري از بهترين دلارها رو خرج کردم کي اهميتي ميده؟
I got the latest anti-buggin' equipment from the same places that sell to the fuckin' C.I.A.
آخرين تجهيزات ضد جاسوسي رو از همون جايي که به سي. آي. اي. ميفروشن، خريدم
I had special police frequency radios, F.B.I. De-scramblers, cameras that see in the dark.
فرکانس راديويي ليس ويژه کشف کننده هاي اف. بي. آي. دوربين هاي ديد در شب رو
And because of that, the miserable sons of bitches never caught me doin' anything.
و به خاطر اينها، اون بدبخت هاي حرومزاده هرز نميدونستن دارم يکار ميکنم
I got my job on the line, and this guy's havin' the time of his life.
من شغلم رو داشتم، و اين آدم داشت از زندي لذت ميبرد
He has every cop in the state watchin' him, and he's out playin' golf.
همه ليس هاي ايالتي مراقبش بودن، و اون داشت لفش رو بازي ميکرد
And at the worst possible time for me.
و در بدترين لحظه ممکن براي من
I had my license hearing coming up, and I didn't want to leave anything to chance.
شنيدم که جوازم در حال نزديک شدنه، و نمي خواستم هي يز رو به شانس بسارم
I mean, if I can't work in Vegas, where am I gonna go?
منظورم اينه که، اه نتونم تو واس کار کنم کجا مي تونستم برم؟
You've been very open with us. I mean, your books and papers.
شما با ما خيلي راحت هستين منظورم ، دفترها و حساب هاتونه
That's gonna mean something when you go before the commission.
اين يزها معني داره قبل از برزاري کميسيون
- All I ask is a fair hearing. - This kind of honesty will guarantee that fair hearing.
تمام درخواستم، دادرسي عادلانه ست - اين نوع صداقت رسيدي عادلانه رو تضمين ميکنه
All right, well, we'll move on to...
باشه، خب، بريم به بحث
- I wanted to hear something about Kansas City.
ميخوام يزهايي راجع به کانزاس سيتي بدونم
What the fuck is this?
اين ديه ه کوفتيه؟
Where's this guy gonna land, the fairway?
اين يارو کجا ميخواد بره، تو بزرراه؟
They're fuckin' agents, Frankie. Look at this.
اون احمق ها، بازرسن، فرانکي ناشون کن
The Feds were watching Nicky play golf for so long...
ماموران فدرال مدت زيادي نيکي رو موقع بازي لف زير نظر داشتن
they ran out of gas.
بنزينشون تموم شده بود
Just what I needed, right in front of the Control Board.
اون يزي که احتياج داشتم، درست جلوي بازرسان کنترل جواز
A hundred dollars, whoever hits the plane.
صد دلار براي کسي که به هوايما بزنه
And as if things weren't bad enough, in comes Piscano, the Kansas City underboss.
و همه يز به قدر کافي بد بود که يسکانو، به کانزاس برشت
He ran that little grocery store in Kansas City where they bought the suitcases.
اون يه فروشاه مواد غذايي کويک تو کانزاس داشت همون جايي که مدان ها رو ميبردن
Fightin' over those suitcases again. You know what that means, right?
جنجال دوباره سر اون مدان هاي لعنتي ميدوني که منظورم يه، درسته؟
I gotta take another trip to Vegas, and it's gonna cost me another couple grand.
بايد سفر دوباره اي به واس برم، و هزينه هايي در بر داره
He ran it with his brother-in-law...
اونجا رو با برادر ناتنيش اداره ميکرد
but mostly what he did was complain about his trips to Vegas.
ولي معمولا اون راجع به سفرش به واس ناله ميکرد
You gotta lay down the law, otherwise they're gonna make a fool out of you.
بايد به قانون احترام بذاري، ور نه مثل يه احمق رتت ميکنن بيرون
I write it all down. Every fuckin' nickel goes down. Receipts...
همش رو نوشتم ... هر سکه بي ارزشي رو، رسيد دارم
- Hey, oh, wha... What's the matter with you? - Everything's here.
هي، اه، ي شده؟ - همه يز اينجاست -
- Since when do you talk like that? - I'm sorry.
از کي تا حالا اينجوري صحبت ميکني؟ - متاسفم -
Nance gives me trouble, I'll tell him I'll take the eyes out of his frickin' head.
نانس منو تو مشکل انداخت، بهش ميم مواظب دهن شادش باشه
- Again. - I said, "frickin' head. "
دوباره - فتم، دهن شاد -
- That's enough. - I'm sorry.
ديه کافيه - ببخشيد -
What happens next? You can't believe it.
بعد ه اتفاقي ميفته؟ باورتون نميشه
Who would believe that the F.B.I. Had a wire in the place...
کي مي تونست باور کنه که اف. بي. آي تو محيط دستاه کار ذاشته
lookin' for some information about some old homicide...
به دنبال برخي اطلاعات درباره يک جنايت قديميه
about some guy who was whacked-out God knows when over God knows what.
درباره آدميه که ناديد شده خدا ميدونه کجا، خدا ميدونه براي ي
What's to prevent him with the suitcases that he could take what he wants?
ي باهاش تو اون مدون ها بوده اون ميدونسته که اون ي ميخواد؟
Fuckin' Nance takes back two suitcases from the Tangiers. What about three or four?
نانس کوني دو تا مدون رو از تنجير برردونده، به جاي 3 يا 4 تا؟
We've got nobody in the room to watch. That's the law.
هي کس رو براي مراقبت از اتاق نداريم اين قانونه
We can't even go into the count room to watch our money. You believe this bullshit?
حتي نمي تونيم به اتاق شمارش، براي ديدن ول خودمون بريم اين مزخرفات رو باور ميکنيد
Sure, he's got his people in there. They could all be in on it together, those fucks.
البته، حتما آدمهاشو اون تو فرستاده ممکنه اون حرومزاده ها با هم باشن
I'll find out. If it's Green, I'll bury that bastard.
يداش ميکنم، اه کار رين باشه اون حرومزاده رو دفنش ميکنم
I never trusted him. They trust that scumbag. I don't.
هرز بهش اعتماد نداشتم اونا به اون عقب مونده اعتماد دارن، نه من
- I'll hit the two of them with a fuckin' shovel. - Take it easy.
من دو نفر از اونا رو با بيل ميزنم - آروم باش -
Ma, I'm sorry. They're beatin' me left and right.
مامان، ببخش اونا بهم از  و راست ضربه زدن
- Ma, I'm sorry. I'm all upset. - I know, but that's enough.
مامان ببخش، کاملا افسرده ام ميدونم، ولي ديه کافيه
You know what they're doin'. I can't take this no more. Back and forth.
ميدوني که اونا يکار ميکنن بيشتر از اين نميتونم تحمل کنم، از عقب و جلو
- Take it easy. You'll get a heart attack like that. - I know. I'm too upset.
آروم باش، اونطوري سکته قلبي ميکني - ميدونم، خيلي افسرده ام
And the damn thing is, they hear all this stuff...
... و اونا همه اين يزهاي لعنتي رو
about Las Vegas and the casinos and suitcases...
راجع به لاس واس و کازينو و مدان ها شنيدن
and that's it.
و همش همين
Everything's comin' outta my pocket. I gotta pay.
همه يز از جيب من بيرون مياد من بايد رداخت کنم
Would you believe that such a thing could happen?
ميتوني باور کني نين يزي اتفاق بيفته؟
I'm in this to make money, not to lose money.
من ول ميسازم نه اينکه ول از دست بدم
Every F.B.I. Man across the country had their ears open now.
هر نفر از اعضاي اف. بي. آي. که تو کشوره الان وشاشون رو تيز کردن
If you want something done right you gotta do it yourself.
ار ميخواي کاري رو درست انجام بدي بايد خودت انجامش بدي
I mean, Piscano, this guy basically sunk the whole world.
منظورم اينه که، يسکانو، اين يارو اساسا تمام دنيا رو غرق کرد
There are some that are good and some that are bad.
بعضي از اونا که خوبن و بعضي از اونا که بدن
Mr. Chairman, members of the commission...
آقاي رئيس ... اعضاي کميسيون
Mr. Rothstein is pleased to be here today.
آقاي راستين، افتخار ميکنه که امروز اينجاست
When the day finally came, I was ready.
وقتي که بالاخره روزش رسيد، آماده بودم
I felt so confident that all I had to do was present my case.
خيلي اعتماد به نفس داشتم تنها کاري که بايد ميکردم اين بود که، درخواستم رو ارايه بدم
We have documents, one of which is a report by retired F.B.I. Agents...
ما مدارکي داريم که يکي ازآنها توسط ارايه شده FBI مامور بازنشسته
which completely absolves Mr. Rothstein from any wrongdoing.
که به طور کامل، آقاي راستين رو از هر ونه عمل خلافي مبرا ميکنه
- Counselor, before you continue... - I want to have this marked...
وکيل مدافع، قبل از اينکه ادامه بدين ميخوام اين موضوع روشن شه
This commission is prepared to act on a motion denying the Rothstein application.
اين جلسه براي لغو درخواست راستين تشکيل شده
- Denying? - Do I hear a motion seconded?
لغو؟ - شنيدم که وارد مرحله دوم ميشه؟
Mr. Chairman, I second the motion.
آقاي رئيس مرحله دوم
Do I have a vote on the motion?
آيا يک راي هم ندارم؟
- Aye. - Aye. Aye.
بله - بله، بله -
The ayes have it. This hearing is adjourned.
بله داريم اين جلسه به وقت ديه اي موکول ميشه
- You have to be kidding. - Adjourned? What do you mean, "Adjourned"?
بايد شوخيت رفته باشه؟ موکول شده؟ منظورت يه، موکول شده؟
Senator, you promised me a hearing. You didn't even look at the F.B.I. Reports.
سناتور، شما قول داده بودين بهم وش بدين هم توجهي نکردين FBI حتي به زارش
When you were my guest at the Tangiers Hotel, did you not promise me a fair hearing?
وقتي مهمانم بودي تو تنجير هتل آيا به من قول رسيدي عادلانه رو ندادي؟
- I was never your guest. - You were never my guest? I never comped you?
هرز مهمان شما نبودم - هي موقع مهمون من نبودي؟ هرز دعوتت نکردم؟
- I don't comp you at least three times a month? - I'd like to answer that.
تو رو 3 دفعه در ماه دعوت نکردم تو تنجير؟
Mr. Rothstein is being very typical to this point. He's lying.
آقاي راستين خيلي شخصي با اين قضيه برخورد ميکنه، اون دروغ ميه
The only time I was at the Tangiers was with Barney Greenstein.
تنها باري که تو تنجير بودم با بارني رنستين بوده
- Was I at that dinner? Tell me, was I at that dinner? - You were wandering.
من تو اون شام بودم؟ بهم بو، من تو اون شام بودم؟
- Was I at that dinner? Was I?
تو اون شام بودم؟ آيا من
- You were... in the... You were in the building. - I was in the building?
تو... در اون... تو در اون ساختمان بودي - من تو ساختمون بودم؟ -
You know I was at that dinner, and you swore to me I would have a fair hearing. Did you not?
خودت ميدوني که تو اون شام بودم و بهم قول دادي که کارم رو راه بندازي، نفتي؟
Did you not? Well, tell me I was at least at the dinner. Allow me that much.
نفتي؟ خب، لااقل بو که اونجا بودم
- Give me that much at least! - Yes, you were.
حداقل اينو بو- بله بودي -
Thanks for not calling me a liar, you son of a bitch. You son of a...
تشکر براي اينکه حداقل منو دروغو نخوندي ... حروم زاده، حرومزاده
A routine licensing hearing turned into bedlam yesterday...
جلسه درخواست جواز روز ذشته تبديل به تيمارستان شد
when the flamboyant Tangiers Casino executive, Sam "Ace" Rothstein...
وقتي که مدير عامل تنجير کازينو ... سام آيس راستين
- What are you runnin' for, Bob? - Accused the state's top gaming officials of corruption.
کجا فرار ميکني، باب؟ مقامات بالاي بازي هاي ايالتي رو به فساد متهم کرد
You promised me when you were getting comped at my hotel.
وقتي تو هتلم مهمونم بودي بهم قول دادي
You were asking me for copies of your bill so you could put 'em on your expense account.
ازم در خواست کي صورت حساب کردي تا بتوني اون رو از ماليات کم کني
In a wild outburst that followed his gaming license denial...
در فوران خشمي که به دنبال عدم ذيرش ... مجوز بازي صورت رفت
- Bullshit! Bullshit! - Rothstein followed several...
!مزخرفه! مزخرفه راستين تعداد زيادي
stunned commissioners into the hallway where he continued his harangue...
از اعضاي کميسيون رو تا تالار ورودي دنبال کرد تا نطقش رو با فرياد ادامه بده
until his own lawyers and friends urged him to leave.
تا وقتي که وکلاش و دوستانش اونو مجبور به ترک کردن
You have a past. I have a past. My past is no worse than yours.
تو ذشته اي داري، منم ذشته اي دارم ذشته من بدتر از مال تو نيست
But you guys think you have the right to pass judgment!
ولي شما آقايون فکر ميکنين که حق اين رو داريد که قضاوت کنين
Long suspected of running the Tangiers without a license...
مشکوک به اداره کردن تنجير به مدت طولاني ... بدون داشتن جواز
yesterday's hearing was to determine whether someone with Rothstein's history...
جلسه ديروز به همين منظور تعيين شد ... آيا کسي با سابقه راستين
was qualified to officially hold a top gaming post.
به طور رسمي واجد شرايطه سطح بالاي سررميه
Fuckin' hypocrites!
!عوضي هاي رياکار
- What the hell's he gonna do now? - I don't know.
الان يکار ميخواد بکنه؟ - نميدونم -
What's he doin'? He knows all those guys he yelled at are friends of ours.
يکار ميخواد بکنه؟ اون ميدونه همه اين آقايون از دوستان ما هستن
What's the matter with him, making all this mess?
مشکل اون يه که اين همه شلوغ ميکنه؟
Maybe he could run things with another job title. What are we gonna do?
شايد بتونه با عنوان کاريه ديه اونجا رو اداره کنه - يکار بايد بکنيم؟ -
However he runs things, it's gotta be quiet. Let him hide upstairs in the office.
به هر حال اين کارو بايد بي سر و صدا انجام بده بايد بهش اجازه بديم طبقه بالا مخفي بشه
Say he's a janitor. I don't give a shit.
بو که سرايداره من که اهميتي نميدم
But, please, whatever job he takes, make sure it's something quiet.
ولي، خواهشا، هر کاري ميکنه مطمئن شو که بي سر و صدا باشه
Ladies and gentlemen...
... خانم ها و آقايون
the Tangiers Hotel proudly presents the all-new...
تنجير هتل ... با افتخار به همه تقديم ميکنه
Sam Rothstein show, Aces High.
نمايش برتر سام راستين
Tonight, taped live from the all-new Sports Book...
تنجير به طور زنده از همه کانال هاي جديد
we present the premiere showing of Aces High...
تقديم ميکند ... نمايش برتر آيس
with the Sasha Semenoff Orchestra...
با ساشا سيمينوف ... و ارکستر
and the Sam Rothstein Dancers!
و روه رقص سام راستين
Mr. Rothstein is a professional gambler and the best football handicapper in America;
آقاي راستين يه قمار باز حرفه اي و و رد آورنده بهترين هاي آمريکاست
a man who will take you inside the real Las Vegas as no one has ever done before.
مردي که شما رو طوري به درون حقيقت لاس واس ميبره، که کس ديري قبل از اون نتونسته
And now, ladies and gentlemen, the new entertainment director of the Tangiers Hotel Casino...
و حالا، خانم ها و آقايون کارردان جديد ... برنامه تنجير هتل کازينو
Mr. Sam Rothstein.
آقاي سام راستين
Welcome to the Sam Rothstein Show. We're very happy to have you here this evening.
خوش آمديد به شوي سام راستين ما خوشحاليم که امروز عصر در کنار شما هستيم
The young lady to my left is Trudy, who is...
خانم جواني که در سمت مه ... تروديه، که
a lead new dancer in our fabulous show from Paris.
رقص شفت انيزش رو از اريس نمايش ميده
Our first guest this evening...
... اولين مهمان اين عصر
is Frankie Avalon.
فرانکي آوالون
- Keep an eye on him. - I've got a large family.
شم هاتون رو باز نهدارين - من يه خانواده بزر دارم -
- How many kids do you have? - I'm very proud to say that we have eight children.
ند تا به داري؟ - خيلي افتخار ميکنم که بم صاحب 8 فرزند هستم
No, no, please. Please.
نه، نه، لطفا، لطفا
- That's amazing. - There's nothing to it. It was my pleasure.
شفت انيزه اين که يزي نيست، باعث افتخاره
- Ace, don't do it. - ##
آيس، اين کارو نکن
Oh, no, no. Oh, no.
اوه، نه، نه، اوه، نه
Oh, Jesus.
Oh, Jesus.
He's juggling!
!اون تردستي ميکنه
Let's not take Commissioner Pat Webb too seriously.
کميسر ت وب بيايد جدي نيرين
I recently challenged him to a debate on this program, and he declined.
من به تازي اون رو براي بحث تو يه برنامه به الش کشيدم و اون رد کرده
What are you worried about, Pat? You don't have to send me any questions.
در مورد ي نراني، ت؟ مجبور نيستي به هر سوالي جواب بدي
You can ask me anything you want.
ميتوني هر ي ميخواي از من برسي
What the hell is he doin' on television, anyway?
قصدش از اين برنامه تلويزيوني يه، به هر حال؟
He's on all night, screamin' about how he's gonna take his lawsuit to the Supreme Court.
هر شب فرياد ميزنه، که اين رونده رو به ديوان عالي کشور ميکشونه
He really must be crazy. He's gonna go to Washington with this?
واقعا بايد ديوونه شده باشه ميخواد اين موضوع رو به واشنتن بکشه؟
He's out of his fuckin' mind.
عقل لعنتيش رو از دست داده
It's a pity we have such hypocrisy. Some people do what they want.
خيلي بده که اينقدر فريب وجود داره بعضي از مردم هر کاري دلشون ميخواد انجام ميدن
Other people have to pay through the nose. Such is life.
بقيه مردم مجبورن حقيقتو حس کنن اين زنديه
Andy, go see him. Tell him maybe it's time he should quit.
اندي، برو ببينش، بهش بو شايد وقتشه اونجا رو ترک کنه
First of all, what they did was totally unconstitutional.
اول از همه، کاري که کردن کاملا خلاف قانون اساسي بوده
We're on the list to be heard before the Supreme Court of the United States.
ما در ليست براي تشکيل جلسه در ديوان عالي ايالت متحده هستيم
These guys don't give a fuck about the Supreme Court. They want you to walk away.
اون ها اهميتي به ديوان عالي کشور نميدن اونا ميخوان خودتو بکشي کنار
Walk away? Andy, you can't be serious. How can I walk away? Don't you see what's at stake?
بکشم کنار؟ اندي، جدي که نميي ميتونم بکشم کنار؟ نمي بيني که ي در جريانه؟
The old man said maybe your friend should give in.
يرمرده فته شايد دوست قديميت بايد به بازي بياد
When the old man says "maybe," that's like a papal bull.
"وقتي يرمرده ميه "شايد مثل اينه که به
Not only should you quit, you should run.
نه تنها بايد بکشي کنار بلکه بايد فرار کني
Every time they mention my name in the papers, they mention Nicky too.
هر بار که اونا اسممو تو روزنامه هاي کير خور ميبرن اسم نيکي رو هم ميبرن
How the fuck does that help?
اين ه کمکي ميتونه بکنه؟
The heat he brought down is murder.
جرياني که توش رفتاره قتله
The police department was cooperative. He pissed 'em off. Nobody can make a move anymore.
اداره ليس در جريانه اون ريد بهم، هي کسي ديه نميتونه حرکتي بکنه
- What are you proposing? - I don't know. He doesn't listen to me.
ه يشنهادي ميکني؟ - نميدونم، اون ديه بهم وش نميکنه -
Maybe he should get lost for awhile. Would that be so bad?
شايد براي مدتي م و ور بشه آيا فکر بديه؟
- They ain't sendin' Nicky nowhere. - If he took a break...
اونا نيکي رو جايي نمي فرستن - اه مدتي کنار بکشه -
it would give everybody time to maneuver.
به همه فرصتي براي مانور ميده
I would forget about the maneuver. I would just get out.
من مانور رو فراموش ميکنم فقط ميخوام بياي بيرون
I can't do that.
نمي تونم اين کارو بکنم
As soon as Andy got home, Nicky heard about our talk.
به محض اين که اندي به خونه رسيد نيکي راجع به صحبت ما خبردار شد
Next morning, bright and early, I get the call.
صبح بعد، بهم زن زد
Great. You know, I've got to do some shopping. You want to go?
عاليه، ميدوني، ميخوام برم خريد ميخواي بياي؟
Getting a call from Nicky wasn't easy.
دريافت تماس از نيکي ندان هم راحت نبود
Even the codes didn't work. So we figured out another act.
حتي کد ذاشتن هم کاري نميکرد بنابراين ما راهکار ديه اي رو در يش رفتيم
If a phone's tapped, the Feds can only listen in on the stuff involving crimes.
اه تلفن رو شنود کنن، فدرالي ها فقط مسائل مربوط به جنايات رو وش ميکنن
So on routine calls, they have to click off after a few minutes.
بنابراين در تماس هاي معمولي اونا بعد از ند لحظه شنود رو متوقف ميکنن
Yeah, I got a sprained fuckin' elbow.
آره آرنجم ر به ر شده
- Yeah. - Meet me at 3:00.
ساعت 3 مي بينمت -
- At Caesar's? - 100 yards down the road.
تو سزار؟ - صد متر ايين تر از جاده -
- Why? - Don't ask questions. Just be there.
را؟ - ازم سوال نکن، فقط اونجا باش
Suzy Cream Cheese has the exact same outfit.
سوزي کرم نيري اين يزها رو داره
I saw something.
يه يزي مي بينم
Something very cute.
يه يز خيلي خوب
Okay, he's out. It's the ant. Brown unit.
باشه، اون بيرونه زارش از موره، واحد قهوه ايه
And he's with the bogey. I think it's Frankie.
و يه نده هم همراشه فکر ميکنم فرانکيه
Nicky started out before me...
... نيکي قبل از من شروع کرد
because it wasn't that easy for him to get around.
براي اينکه براش ساده نبود که بيرون بياد
Nicky couldn't even go for a ride without changing cars...
نيکي حتي نميتونست ... رانندي کنه، بدون عوض کردن ماشين
at least six times before he could shake all his tails.
حداقل 6 بار قبل از اون اين کارو کرد
Because of the planes, he had to use underground garages.
از اونجا که هوايما دنبالش بود از اراژهاي زيرزميني استفاده ميکرد
Meeting in the middle of the desert always made me nervous.
ملاقات در وسط صحرا هميشه منو عصبي ميکنه
It's a scary place.
محل ترسناکيه
I knew about the holes in the desert, of course.
البته راجع به ودال هاي توي صحرا اطلاع داشتم
And everywhere I looked, there could have been a hole.
و هر جايي که ناه ميکردم ممکن بود يه ودال باشه
Normally, my prospects of comin' back alive...
به طور طبيعي امکان زنده برشتن من
from a meetin' with Nicky were 99 out of 100.
از ملاقات با نيکي نود و نه از صد بود
But this time, when I heard him say a couple of hundred yards down the road...
ولي اين بار، وقتي شنيدم که فت ... صد متر ائين تر از جاده
I gave myself 50-50.
به خودم 50، 50 دادم
Where the fuck you get off talkin' to people behind my back, goin' over my head?
از کي تا حالا تو، کس کش شت سرم حرف ميزني رفتي رو مخم؟
- What people? - What people? What'd you think, I wasn't gonna find out?
يش کي؟ - يش کي؟ فکر کردي، يدات نميکنم؟
I don't even know what you're talkin' about.
حتي نميدونم در مورد ي حرف ميزني
You said I'm bringin' heat on you? I gotta listen to people because of your shit?
تو فتي که من تو رو تو دردسر انداختم؟ مردم بهت وش ميدن ون تو يه وهي؟
You're orderin' me out? You better get your own fuckin' army, pal!
سفارش کردي بيرونم کنن؟ !بهتره با يه ارتش کوني بياي سراغم، رفيق
I didn't order you or anybody. I told Andy Stone that you had heat, and that was a problem.
من به کسي درباره ات سفارش نکردم به اندي استون فتم که تو دردسر افتادي، و اين مشکل اون بود
- You want me to get out of my own fuckin' town? - Yeah.
ميخواهي از محله ام برم بيرون؟ - آره -
Let the bullshit blow over so I can run the casino.
بذار اين مزخرفات تموم بشه تا بتونم کازينو رو اداره کنم
Anything goes wrong with the casino, it's my ass. It's not yours. It's my ass.
هر مشکلي تو کازينو يش بياد با کون منه، نه مال تو، با کون منه
I don't know whether you know you have your fuckin' casino because I made that possible!
نميدونم آيا خبر داري که اون کازينوي لعنتي که داري !به خاطر اينه که من ممکنش کردم
I'm what counts out here. Not your fuckin' country clubs or your fuckin' TV shows!
ه يزي اينجا داشتم !نه کلوب هاي شهر رو، نه نمايش هاي مسخره تلويزيوني
And what the fuck are you doin' on TV anyhow?
و ه غلطي ميکني تو اون نمايش هاي تلويزيوني؟
I get calls from home every day. They think you went batshit!
هر روز اونها بهم تلفن ميکنن فکر ميکنن تو داري وُه زيادي ميخوري
I'm only on TV because I gotta be able to hang around the casino. You understand.
من فقط تو تلويزيونم براي اينکه بتونم اطراف کازينو باشم، فهميدي؟
You could have had the food-and-beverage job without goin' on television!
ميتوني شغل غذا و نوشيدني رو بدون رفتن تو تلويزيون هم داشته باشي
You wanted to go on TV.
تو ميخواستي بري تو تلويزيون
Yeah, I wanted to go on TV. That way I have a forum. I can fight back.
آره، ميخواستم برم تلويزيون اينطوري ميرم تو انجمن، ميتونم به مبارزه برردم
They know they can't fuck around with me like they could if I was an unknown. That's right.
اونا ميدونن که نميتونن مثل وقتي که ناشناخته بودم با من رفتار کنن، اين درسته
You're makin' a spectacle of yourself.
تو از خودت يک تابلو ساختي
Me? I wouldn't even be in this situation if it wasn't for you.
من؟ نميخواستم تو اين موقعيت باشم اه به خاطر تو نبود
Every time I meet somebody, the question is: Do I know you?
هر وقت يکي رو مي بينم سوال ميکنه که آيا تو رو ميشناسم؟
- Sure, now you wanna blame your fuckin' license on me. - No, Nicky.
البته، حالا ميخواي نرفتن جواز لعنتيت رو، سر من خراب کني - نه، نيکي -
When you asked me if you could come out here...
وقتي ازم رسيدي که ... ميتوني اين جا بياي
what did I tell you? Do you remember?
ي به بهت فتم؟ يادت مياد ي به بهت فتم؟
- Back up a fuckin' minute here. - Do you remember what I told you?
بکش عقب يه لحظه لعنتي - يادت ميآد بهت ي فتم؟ -
I asked you? When the fuck did I ever ask you if I could come out here?
ازت رسيدم؟ کي ازت رسيدم که ميتونم بيام اينجا؟
Get this through your head, you Jew motherfucker, you!
اينو تو مغزت فرو کن !يهودي مادر جنده
You only exist out here because of me! That's the only reason!
!تو فقط به خاطر وجود من اينجايي ! فقط به اين دليل
Without me, you personally...
بدون من ... تو شخصا
Every fuckin' wise guy still around will take a piece of your fuckin' Jew ass!
هر کدوم از اين لعنتي ها !يه تيکه از تو رو داشتن يهودي الاغ
Then where you gonna go? You're fuckin' warned.
کجا مي خواهي بري؟ بهت هشدار ميدم
Don't go over my head again, you motherfucker, you!
دوباره اطراف من يدات نشه !تو مادرجنده
# Crack that whip #
# Crack that whip #
- # Give the past the slip # - Well, we got company.
- # Give the past the slip # - Well, we got company.
# Step on a crack #
# Step on a crack #
# Break your mama's back #
# Break your mama's back #
# When a problem comes along you must whip it #
# When a problem comes along you must whip it #
# Before the preacher talks too long #
# Before the preacher talks too long #
- # You must whip it # - Did you see that?
- # You must whip it # - Did you see that?
Dumb Jew motherfucker. Grew up together, and he's actin' like he don't know me.
احمق يهود مادرجنده، با هم بزر شديم و طوري رفتار مي کنه که انار منو نمي شناسه
I know we're supposed to avoid each other, but there's ways to do things.
ميدونم که بايد از هم جدا باشيم ولي راهي براي انجام کارها وجود داره
Fuck him.
لعنت به اون
To Abraham Lincoln.
به سلامتي آبراهام لينکلن
- Don't let it bother you. - Does it look like it's botherin' me?
اجازه نده اين موضوع اذيتت کنه - به نظرت ميرسه اذيتم ميکنه؟ -
Why do I give a fuck?
را بايد اهميت بدم؟
That prick. He won't even look over. What's his fuckin' problem?
احمق، حتي اين طرفو ناه نکرد مشکل اون لعنتي يه؟
- Fuckin' Jews stick together, don't they? - They're havin' a good time.
يهودي هاي کوني با همن، مه نه؟ - اونا خوش ميذرونن -
- So are we. - # Whip it good ##
بنابراين ما هم خوش ميذرونيم
Yeah?
بله؟
- Sam, we got a problem. - What is it?
سام، به مشکل برخورديم - ي شده؟ -
The little guy. Nobody told him he was eighty-sixed from the joint.
کوتوله، هموني که نميخوام اسمش رو بيارم هشتاد و شش تا ازمون رفته
We turned our heads and made out we didn't know who he was.
ما سرمون رو رخونديم و خارج شديم نميدونيم اون کيه
He's over at the 21 table with his nose wide open.
اون شت ميز 21 داره بو ميکشه
He took money out of his own kick. His nose is open for about 10,000.
داره ول ميزاره براي10000 تاي ديه
- Now he's really pissed. - Oh, no.
حالا ديه واقعا مزاحم شده - اوه، نه -
- He wants a 50,000 marker. - Just give him ten.
نجاه هزار تا ميخواد - فقط بهش ده هزار تا بدين -
That's it. I'll be right down.
همين الان ميام ايين
- He's gonna come up with 10,000, the way you want it. - No, 50,000. I said 50!
داره مياد با 10000 تا، همان طور که ميخواستي - نه 50000، فتم 50
Go get it. I don't give a fuck where you get it. Fuckers. They take but don't give back.
بريد بيريد، اهميتي نميدم از کجا ميارين کوني ها، اونا رفتن ولي س نميدن
# I ain't got a home I got a phone ##
# I ain't got a home I got a phone ##
How the fuck can you grin?
طور مي توني وزخند بزني؟
You know how much I'm stuck? You give a fuck? Do you?
ميدوني قدر معطل شدم؟ اهميتي ميدي؟ آره؟
Give yourself a hand, right across your fuckin' mouth.
يه دست تو خودت بکن يک راست بکنش تو دهنت
Look at this beaut they put in now.
به اين خوشلي که فرستادن ناه کن
Sherbert send you to rob me now?
شربرت تو رو فرستاده تا ازم دزدي کني؟
Been fuckin' knockin' everybody's dick all night? Been beating the customers?
طور ميتوني تموم شب رو وزخند بزني؟ مشتري ها رو وب ميزني، مادر جنده، ها؟
Huh, jag-off? Hit me.
ها، کثافت؟ آره بنداز
Take this stiff and pound it up your fuckin' ass.
اين وب رو بير و به کونت فرو کن
Hit me again.
دوباره بنداز
Take this one and stick it up your sister's ass. Hit me again.
اين يکي رو بير و تو کون خواهرت فرو کن
That's it. Keep lookin' at him. If you had any heart at all, you'd be stealin' for a livin'.
همينه، مواظبش باشين، اه عاطفه اي دارين بايد براي زندي دزدي کنين
Hit me again! What the fuck you keep lookin' at him for?
دوباره برام بنداز براي ي به اون زل زدي
You fuckin'... Look at this, 20 fuckin' paints in a row. Hit me again.
توه کوني... اينو ناه کن، 20 تا رن تو يه رديف دوباره بنداز
You should pay as fast as you collect, you know.
بايد به همون سرعت رداخت کني دقيقا جمعش کن، خودت ميدوني
- You gotta get outta here. - Tell this Jew motherfucker to pay that marker off.
بايد از اينجا بري بيرون - به اون يهودي مادرجنده بو که اون رو بردازه
I'm here to help you. You're gonna bury us both.
اينجا اومدم که کمکت کنم تو جفتمونو دفن ميکني
- Just give me the money. Give me the fuckin' money. - I'm gonna okay you ten.
فقط ولم رو بهم بده، ول لعنتي رو بهم بده - من ميم 10 تا خوبه -
Then you gotta get out before the cops are all over you.
بعدش از اينجا برو قبل از اينکه ليس ها دورتو بيرن
Ten and that's it.
ده تا همين
What are you starin' at, you bald-headed Jew prick?
به ي زل زدي کل يهودي احمق؟
- Come on, come on. Let's get outta here. - Sue me, you Jew fuck!
زود باش، زودباش، بايد از اينجا بريم !ازم شکايت کن، يهودي کوني
Get outta here? I got a marker comin'. Deal.
بريم بيرون؟ يه نشانه رفتم، قبوله
Everything's changed now. You're talking about a divorce.
الان همه يز تغيير کرده تو در مورد جدايي حرف ميزني
You're asking for alimony payments and child support, and now custody.
تو در مورد رداخت خرجي و سررستي به سوال ميکني
I just want what any divorced woman would get.
من فقط يزي رو که هر زن مطلقه اي لازم داره ميخوام
She's only sober about two hours a day.
اون فقط براي دو ساعت تو روز هوشياره
It's usually from 11:00 in the morning 'til 1:00 in the afternoon.
تقريبا از 11 صبح تا يک بعد از ظهر
If I gave her her money and her jewels, she's gonna piss it all away in a year.
بهش ول و جواهرات دادم ولي تموم اونو ظرف يکسال از بين برد
Where would you be then? Comin' right back to me...
کجا ميخواهي بري؟ ... يش من بررد
- or findin' some other excuse to come... - We had a deal.
يا يه دليل ديه براي اومدن ير بيار - ما قرار ذاشتيم -
Remember that?
يادت ميآد؟
He said if it didn't work out between us, I could get my things, and I could leave.
اون فت اه همه يز بين ما درست کار نکرد ميتونم يزهامو بردارم و برم
Look in my eyes.
به شم هام ناه کن
Look-Look in my eyes. You know me.
منو ميشناسي
Do you see anything that makes you think I would ever let...
آيا نميبيني که هرز بهت اجازه نميدم
someone in your condition take my child away from me?
کسي در موقعيت تو بتونه به مو ازم دور کنه؟
Do you?
اينطور نيست؟
You know that won't happen.
ميدوني همين يزي اتفاق نميفته
And after all this time...
... و بعد از اين همه مدت
and as hard as I tried, as much as I wanted...
هر قدرسخت تلاش کردم ... هر قدر خواستم
I could never reach her.
هرز نتونستم به اون دست يدا کنم
I could never make her love me.
هي وقت نتونستم مجبورش کنم دوستم داشته باشه
I always felt she should have gone for all that money...
هميشه فکر ميکردم ممکنه براي ول ها رفته باشه
being somebody for the first time in her life...
و براي اولين بار تو زنديش کسيه براي خودش
a home, a kid.
يه خونه، يه به
That's not what happened. It didn't work out that way.
اين يزي نبود که اتفاق افتاد اين کار جواب نداد
- Everything all right? I mean, what could we do?
همه ي روبراهه؟ - منظورم اينه که، يکار ميتونيم بکنيم؟ -
After a while, we'd just take breathers from each other. Little separations.
بعد از يه مدتي، ما از هم بريديم جدايي هاي کويک
At that time, I remember Ginger took Amy to Beverly Hills.
در اون زمان، يادم مياد که جينجر امي رو با خودش به بورلي هيلز برده بود
She was gonna spend a week shopping.
اون يه هفته رو تو خريد صرف کرد
- Yes, Mr. Rothstein. - Operator, the Beverly Hotel in Beverly Hills, please.
بله آقاي راستين - اوراتور، بورلي هتل تو بورلي هيلز، لطفا
- Beverly Hotel. - Mrs. Sam Rothstein, please.
سلام، بورلي هتل - خانم سام راستين، لطفا -
Mr. And Mrs. Rothstein have checked out already.
متاسفم، آقا و خانم راستين همين الان رفتن
Mr. And Mrs. Rothstein?
آقا و خانم راستين؟
Hey, little Dale Evans.
سلام
- Yes, they both checked out. - Thank you.
بله، هر دوشون رفتن - متشکر -
Hello. Yeah.
سلام. بله
My wife is with an old friend of hers in L.A.
همسرم با يکي از دوستان قديمي تو لس آنجلسه
Some lowlife. A guy named Lester Diamond.
يه بي سر و ا مردي به اسم لستر دياموند
My daughter is with them, and I think they're gonna try and kidnap her.
دخترم هم باهاشونه، و فکر ميکنم اونا سعي ميکنن بدزدنش
- Is there anybody you can send? - We'll take care of it.
مي تونيد کسي رو بفرستين؟ - ترتيبش رو ميديم -
We got a number and an address.
ما يه شماره و يه آدرس داريم
- Hello. Is this Lester? - Hello.
الو، شما لستر هستين؟ - الو -
Who's calling?
ه کسي تماس مييره؟
This is Sam Rothstein. I want to talk to Ginger. Put her on the phone.
سام راستين هستم، ميخوام با جينجر صحبت کنم بو بياد اي تلفن
She's not here, Sam.
اون اينجا نيست، سام
Listen to me very carefully. I want to talk to Ginger.
بهم وش کن، خيلي مواظب باش ميخوام با جينجر صحبت کنم
I want my kid back. I want her put on a plane immediately.
ميخوام به ام بررده ميخوام هر ه زودتر با هوايما بفرستينش
- I know she's there. Don't fuck around. - Sam, I wouldn't.
ميدونم که اونجاست، منو مسخره نکن سام، نميکنم
You shouldn't do this.
نبايد اين کارو بکني
- You understand? Put her on the fuckin' phone.
متوجه اي؟ بهش بو بياد اي تلفن لعنتي
Sam, I don't know where she is.
سام، نميدونم اون کجاست
So... listen... Can I call you back?
... خوب... وش کن ميتونم ند لحظه بعد بهت زن بزنم؟
- 702-472-1862. - Mm-hmm. 1862.
- 702-472-1862. - Mm-hmm. 1862.
- Okay, I'll call you right back. - Right away.
باشه، بعد باهات تماس مييرم
- Right back. - You got it.
بعدا - رفتم -
Schmuck. All right, I just bought us a few minutes.
فقط ند دقيقه وقت دارم
You want to get back at this prick? Hmm?
ميخواي با اون احمق بري؟ ها؟
- Okay, you got what? Two million in that box?
خب، ي ميخواي؟ دو ميليون تو صندوق؟
Hey, you got a minute? He's got two million in the box, am I right?
هي، يه دقيقه وقت داري؟ دو ميليون تو صندوق، درست ميم؟
You let him keep your jewels.
اجازه داري جواهرات رو نه داري
We take the cash and the only other thing he cares about. Huh? Her majesty.
ما ول و تنها يز به درد بخور رو بر ميداريم، ها؟ عليا حضرت؟
We go to Europe. You dye your hair.
به اروا ميريم موهاتو رن کن
I don't want to go to Europe. I want to go to see "The Elephant Man. "
نميخوام برم اروا ميخوام برم مرد فيل نما رو ببينم
We're going to Europe. Let the adults talk. You dye your hair.
ما ميريم اروا بزار بزر ترها صحبت کنن. موتو رن کن
You get plastic surgery like we talked about.
جراحي لاستيک کن درباره اش صحبت کرديم
You're the mother. How much you think he'll pay to get this kid back?
تو مادري، فکر ميکني قدر براي برردوندن به اش خرج کنه؟
- I don't want to go to Europe. - Shut your mouth. You know where she gets this?
نميخوام برم اروا - خفه شو، ميدوني اينو ازکجا آورده؟
- You shut up. You want me to come over there?
خودت خفه شو تو ازم ميخواي بيام اونجا؟
I'll smack your face. Don't give me your shit!
صورتت رو خورد ميکنم بهم رت و رت نو
This has always been a dream, but now we're going.
هميشه روياش رو ميديدم ولي الان داريم ميريم
- Lester, he called you here. He called you right here. - That's who was on the phone.
لستر اون اينجا باهات تماس رفته، اون اينجا بهت زن زده - اون بوده که تلفن زده
- I just talked to him. - So he knows where you are.
من فقط باهاش صحبت کردم - بنابراين ميدونه کجايي
That means he's sending some guys over here, probably right now.
يعني اينکه، آدم هايي رو دنبال ما فرستاده شايدم همين الان
It means he's sitting by the phone, like a dumbbell...
منظورم اينه که، کنار تلفن نشسته ... مثل يه احمق
- waiting for me to call him back. - He's sitting by the phone just waiting for you to call.
منتظره که باهاش تماس بيرم - نشسته اي تلفن فقط براي اينکه باهاش تماس بيري -
What do you think we're gonna do? He's probably got guys outside the fuckin' house!
فکر ميکني يکار کنم؟ ممکنه آدم هايي رو خارج از خونه ذاشته باشه
- This is fuckin' bullshit! This is bullshit! - Get your bag! Let's go!
اين مزخرفه! اين مزخرفه !کيفتو بردار! بريم
- Oh, what bullshit? What? You want to talk it over now? - Okay, you done yakkin'?
اوه، ي مزخرفه؟ ي؟ ميخواي الان تمومش کني؟ خب، تموم شد
- Go, go! Get in the car! - Go, go, go.
برو، برو، برو تو ماشين برو، برو، برو
Just relax. Nobody's killing anybody.
فقط آروم باش هيکسي کسي رو نميکشه
I think he's gonna kill me. - Just relax.
فکر ميکنم ميخواد منو بکشه - آروم باش -
Call me back here in exactly an hour on this phone. I'll see what I can do.
دقيقا يه ساعت ديه به اين تلفن زن بزن ببينم يکار ميتونم بکنم
I'm gonna call you back in an hour at this number...
يه ساعت ديه ... به اين شماره زن ميزنم
- and you're gonna be there, right? - I'll be here.
و اونجا خواهي بود، باشه؟
Listen, don't do anything else crazy, okay? You all right? Okay.
وش کن، کار ديوانه واري انجام ندي، باشه؟ حالت خوبه؟ باشه
Bye.
Bye.
- Just knock it off. You two knock it off. - She started it.
فقط دست بکش، شما دو تا دست بکشين - اون شروع کرد -
- She started the whole thing. I'm just standing here. - Get in the car.
اون همه يز رو شروع کرد، من فقط اينجا نشستم
You're not gonna drive. Don't even think you're gonna drive. I'm gonna drive.
تو رانندي نميکني، حتي فکرشم نکن رانندي کني، من رانندي ميکنم
- I'm not gonna drive with some crazy woman. - You're driving me nuts!
من با يه زن ديوونه رانندي نمي کنم راننديت منو ديوونه ميکنه
Get on the passenger side! And I'm sending this kid to Bolivia in a box!
سمت مسافر بشين، و من اين به رو تو يه جعبه به بوليوي ميفرستم
Can we...
... مي تونيم که
# You can go your own way #
# You can go your own way #
# Go your own way #
# Go your own way #
# Tell me why #
# Tell me why #
- # Everything turned around # - Ginger called me.
- # Everything turned around # جينجر بهم زن زده
Yeah.
درسته
- I just told you she called me. - What'd she want?
بهت فتم که بهم زن زد - ي ميخواد -
She was afraid to call you.
اون مي ترسيد بهت زن بزنه
- She's with that cocksucker. They got Amy. - That's why I'm here.
اون با اون مرتيکه کيرخوره، اونا امي رو بردن - به اين دليله اينجام -
She wants to come back, but she's afraid you're gonna whack her out.
اون ميخواد بررده ولي ميترسه بندازيش بيرون
- They're gonna kidnap my kid. What do you want? - I know.
اونا به ام رو دزديدن، ي ميخوان؟ - ميدونم -
Why didn't you come to me? I mean, this is family. It ain't business.
را يش من بر نميردي، منظورم اينه که اين موضوع خانواديه، به تجارت ربطي نداره
You make calls back home. It makes us look bad out here. You know what I mean?
تو بهش زن ميزني، براي ما بد ميشه، ميدوني که منظورم يه؟
Back and forth, this one and that one.
عقب و جلو اين يکي و اون يکي
In the meantime, she's gone anyway.
به هر صورت اون در هر صورت رفته
Am I right?
درست ميم؟
What am I going to do with this woman?
با اين زن يکار کنم؟
- Driving me fuckin' crazy. - I think if you, uh...
داره ديوونم ميکنه - ... فکر ميکنم اه تو، اه
assure her that she's gonna be all right, she'll come back.
مطمئنش کن که وضعيتش درست ميشه اون بر مي رده
Driving me fuckin' crazy.
داره ديوونم ميکنه
Once you get her here, you think about it.
يه بار اينجا بيارش راجع بهش فکر کن
Wait 'til you get the kid back. She wants to come back.
منتظر بمون تا به ات رو برردونه - اون ميخواد بر رده -
That's the main thing here.
موضوع مهم اينه
You want your kid, don't you? Huh?
تو به ات رو ميخواي، مه نه؟ ها؟
Hello.
سلام
Hi, it's me. Just who you wanted to talk to, right?
سلام، من همون کسي هستم که ميخواستي باهاش صحبت کني، درسته؟
Listen, I'm not gonna ask you where you are.
وش کن، نميخوام ازت برسم کجايي
Just, please, put Amy on a plane, any plane, to get her here right away.
فقط، لطفا، امي رو سوار هوايما کن هر هوايمايي، که اونو به اينجا بياره
- That's all I'm asking. - Do you...
تمام يزي که ميخوام - ... تو ميتوني
I mean, I don't think she should go by herself.
منظورم اينه که، فکر نکنم خودش بتونه بياد
What do you mean?
منظورت يه؟
What I mean is...
... منظورم اينه که
Do you think if I came back...
... فکر ميکني اه برردم
Do you think you could forgive me?
فکر ميکني ميتوني منو ببخشي؟
I gotta tell you, I don't know.
بايد بهت بم، نميدونم
I understand that.
درک ميکنم
I know I fucked up.
ميدونم که ند زدم
- What about the money? Where's the box? - I gotta tell ya...
ول ي شد؟ صندوق کجاست؟ ... ميخوام بهت بم
I made some mistakes, and I spent some money.
من اشتباهاتي کردم و مقداري ول خرج کردم
- What's it under? - Pretty serious.
تقريبا قدر؟ به طور دقيق
- How serious? - It's under 25.
قدر دقيق؟ بيست و نج تا
- It's under 25,000? - Yeah.
بيست و نج هزار تا - آره -
- The rest of the two million is still there? - Yeah, I got the rest.
بقيه دو ميليون هنوز سر جاشه؟ - آره، سر جاشه -
Okay, no big deal. That's okay.
باشه، مهم نيست خوبه
He got his 25.
اون 25 تاش رو برداشت
That I'll live with. Any more, I couldn't.
من با اون زندي کردم بيشتر از اين بهش ندادم
Okay.
باشه
All right, all right. Where are you? I'll send a plane for you right away.
خيله خب، خيله خب، کجايي؟ يه هوايما برات ميفرستم
Hi, Sam.
سلام، سام
So what'd you do with it?
باهاش يکار کردي؟
With what?
با ي؟
With the money.
با ول
He needed some clothes.
اون مقداري لباس احتياج داشت
25,000 for clothes?
بيست و نج هزار تا براي لباس؟
He wanted a watch too.
يک ساعت هم مي خواست
- 25,000 for clothes and a watch? - Mm-hmm.
بيست و نج هزار تا براي لباس و ساعت؟ - اهم -
- Good evening, signora. This way. - Geno.
عصر بخير خانم، از اين طرف - جنو -
The good part was I had Amy back.
قسمت خوبش اين بود که امي رو برردوندم
So we went home, had the housekeeper stay over, put the kid to bed.
بنابراين رفتيم خونه، رستار رو فرستاديم بره به رو تو تختش ذاشتيم
I calmed myself down, and we went to dinner.
خودمو خونسرد نه داشتم و شام خورديم
I tried to keep things nice and civil...
... سعي کردم همه ي رو خوب نشان بدم
but, hey, 25,000 for three suits?
ولي خب، هي بيست و نج هزار براي 3 دست لباس
That doesn't make much sense.
با عقل جور در نمياد
First of all, he's not gonna wear thousand-dollar suits.
اول از همه اينکه اون لباس هاي هزار دلاري نمي وشه
Let's say he did, which he won't.
بيم که اين کار رو کرده باشه
How you gonna get fitted for 25 suits in three days?
طور تونست بيست و نج دست لباس رو تو 3 روز امتحان کنه؟
- # I'm confessin' # - I mean, how could you get fitted that fast?
- # I'm confessin' # منظورم اينه که، طور به اين سرعت تونست؟
I can't get fitted that fast, and I pay twice as much.
من نميتونم اينقدر سريع باشم براي همين بايد دو تا بوشم
- I bought him a watch too. - Yeah.
يه ساعت هم براش خريدم - آره -
But even if you bought him a really nice watch, one that he thought was nice...
ولي حتي اه بهترين ساعت رو براش خريده باشي ... اوني که اون ميه بهترينه
He doesn't know what the fuck a good watch is.
که اون نميدونه ساعت خوب ي هست
- Say you go five, ten, twelve grand... - Yeah.
... بو 5، 10، 12 هزار خرج کردي آره -
At the most, which is impossible, for him.
باز هم براي اون غير ممکن به نظر ميرسه
Plus, at the most, three suits, 1,000 apiece. That still leaves what?
بعلاوه، سه دست لباس ده هزار، باز هم مقداريش مونده؟
- Around 10,000? - Would you knock it off, Sam?
در حدود 10000؟ - تمومش ميکني، سام؟
- I'm just trying to figure it out. - There's nothing to figure out.
دارم سعي ميکنم بفهمم - هي يزي براي فهميدن وجود نداره -
I'm home. We're working it out.
ميرم خونه روش کار ميکنيم
I've been told before, "We're working it out. "
قبلا بهت فتم
You think that you're home...
فکر ميکني ... خونه هستي
after what you just put me through with Amy, is a favor to me?
با اين وجود فکر کردي با رسوندن امي به من در حقم لطف کردي؟
So, counting the watch, let's say another 4,000...
... بنابراين، با احتساب 4000 تاي ديه
for expenses over the weekend...
براي خرج هاي آخر هفته
of which you must have had a good time.
که بايد حسابي بهتون خوش ذشته باشه
I know he did. That's for sure.
ميدونم که همينطوره از اين بابت مطمئنم
I know that fuckin' piece of shit had a good fuckin' time.
ميدونم که به اون تيکه وه خيلي خوش ذشته
On my money.
با ول من
You might as well have fucked him, which you probably did anyway.
تو هم باهاش بودي که احتمالش هم هست
You're lookin' at me a certain way.
به شيوه معني داري نام ميکني
You're teary-eyed, huh?
با شم هاي اشک بار، ها؟
You're upset. You're a good actress, you know that?
تو ناراحتي، هنريشه خوبي هم هستي اينو ميدونستي؟
Good fuckin' actress.
هنريشه لعنتي خوبي هستي
You can fuckin' get that pity out of people.
ميتوني احساسات مردم رو به بازي بيري
I'm not a john. You understand?
احمق نيستم فهميدي؟
You always thought I was, but I'm not. And I'm not a sucker.
هميشه فکر ميکردي هستم ولي نيستم، و يه کيرخور هم نيستم
That fuckin' pimp cocksucker.
... اون جاکش کيرخور
He's lucky I didn't kill him last time.
خوش شانس بود که نتونستم بکشمش
Lucky he's fuckin' livin'. If you would have stayed with Amy...
خوش شانسه که هنوز زندي ميکنه ار يش امي مونده بودي
and you would have ran away, he would have been fuckin' dead.
و فرارکرده بودي اون الان مرده بود
Both of you. Dead. Dead.
همراه تو، مرده، مرده
# Dreamin' dreams of you Little babe ##
# Dreamin' dreams of you Little babe ##
No, it isn't right. It isn't fair.
نه اين درست نيست، عادلانه نيست
Yes.
بله
He doesn't come home at night. What is the big fuckin' deal?
اون شب خونه نمياد قرار يه؟
I go... Listen, I just can't fuckin' take it.
من ميرم... وش کن، فقط نمي تونم تحمل کنم
Why should I fuckin' take it? That wasn't the deal.
را بايد تحمل کنم؟ قراري در کار نيست
He acts like I'm the only one around here with a fuckin' past.
جوري رفتار ميکنه که انار من تنها کس اين اطراف هستم، با يه ذشته لعنتي
He'll never let me live it down.
هي موقع بهم اجازه نميده زندي کنم
Well, yes, I have tried. Of course I've tried.
خب، بله، من تلاش کردم البته که تلاش کردم
What the fuck do you think I came back here for?
فکر ميکني براي ي برشتم اينجا؟
No, I'm not. I want to have him killed.
!ميخوام که اون کشته بشه
Yes, I want him killed. I've fuckin' had it.
بله، ميخوام که کشته بشه اين يزيه که ميخوام
So are you with me on this?
خب تو اين موضوع با من هستي؟
You want to get rid of me? Here I am.
ميخواي از دستم خلاص شي؟ بفرما
Go ahead. Get rid of me.
خلاص شو از دستم
- Hello. - Yes, I do!
الو - !آره، ميخوام
I fuckin' hate you! I can't take it anymore!
!ازت متنفرم !نمي تونم ديه ادامه بدم
- Yes, I want to kill you! I hate your fuckin' guts! - You hate my guts?
!آره، ميخوام بکشمت! ازت متنفرم ازم متنفري؟
- I'm sick of being with you! - I want you to come with me now!
از با تو بودن مريض ميشم - ميخوام همين الان باهام بياي -
Come with me now. Come with me now.
با من بيا، با من بيا
- I want you out. I want you out of here.
ميخوام بري بيرون ميخوام م شي از اينجا
- I want you out of here! I want you out of here!
!ميخوام م شي از اينجا
Take your fuckin' bag and get out of here!
کيف لعنتيت رو بردار !و م شو از اينجا
I'll go, but I want my money right now!
!ميرم، ولي ولمو همين الان ميخوام
- You'll get your money! Don't worry. - The arrangement is over.
ولتو مييري، نران نباش - قرارداد بهم خورده -
- No kidding! - And I still get my money.
شوخي ندارم - و هنوز ولم رو ميخوام -
I need some cash right now! You can't just put me in the street!
احتياج به ول نقد دارم همين الان نميتوني همين جوري رتم کني داخل خيابان
You haven't been straight with me ever since I met you!
از موقعي که ديدمت با من صاف و ساده نبودي
You never even loved me in the first place!
!حتي از اولش منو دوست نداشتي
I need eyes in the back of my head with you, you fuckin' bitch!
من با تو احتياج به مراقبت از خودم داشتم جنده لعنتي
How could I love you? You treat me like I'm your fucking dog!
طوري ميتونم دوست داشته باشم؟ !با من مثل س لعنتيت رفتار ميکردي
- You're lower than a dog! - Fuck you!
!تو ازس بدتري لعنت به تو
Here! Here! Is this enough money?
!بيا! بيا اين ول کافيه؟
Will it last you two fuckin' days? Take it!
براي 2 روز کافيه؟ برش دار
- Greedy bitch. Take the fuckin' money. - I'm going to the bank...
جنده ولکي، ول لعنتي رو بردار - ... من به بانک ميرم -
- and I'm getting my jewelry too! - It opens at 9:00 a. m.
و جواهراتم رو بر ميدارم - ساعت 9 صبح باز ميشه -
Don't send your guys down there to stop me! I mean it!
افرادت رو نفرست که مانعم بشن !جدي مي م
I guarantee you, I will not stop you.
تضمين ميکنم مانعت نشم
You're not getting rid of me with one fucking suitcase!
از دستم خلاص نميشي !با يه مدان لعنتي
Come back tomorrow and get the rest. Just get out of here. Fine!
فردا بر رد و بقيه اش رو بير فقط از اينجا م شو، خوبه
- I'm taking Amy. - You're not taking Amy.
با امي ميرم - تو با امي نميري -
I am. I'm waking her up right now.
ميبرم همين الان بلندش ميکنم
You're stoned. You're a junkie. Get out of here.
تو سني، تو يه معتادي م شو از اينجا
- I am not! She's my daughter too! - Get out of here!
من نيستم، دختر منم هست - م شو از از اينجا -
Send my lawyers a letter, god-fuckin'- damn you!
به وکيلم نامه بنويس خدا لعنتت کنه -
You're not getting away with this! You're not gonna cheat me out of my end!
نميتوني همين جور دور شي !نمي توني تا آخر بهم حقه بزني
Fucker!
کوني
The funny thing was, after all that, I didn't want her to go.
نکته جالبش اينجا بود که بعد از همه اين ماجراها، نمي خواستم که اون بره
She was the mother of my kid. I loved her.
اون مادر به ام بود دوستش داشتم
And later, I realized I didn't want to give her the money...
و بعدا فهميدم که نميخوام ولو بهش بدم
because if I did, I knew I'd never see her again.
براي اينکه اه اين کار رو مي کردم ميدونستم که ديه دوباره نمي بينمش
- Oh. Have a good day at school, okay? - Okay.
روز خوبي تو مدرسه داشته باشي، باشه؟ باشه
Okay, angel.
خيله خب، فرشته
From now on, I have to know where you and Amy are at all times.
از الان، بايد بدونم تو و امي هر لحظه کجا هستين
Here's a beeper.
اين يه يجره
I want you to keep it on you.
ميخوام اين يش خودت باشه
It's very light.
خيلي سبکه
So I can call you whenever I have to.
بنابراين هر موقع خواستم تماس مييرم
Okay?
باشه؟
What are you supposed to do? What do you want to do?
قراره کاري انجام بدي؟ يکار ميخواي بکني؟
You want to stay the way you are? You can't do that.
ميخواي روي رفتارت ا فشاري کني؟ نميتوني اين کار رو بکني
Listen, two people don't get along, at some point you gotta call it.
وش کن، دو نفر هي وقت با هم راهشون يکي نيست ميتوني اينو اينطوري بي
It's none of my business, but I think that's what you gotta do.
به من ربطي نداره ولي ميخوام بدونم يکار ميخواي بکني
You're right. I know.
حق با توه ميدونم
- I was just... - What? What?
... من فقط ي؟ ي؟
- Nothing. - What were you gonna say?
هيي - ي ميخواستي بي؟ -
- I don't... - Tell me what you were gonna say.
... نميخوام بو ي ميخواستي بي؟
- Yeah? - Yeah.
آره؟ - آره
I was thinking maybe you know somebody at the bank...
فکر کردم شايد تو يه نفر رو تو بانک بشناسي
who could help me get my jewelry out?
که بتونه کمکم کنه تا جواهراتم رو خارج کنم
There's a lot of money in there.
ول زيادي اونجاست
I'd be willing to take care of anybody who helped me out.
منم هواي کسي رو که بهم کمک کنه دارم
- Let me think about that. - Okay.
بذار در موردش فکر کنم - باشه -
Let me see who I got. Gotta get somebody I can trust, you know?
ببينم کسي رو يدا ميکنم بايد بهش اطمينان داشته باشم، ميدوني؟
- You know he's never gonna give me my jewelry. - Hmm.
ميدوني که اون هي وقت جواهراتمو بهم نميده - همم -
He holds that key so tight, he's probably got it stuck up his ass.
اون حسابي از کليدش مراقبت ميکنه شايد اونو تو کونش قايم کرده باشه
You're right. That's Sammy.
راست ميي، سامي اينطوريه
And he's probably got it there too.
و ممکنه اونجا نهش داشته باشه
He's so fuckin' lucky. I could have buried him.
خيلي خوش شانسه مي تونستم لهش کنم
I could have gone to Europe and taken the baby.
ميتونستم به اروا برم و به رو هم ببرم
- Then he'd have tracked me down, and he'd have killed me. - No, he wouldn't.
بعدش اون دنبالم ميومد و منو ميکشت نه، اين کارو نميکرد
I would have.
من ميکردم
- He'd have been right too. Seriously. - Come on.
اون هم اين کارو ميکرد، جدي ميم - دست بردار -
- You don't take a guy's kid and then take off. - I didn't.
تو به يه نفرو بر نميداشتي و بعد ول کني - نميکردم -
I mean, I did, but then I did exactly what you told me to do, and I came back.
منظورم اينه که، انجامش ميدادم ولي بعدش درست همون کاري که بهم فتي رو ميکردم و برميشتم
- You did. You're right. You did. I like that. - Exactly what you said.
اين کارو ميکردي، درست ميي انجامش ميدادي، خوشم اومد
- That's what I like about you. You did the right thing. - I did what you told me.
اون يزي که درباره ات دوست دارم، اينه که درست انجامش ميدي همون طور که فتي
- Yes, you did. - Because you always tell me the right thing to do.
آره انجامش دادي به خاطر اينکه تو هميشه کارهاي درست رو بهم يشنهاد ميدي
Yeah.
آره
# And now that it's all over ##
# And now that it's all over ##
He really fucked himself up out here, didn't he?
اون حسابي خودش رو از بين برده مه نه؟
- He sure did. - Everything went to his head.
البته که برده - همه ي زده به سرش -
- Changed.
عوض شده
- He did. He ain't the same person. - No, he's not.
اون همون آدم نيست - نه نيست -
- He really thinks who the fuck he is. - Exactly.
واقعا فکر ميکنه کيه - دقيقا -
He hates me.
اونم ازم متنفره
He hates my fuckin' guts.
اون از وجود من متنفره
Come on, come on. You're a toughie. You can take this.
بي خيال، بي خيال تو سندلي، نميتوني اينجور باشي
- Don't cry. - I'm not as tough as you think I am.
ريه نکن - اونقدرا که به نظر ميرسه سندل نيستم -
Yes, you are.
را هستي
I'm not, and he scares the shit out of me.
نه نيستم، اون منو بيرون ميکنه
- I never know what he's gonna do. - Come on.
هي وقت نمي فهمم ميخواد يکار کنه - بي خيال -
- Don't be scared. - I need some help. I do.
نبايد بترسي - به کمک احتياج دارم -
I need some help.
به کمک احتياج دارم
You gotta help me.
بايد بهم کمک کني
I need a new sponsor, Nicky.
احتياج به يه حامي مالي دارم، نيکي
I do. I need a new sponsor.
ميدونم احتياج به يه حامي دارم
- Is that what you want? - Yeah.
اين يزيه که ميخواي؟ - آره -
- A sponsor?
يه حامي؟ -
Okay. Don't worry about it.
باشه در موردش نران نباش
Nobody will fuck with you anymore.
ديه کسي به هي وجه اذيتت نميکنه
- I'll take care of you. Yes, I will. - Take care of me.
ازت مراقبت ميکنم، آره انجامش ميدم - ازم مراقبت کن -
- It's what you want, isn't it? - Thank you. Yeah.
اين يزيه که ميخواي، درسته؟ - متشکرم، آره -
- Yeah. Uh-huh. - It's what you want?
آره، اه- ها - اين يزيه که ميخواي؟ -
# Yes, it came from your pen, dear, but not from your heart #
# Yes, it came from your pen, dear, but not from your heart #
- # The third king The joke of the deck #
- # The third king The joke of the deck #
# You ended your letter enclosed "Please sign my check" #
# You ended your letter enclosed "Please sign my check" #
- That's Ace's wife. - # Why, you fool #
- That's Ace's wife. - # Why, you fool #
- # You poor, sad, worthless foolish fool # - Fantastic.
- # You poor, sad, worthless foolish fool # - Fantastic.
# If you think that money can pay for the hard years I've suffered #
# If you think that money can pay for the hard years I've suffered #
# 'Til things broke your way #
# 'Til things broke your way #
- This is great for the boss. - # I'm answering your last letter that says we must part #
- This is great for the boss. - # I'm answering your last letter that says we must part #
# I'm tearing up the pieces the way you tore up my heart #
# I'm tearing up the pieces the way you tore up my heart #
# I smile when you kiss me and I thrill at your touch #
# I smile when you kiss me and I thrill at your touch #
# My only sin was I loved you much too much #
# My only sin was I loved you much too much #
# Win a little #
# Win a little #
# Lose a little ##
# Lose a little ##
- Hi.
سلام -
- You didn't answer your beeper. - I threw it away.
يجرت رو جواب ندادي - اونو به کناري انداختم -
You threw it away?
به کناري انداختي؟
I tried to do this thing. I know that you want me to, but it's just...
سعي کردم اين کارو بکنم، ميدونم که ... ميخواي اين کارو بکنم، ولي فقط
I'm driving down the freeway and the fuckin' thing's beep, beep, beep, beep, beep!
تو بزرراه داشتم ميروندم، و اين !يز کوفتي داشت بيب ميزد، بيب، بيب، بيب، بيب
I'm in a restaurant, it's embarrassing.
تو يه رستوران بودم رفته بود رو اعصابم
I don't want to do it anymore. Where's Amy?
ديه نميخوام اين کارو بکنم امي کجاست؟
- I put her to bed. - Oh.
ذاشتمش تو تخت - اوه -
I got your cigarettes.
سيارها تو رفتم
Oscar wants you to call him.
اسکار خواست باهاش تماس بيري
- So who'd you go to lunch with? - Jennifer.
س با کي ناهار خوردي؟ - جنيفر -
- Where'd you go? - To the Riviera.
کجا رفتين؟ - به ريويرا -
What'd you have?
يکار کردين؟
- I had a salad. - What did Jennifer have?
من يه سالاد رفتم - جنيفر ي؟ -
She had the same.
اونم همينو رفت
Okay.
باشه
I want you to call Jennifer...
... ميخوام به جنيفر زن بزنم
and I want you to tell her to tell you what you had for lunch.
و ميخوام بهش بم که آيا ناهار باهات بوده
I'm gonna listen in on the other line.
من روي خط ديه بهتون وش ميدم
- Why do you want to do that? - You know why.
را ميخواي اين کارو بکني؟ - خودت ميدوني را-
- Just do it. - Fine.
فقط انجامش بده - باشه -
I just need to get the bowl for my thing.
فقط يک سري از کارهامو انجام بدم
The line's busy.
خط مشغوله
There's nobody there.
هيکي اونجا نيست
- Hello. - Hello, Jennifer. It's Sam.
الو - الو، جنيفر، سام هستم -
All right. I didn't have lunch with Jennifer.
باشه ناهار رو با جنيفر نخوردم
Okay.
خب
Who were you with?
با کي بودي؟
I was with somebody.
با يکي بودم
I know you were with somebody. Who was it?
ميدونم با يه کي بودي کي بود؟
I just hope it's not someone who I think it might be.
فقط اميدوارم اون کسي نباشه که فکر ميکنم
I just hope it's not that.
اميدوارم اون نباشه
I knew she fucked around.
ميدونم همين دورو بره
She did what she did, and I did what I had to do...
اون کاري رو که ميخواست انجام داد ... و من کاري رو که لازمه انجام ميدم
but, Jesus, Nicky was the worst thing she could have done.
ولي، خدايا، نيکي بدترين يزي بود که ممکن بود اون داشته باشه
What if he won't stop?
اه اون بس نکنه، ي؟
It could get us both killed.
ممکنه هر دومون رو به کشتن بده
I can back him off.
نميتونم برردم
She was very convincing when she wanted to be.
وقتي خواست راحت متقاعدش کرد
And this is how she backed him off.
و اين طور متوقفش کرد
Hey, Ginger.
هي، جينجر
Don't forget, if you're challenged...
فراموش نکن ... اه با هم بحثتون شد
if he asks anything, deny everything.
اه يزي ازت رسيد همه يز رو انکار کن
You understand? I don't want him bringing beefs back home.
متوجه اي؟ نميخوام وقتي ... برشتي خونه
That could really cause a serious problem.
يه مشکل جدي برام يش بياري
Got to be careful. He's not dumb, you know?
بايد مواظب باشي اون احمق نيست، خودت ميدوني
You hear what I'm saying, right?
فهميدي ي بهت فتم، آره؟
I know. You don't have to tell me that.
ميدونم، لازم نيست بهم بي
What? Do you think I'm stupid?
فکر کردي احمقم؟
Do I think you're stupid? No.
فکر کردم احمقي؟ نه
I think you're beautiful. But I gotta go.
فکر ميکنم تو زيبايي ولي بايد برم
By this time, Nicky had things so fucked up on the streets...
نيکي اونقدر همه يز رو تو خيابون ها خراب کرده که
that every time Marino went back home, the packages got smaller and smaller.
هر بار که مارينو بر ميشت خونه بسته ها سبک و سبک تر ميشدن
It got to the point, when he walked into the place...
هر وقت به اون محل ميرفت
he didn't know whether he was going to be kissed or killed.
نميدونست بوسيده ميشه يا کشته ميشه
Frankie, I want to ask you something.
فرانکي مي خوام يزي رو ازت برسم
It's private.
خصوصيه
But I want you to tell me the truth.
ولي ازت ميخوام راستش رو بهم بي
Of course, Remo.
البته، ريمو
I want you to tell me the truth, mind you.
ميخوام راستش رو بهم بي اين کارو ميکني
I always tell you the truth, Remo.
هميشه بهت راستشو فتم، ريمو
Frankie... the little guy...
فرانکي... اون کوتوله
he wouldn't be fucking the Jew's wife, would he?
ترتيب زن اون يهودي رو ميده؟
Because if he is, it's a problem.
براي اينکه اه اين کارو کنه برامون مشکل سازه
What could I say?
ي ميتونستم بم؟
I knew if I gave the wrong answer...
مي دونستم که اه جواب غلط بدم
Nicky, Ginger, Ace, all of them could have wound up gettin' killed.
نيکي، جينجر، آيس، همشون کشته ميشدن
Because there's one thing about these old-timers.
براي اينکه يه يز در مورد اين قديمي ها صدق ميکرد
They don't like any fucking around with the other guys' wives.
اونها دوست ندارن کسي ترتيب زن هاي بقيه رو بده
It's bad for business.
اين براي کار بده
So I lied, even though I knew that by lying to Gaggi...
س دروغ فتم، با اينکه ميدونستم که ... با دروغ فتن به اي
I could wind up gettin' killed too.
مي تونستم کشته بشم
- No, I ain't seen anything like that. - Are you sure?
نه، من نين يزي نديدم - مطمئني؟ -
I'm positive.
مطمئنم
Remo, things are very fucked up down there.
ريمو، اون اطراف خيلي يزها بهم ريخته
I know. That's why I'm asking.
ميدونم به همين دليل مي رسم
- You see, my main concern is Nicky. - Mm-hmm.
ميدوني، نراني من بيشتر نيکيه - ام-هم -
I want to know if he's doing all right, if he's okay.
ميخوام بدوني اه اون کارش رو انجام ميده، اه اون خوبه
- He's good. He's fine. - I'm asking you to keep an eye on Nicky.
اون خوبه، اون عاليه - ازت ميخوام شم از نيکي بر نداري
- Do it for me. - No problem.
اين کارو برام بکن - مشکلي نيست -
I wouldn't want to be jeopardizing anything for our friends. Understand?
نميخوام اتفاقي براي دوستانمون بيفته فهميدي؟
- I understand. - Okay.
مي فهمم - باشه -
Frankie, you're a good boy.
فرانکي، تو سر خوبي هستي
Thanks, Remo.
متشکرم، ريمو
By now, Nicky and his crew had already hit rock bottom.
در همين زمان نيکي و افرادش ضربه نهايي رو زدن
Vegas really got to him.
واس واقعا مال اون بود
The booze, the coke, the broads.
مشروبات، کوکائين، فاحشه ها
I mean, he got sloppy.
منظورم اينه که، اون حسابي شلخته شده بود
He just wasn't the same Nicky anymore.
اون ديه نيکي قديم نبود
- You must have drank too much. - Go fuck yourself.
تو بايد خيلي خورده باشي - برو در خودت رو بزار
One night he had to belt a guy three times...
يه شب، يه نفرو سه دفعه کتک زد
before the guy finally went down.
قبل از اينکه بالاخره بيفته زمين
In the old days, Nicky would have decked him with one shot.
قديما نيکي معمولا با يک ضربه کارشو تموم مي کرد
You add this into the mix...
... اينو به مخلوط اضافه کن
Maybe just Vegas got to all of us.
شايد واس به همه ما تعلق داشته باشه
His crew followed him right over the edge.
افرادش تا لبه رتاه باهاش بودن
They were all tuned up half the time on coke.
همه اونها نصف وقت رو کوک ميزدن
They started doing stupid things. The worst was Blue.
اونها دست به کارهاي احمقانه ميزدن بلو کارهاي بدي ميکرد
- Hey, what do you guys want? - Police! Stay in the car!
هي، اين آقايون ي ميخوان؟ - ليس! تو ماشين بمون -
He never knew when to keep his mouth shut.
هي وقت نفهميد کِي بايد خفه بشه
- Drop the gun! - Fuck you!
اسلحه ات رو بنداز - - Fuck you!
The cops shot Blue...
ليس ها به بلو تيراندازي کردن
- because they thought his hero sandwich was a gun.
براي اينکه فکر کردن ساندوي تو دستش اسلحه ست
- They could have been right, but who knows? - Jesus Christ!
مي تونست درست باشه، ولي کي ميدونه؟ - - Jesus Christ!
What gun? He's got a fuckin' hero sandwich here.
ه اسلحه اي؟ اون با خودش يه ساندوي داره
- What do you want? It's pitch black. - Pitch black!
ي ميخواي؟ ي سياه - ي سياه -
- It's tinfoil. It looked like a gun! - You fuckin' moron!
اين يه لوله نازکه، مثل يه اسلحه ست - احمق کودن -
- I'll be fillin' out paperwork for the next two months! - What are we gonna do?
از اين به بعد بايد براي دو ماه زارش بنويسم - يکار بايد بکنيم؟ -
- I'm sorry! - You jerk-off!
!متاسفم تو کثافت
To get even, Nicky's crew got stoned one night...
افراد نيکي يک شب کنترلشونو از دست دادن
and they started shooting up the cops' houses.
و شروع به تيراندازي به به خونه ليس ها کردن
It got to the point where they couldn't talk in the Gold Rush anymore...
فهميدم که اونها ديه نميتونن به هي وجه تو لد راش صحبت کنن
because the Feds put a wire in the wall.
براي اينکه فدرالي ها استراق سمع کار ذاشته بودن
Even when they talked outside, they had to cover their mouths...
حتي اه بيرون صحبت ميکردن بايد دهنشونو مي وشوندن
- Shit, he's covering up again. - Because the Feds brought in lip readers.
کثافت، باز دهنشو وشوند - ونکه فدرالي ها، متخصص لب شناسي آورده بودن
Nicky found out from a teller who owed him money.
نيکي با تحويل دار خارج شد کي به اون ول بدهکاره
He asked me again about you and the Jew's wife.
دوباره ازم سوال کرد راجع به تو و زن اون يهودي
Walk, walk, walk. What'd you say?
قدم بزن، قدم بزن تو ي فتي؟
He asked me again about you and the Jew's wife.
اون دوباره راجع به تو و زن يهوديه رسيد
Yeah? What'd you tell him?
خب؟ ي بهش فتي؟
I told him I didn't know nothin'.
بهش فتم يزي نميدونم
Jiggs and Tony Gorilla said if you did anything, you're fucked up.
جيز و توني وريله فتن ار کاري ازت سر بزنه، از بين ميري
You think he's going home making a beef behind my back?
فکر ميکني شت سرم بر ميرده خونه؟
Nah, you would have heard something.
نه، بايد يزي شنيده باشه
- What's to stop him? - I know, I know.
طور ساکتش کنيم؟ - ميدونم، ميدونم -
I don't trust him anymore, but they'd never okay anything.
ديه بهشون اعتماد ندارم ولي اونا هم هيي رو تاييد نميکنن
Yeah, but they keep asking about it.
آره، ولي همش راجع به اون مي رسن
Sure they're asking. They earn with the prick.
معلومه که مي رسن اونا با اون احمق درآمد کسب ميکنن
I got a funny feeling he's gonna start a fuckin' war or something.
احساس ميکنم که ميخواد جني به راه بندازه
I'm not sure yet, but you know what I want you to do?
هنوز مطمئن نيستم ولي تو که مي دوني کار مي خوام بکنم؟
Who's this guy?
اين يارو کيه؟
That ain't nobody.
هي کس نيست
You know what I want you to do?
مي دوني يکار ميخوام بکنم؟
Get a couple of guys to dig a hole in the desert, then let them show you where it's at.
ميخوام ند تا از افرادم ودال هايي رو تو صحرا بکنن بعدا محلش رو بهت نشونت ميدم
- Angelo and Buster. - Yeah, but I'm not sure yet.
آنجلو و باستر؟ - آره، ولي هنوز مطمئن نيستم
- They'll do it. - When I'm ready, I'll say the word.
اونها انجامش ميدن - هر وقت حاضر بودم، کلمه رو ميم
- Go see the Jew, and you make it disappear. - Yeah.
برو يهوديه رو ببين، و ناديد شو - باشه -
Just let me know. But you got to be ready.
فقط منو با خبر کن ولي بايد آماده باشي
You know what I'm talkin' about?
ميدوني راجع به ي صحبت ميکنم؟
Did I say to do anything yet?
هنوز نفتم کاري کني که؟
I said I'm not sure. I'll let you know. I want to think about it.
فتم هنوز مطمئن نيستم، خبرت ميکنم بايد درباره اش فکر کنم
Where are these pricks at? Dominick said they're in the motel?
اين ابله ها کجان؟ دامنيک فت تو متلن
There or in the fuckin' bank. I don't know. All over the joint.
اونها تو بانک لعنتي هستن، نمي دونم
# Hey, hey, hey That's what I say #
# Hey, hey, hey That's what I say #
# I can't get no #
# I can't get no #
# Satisfaction #
# Satisfaction #
# I can't get me no #
# I can't get me no #
# I can't get no #
# I can't get no #
- # And I try and I try And I try, try, try, try #
- # And I try and I try And I try, try, try, try #
# I can't get no I can't get me no #
# I can't get no I can't get me no #
- # When I'm watchin' my TV # - Be right back. I'll be right back.
- # When I'm watchin' my TV # - Be right back. I'll be right back.
- # And a man comes on to tell me # - Rudy.
- # And a man comes on to tell me # رودي -
Any calls for me, just give them to Mr. Sherbert. I'll be right back.
هر کي زن زد، فقط وصل کن به آقاي شربرت، زود بر ميردم
- Sure, Mr. Rothstein. - I'm going home for a few seconds.
حتما آقاي راستين - براي ند دقيقه ميرم خونه -
# Same cigarettes as me #
# Same cigarettes as me #
- # I can't get no No, no, no #
- # I can't get no No, no, no #
# Hey, hey, hey #
# Hey, hey, hey #
- # That's what I say # - He's on his way home.
- # That's what I say # اون تو راه خونه ست -
- Oh... okay. - # And I'm doing this And I'm trying that #
اوه... باشه - - # And I'm doing this And I'm trying that #
# And I'm trying to make some dough #
# And I'm trying to make some dough #
# Baby, baby, baby baby, baby, baby #
# Baby, baby, baby baby, baby, baby #
- # Baby, baby, baby, baby, baby baby, baby, baby, baby # - Hello?
- # Baby, baby, baby, baby, baby baby, baby, baby, baby # سلام -
- # Baby, baby, baby, baby, baby baby, baby, baby, baby ## - Hello? Ginger?
- # Baby, baby, baby, baby, baby baby, baby, baby, baby ## سلام؟ جينجر؟ -
- Help, Daddy! - Amy!
!کمک، در !امي
- Amy, open the door! - I can't! I'm tied!
!امي، درو باز کن !نميتونم! منو بستن
- Dad! - What happened?
!بابا ه اتفاقي افتاده؟
- Who did this to you? - Mommy.
کي اين کارو باهات کرده؟ - مامان -
I'm gonna get a knife and cut you loose, honey.
ميرم يه اقو بيارم و آزادت کنم، عسل
- No, please, please! - Okay, Papa will be right back.
نه، لطفا، لطفا - باشه، بابا زود برميرده -
- When did this happen, honey? - I don't know.
کي اين اتفاق افتاد، عسل - نميدونم -
What time did your mother do this? When did she leave?
ه وقت مادرت اين کارو کرد؟ کي ترکت کرد؟
I don't know.
نميدونم
- Hello? - Sammy.
سلام؟ - سامي -
- Yeah. Who's this? Nick? - Me.
بله، کيه؟ نيک؟ منم -
- Yeah. You okay? - No, I'm not okay.
آره، خوبي؟ - نه، خوب نيستم -
- How'd you know I was here? - I just wanted to talk to you.
از کجا ميدوني که اينجام؟ - فقط ميخواستم باهات صحبت کنم -
Ginger's missing. She tied Amy up and locked her in her room.
جينجر م شده، امي رو بسته و در اتاق روش قفل کرده
I gotta find her. I don't know where she is.
بايد يداش کنم نميدونم کجاست
Well, listen, Ginger's here at the Leaning Tower with me.
خب، وش کن، جينجر اينجا تو برج با منه
She's there with you?
اون اونجا با توئه؟
- Yeah, she's here. - I'll be right over.
آره اون اينجاست
Uh, all right.
اه، باشه
- Comin' over. - Great.
ميام اونطرف - خوبه
Ace, listen, don't make a scene, all right?
آيس، وش کن کاري نکن، باشه؟
- I want to just talk to that Irish bitch. - She didn't know who to turn to.
فقط ميخوام با اون ايرلندي جنده حرف بزنم - اون نميدونه طرف کي رفته -
She didn't know where to turn. She's trying to save your marriage.
نميدونه طرف کي بره داره سعي ميکنه ازدواجتون رو نجات بده
- Nicky, I want to talk to that fuckin' bitch. - Hey.
نيکي، ميخوام با اون جنده کوني حرف بزنم - هي -
Be fuckin' nice. Calm.
بهتره خونسرد باشي
Be nice. Don't fuck up in here.
مهربان باش اينجا رو به هم نزن
# I'll throw off my sorrow ##
# I'll throw off my sorrow ##
- Hi, Sam. - Are you out of your fucking mind?
سلام، سام - عقل لعنتيت رو از دست دادي
You tie up our kid and lock the fucking door? Are you out of your mind?
تو به رو بستي و در رو روش قفل کردي عقلتو از دست دادي؟
That's our child. Are you out of your fuckin' mind?
اون به مونه عقل کوفتيت رو از دست دادي؟
It was just for a little while, Sam. The baby-sitter wasn't there.
فقط براي يه مدت کوتاه بود سام رستار به اونجا نبود
I ought to fuckin' have you committed. You fuckin' do that again, I'll...
من بايد بهت معتهد باشم دوباره اين کارو انجام دادي
- I was just gonna be out for a little while. - I should have...
فتم که براي يه مدت کوتاه بود - ... من بايد
- She was asleep. I was gonna be right back... - Listen.
اون خوابيده بود، داشتم بر ميشتم - وش کن -
- Before she even woke up. - Listen, you fuckin' cunt. Listen to me.
قبل از اينکه بيدار بشه - وش کن، احمق، ابله، وش کن
- Fuck you. I was gonna be back... - Let me tell you something.
م شو، من بر ميشتم - بذار يه يزي رو بهت بم -
- Before she woke up. - Listen to me. Listen carefully.
قبل از اينکه بلند بشه - بهم وش بده، مراقب باش -
You ever touch her again, you ever do anything like that again...
اه دوباره بهش دست بزني ... اه دوباره همين کاري کني
I'll fuckin' kill ya, pure and simple.
خيلي راحت ميکشمت
You hear me? Pure and fuckin' simple.
شنيدي ي ميم؟ خيلي راحت
- Why don't you just let me go, Sam? - I'll fuckin' kill you.
را نميزاري برم، سام؟ مي کشمت
- You fuckin' whore. - I'll sign anything you want me to sign.
تو لعنتي هر يزي که ازم خواستي امضا کردم
I just want the key to my jewelry, and I want you to let me go.
فقط کليد جواهراتمو ميخوام و ميخوام که بذاري برم
- You want your jewelry? - I want you to let me go.
جواهراتتو مي خواهي؟ - ميخوام بذاري برم -
And let you disgrace me, you fuckin' pig?
تا منو خار کني خوک کثيف؟
Let you disgrace me? Get up and be a mother.
تا منو تحقير کني؟ بلند شو و يه مادر باش
Get in the car and go to the house right now.
سوار ماشين شو و همين الان برو خونه
Get up and get in the... Get... Get up. Get up!
... بلند شو و سوار شو بلند... بلند شو. بلند شو
- Get up. Get up. - I wouldn't do that if I were you.
بلند شو. بلند شو - نميخوام اه زور کني -
- I wouldn't do that... - Get up!
نميخوام - بلند شو -
- Get the fuck... Are you threatening me?
... نميخوام سوار شو لعنتي... منو تهديد مي کني؟
I'll fuckin' kill you in this place. Get up and go home.
همين جا ميکشمت بلند شو و برو خونه
- I'm going! I'm going! - You...
!ميرم! ميرم ... تو
- Now you need approval from him to go home? - So what?
حالا به اجازه اون براي رفتن به خونه احتياج داري؟ - که ي؟ -
So who fuckin' blew you in the parking lot before you came in?
ه کسي بزرت کرد قبل از اينکه از تو ارکين بياي تو؟
- Huh? - You make me sick, you fuckin'...
ها؟ - ... حالمو بهم ميزني، توه کوني
- Once a fuckin' hooker, always a hooker. - Oh, fuck you!
يه فاحشه، هميشه يه فاحشه ست - اوه، م شو -
- Fuck you, Sam Rothstein! Fuck you! - # I can't get no satisfaction #
لعنت به تو، سام راستين! لعنت به تو - - # I can't get no satisfaction #
# I can't get me no satisfaction #
# I can't get me no satisfaction #
# I can't get no
# I can't get no
- # I can't get me no satisfaction # - Yeah, Billy Sherbert, please.
- # I can't get me no satisfaction # آره، بيلي شربرت، لطفا -
- Who's this? - Billy, listen, I'll explain later.
کي هستي؟ - بيلي، وش کن، بعدا توضيح ميدم -
- You got a gun at home? Bring it over right away. - Yeah.
تو خونت تفن داري؟ بيارش اينجا - آره -
- Take it easy. I'll do it. - Okay.
آروم باش، اين کارو ميکنم - باشه -
# No-no-no-no-no satisfaction #
# No-no-no-no-no satisfaction #
- # No-no-no-no, I can't get me no satisfaction # - Leave it where it is!
- # No-no-no-no, I can't get me no satisfaction # - Leave it where it is!
# I can't get no satisfaction ##
# I can't get no satisfaction ##
Where is he? Goddamn it, I want that Jew bastard killed!
کجاست؟ لعنت بهش ميخوام اون يهودي حرومزاده کشته بشه
Calm down. Shh. Hide her car in the back.
آروم باش، شش ماشينشو اون شت مخفي کن
There's no reason to hide my car! He already knows!
دليلي نداره ماشينمو مخفي کنم الان هم ميدونه
What did I tell you? Supposin' he goes back home and makes a fuckin' beef?
بهت ي فتم؟ فکر کردي ميره خونه و غذا درست ميکنه؟
- I gotta know exactly what you said. Tell me what you said. - Me? I said nothing.
ميخوام بدونم دقيقا ي فتي. بهم بو ي فتي - من؟ هيي نفتم -
I said, "No, no, no. " Everything he said, I just kept saying no.
فتم نه، نه، نه، هر ي مي فت من فقط ميفتم نه
I told you this was fuckin' dangerous.
بهت فتم مي تونه خطرناک باشه
I said, "Ginger, this is a dangerous situation. Be very careful. "
بهت فتم جينجر، اين يه موقعيت خطرناکه خيلي مواظب باش
If it's so fucking dangerous, then why don't you kill him?
اه اينقدر خطرناکه س را نمي کشيش؟
I'm not gonna kill him. Shut the fuck up.
من اونو نمي کشم خفه شو
- Have him killed, and get it over with! - Don't be such a smart-ass!
بايد بکشيش، و از شرش خلاص شي - اينقدر يه الاغ باهوش نباش -
I know the guy 35 years, I'm gonna fuckin' whack him for you?
من 35 ساله اونو ميشناسم اونو به خاطر تو بکشم؟
Motherfucker.
مادرجنده
- I knew this. I knew it. - What about my money?
ميدونستم، ميدونستم - س ول من ي؟ -
How the fuck am I gonna get your money now?
طوري الان ولتو بدم؟
You think he's gonna give you fuckin' money? Are you out of your mind?
فکر ميکني ولتو بهت ميده؟ عقلت رو از دست دادي؟
- Look what you did to this fuckin' guy? - What?
ببين ي سر اون آوردي؟ - ي؟ -
If you would have just kept your fuckin' mouth shut.
اه فقط دهنتو بسته نه ميداشتي
What the fuck is the use! I should've never got involved...
ديه ه سودي داره نبايد هرز خودمو درير ميکردم
Hey! Hey! You motherfucker, you!
هي! هي! مادرجنده
Ow! You fuck! You fucker! Get out! Get the fuck out!
!اوه! توه کوني! توه فاحشه !برو بيرون! ورتو م کن
- No! No! - Get down there! Take it easy!
!نه! نه برو ايين! راحت باش
I should never have gotten involved with this fucking nut!
نبايد خودمو هرز دريراين موضوع مي کردم
You'll fuckin' kill her. Take it easy.
اونو ميکشي آروم باش
- Get her out of here. Get her out of here.
اونو بنداز بيرون
Let's go. Let's go.
بريم. بريم
I don't need you! I'll get my own fucking money!
بهت احتياجي ندارم من خودم ول دارم
- All right. - I'm going to the F.B.I.! I'm not scared anymore!
باشه - ميرم يش اف بي آي! ديه از هيي نميترسم
- All right. Be careful. - You've fucked with me for the last time!
باشه، مواظب باش - آخرين بار بود که با من خوابيدي
Okay. Yeah.
باشه، آره
Be careful. Come on. Get inside.
مواظب باش. زود باش. بيا تو
- Can you believe that? - Look at this motherfucker.
ميتوني باور کني؟ - مادرجنده رو ديدي -
Whew.
عجب
I fucked up, Frankie. I fucked up good this time.
ند زدم، فرانکي تو موقع خوبي ند زدم
I should never have started with this fuckin' broad.
نبايد هرز اين ماجرا رو شروع مي کردم
Take it easy. What could you do?
آروم باش يکار مي تونستي بکني؟
I mean, she threw herself at you, right?
منظورم اينه، اون خودش رو انداخته بود بهت درسته؟
I'm in a bad fuckin' spot here. You know that?
اينجا خيلي تابلوم اينو ميدونستي؟
A bad fuckin' spot.
يه تابلو بد
I'd already left the kid with neighbors...
... به رو يش همسايه ها ذاشتم
and I had about a million in cash and jewels...
و يه ميليون نقد و جواهراتو
that I gave to Sherbert to lock up in the hotel.
دادم به شربرت تا توي او صندوق تو هتل بذاره
Put it in the hotel safe, then I want you to come right back.
تا بعدا که خواستم برش ردونم
- She's alone. Take the gun and go into Amy's...
اون تنهاست اسلحه رو بردار و برو تو اتاق امي
- Wait there for me. Get out here and talk to me!
اونجا منتظر من باش بيا بيرون و باهام صحبت کن
You fuckin' ignore me, you motherfucker!
منو ناديده رفتي !توه مادرجنده
I mean it! Come down here right now!
دارم ميم !بيا بيرون همين الان
Get down here and talk to me, goddamn it!
بيا اينجا و باهام حرف بزن، لعنتي
Fuck you! Goddamn you, come out here!
!لعنت بهت لعنت بهت، بيا اينجا
I'm going to drive your fucking car through the living room!
ميخوام با ماشين از اتاقت رد شم
You fucking coward! You motherfucker!
!تو بزدلي !مادرجنده
- Come out here and talk to me, you fucker! - Will you stop it?
بيا بيرون و باهام حرف بزن کوني - بسش مي کني؟-
- You're drunk. You're on drugs. - I am not!
مشروب زدي، مواد زدي - نه نزدم -
- You're going to be sorry if you don't stop it. - Don't you threaten me!
شيمون ميشي اه بسش نکني - منو تهديد نکن -
You are not threatening me anymore!
نميتوني ديه منو تهديد کني
You fuck! You fuck! I'm sick of you!
!لعنت به تو! لعنت به تو حالم ازت بهم ميخوره
I am fucking Nicky Santoro! I am! He's my new sponsor!
با نيکي سانتورو خوابيدم اون اسانسر جديد منه
How about that, you fuckhead!
اين طوره، مغز وه
What are you looking at? Fuck off!
به ي ناه مي کنيد؟ م شيد
Hey. Go back inside! This is none of your business!
هي، بررد داخل به تو ربطي نداره
I don't have to take your shit all the time anymore!
ديه نميتونم ند کاري هات رو درست کنم
I'm going to the F.B.I.! I will go to the police!
ميرم يش اف بي آي ميرم يش ليس
- I am not protecting you anymore, you fuck! - Mrs. Rothstein... Shh.
ديه ازت حمايت نمي کنم، لعنتي خانم راستين... شش
He won't let me inside!
نميذاره برم تو
Mr. Rothstein, I'm sorry. We've been getting some complaints about the noise.
خانم راستين، متاسفم به ما شکايت هايي راجع به سرو صدا شده
- I'm trying to get in my house. He won't let me in. - I understand.
سعي ميکنم برم داخل، نميذاره برم تو - متوجه ام -
I won't let her in. I'm sorry, Randy, I'm not gonna let her in.
بهش اجازه نميدم، متاسفم رندي بهش اجازه نميدم
- I'm not gonna let her in the way she's behaving. - Not gonna let me in?
به دليل رفتارش اجازه نميدم بياد تو - نميزاري بيام تو؟ -
- Who knows what you're gonna do in there. - What am I gonna do?
کي ميدونه اونجا ميخواد يکار کنه - من ميخوام يکار کنم؟ -
I've been in the same clothes for two days!
دو روزه که يک لباس رو وشيدم
- I want to get a few of my things! Big deal! - Okay.
!ند تا از يزهامو ميخوام! قبوله - باشه -
How about if we just let her in the house to get a few things?
ي ميشه اه اجازه بدين بره تو خونه يزهاشو برداره؟
- This is half her house anyway. - I'm afraid to let her in the house.
به هر حال نصف خونه مال اونه - ميترسم که بره تو خونه -
You aren't afraid, you fucker! - I'm afraid she'll destroy stuff.
!تو نمي ترسي! کوني ميترسم همه يز رو نابود کنه
- Let me in the house! - Hey, hey, hey!
!اجازه بدين بيام تو هي، هي، هي
- Fucker! Fucker! Hold on! Hey! Please!
!کوني! کوني !صبر کن! هي! لطفا
You ought to be afraid, the way you fuckin' treat me!
بايدم بترسي طوري منو تهديد ميکني
- It'll make it easier... - If we let her get her things...
کار راحت تر ميشه - اه اجازه بديم يزهاشو برداره -
- we'll be out of your hair. - If she calms down, I will let her in the house...
اه آروم باشه اجازه ميدم بياد تو
- I am calm! - If she calms down...
!من آرومم - ... اه آروم باشه اجازه ميدم
I will let her in the house for five minutes...
... ميذارم براي 5 دقيقه بياد تو خونه
if you gentlemen will escort her out if she happens to not want to leave.
اه شما آقايون ايشون رو همراهي کنين تا خارج شه اه اتفاقا نخواست اونجا رو ترک کنه
- Can I go in? Can I go in? - That's not a problem.
ميتونم برم تو؟ ميتونم برم تو؟ - مشکلي نيست -
- Jeff, would you go in with her? - Yes. Yes. Fine! Fuck you!
جف، ميتوني باهاش بري تو؟ - !آره، آره، خوبه، لعنت به تو
You wouldn't believe how mean he's been to me. He's locked up most of my important stuff.
باورت نميشه طور باهام رفتار ميکنه تمام يزهاي قيمتيم رو قايم کرده
All my papers and things... I have to get them. So don't let him come up here.
همه مدارک ها و يزهام رو... بايد بردارم س بهش اجازه ندين بياد بالا
I know they're in here in the desk... Fuck.
ميدونم اونا اينجا تو ميز هستن... لعنت
Just pay attention. He could come up here at any time.
فقط مواظب باش ممکنه هر لحظه بياد اينجا
Are you watching for him?
مواظب اون هستي؟
Got 'em.
رفتمش
I don't want her in there more than a few more minutes.
نميخوام بيشتر از ند دقيقه اينجا بمونه
No, it'll just be a couple... We got other things to do too.
... نه فقط يه خورده ديه ما کارهاي ديه اي هم داريم
I'll hurry her up.
ميخوام عجله کنه
- How's everything else besides this? - Fine. Fine.
از اين که بذريم اوضاع طوره؟ - خوبه، خوبه -
- How's your family? - Not bad. In fact, my wife's pregnant again.
خانواده ات طورن؟ - بد نيستن. همسرم دوباره حامله شده -
- Oh, good. Congratulations. - Thanks. Yeah.
اوه، عاليه. تبريک ميم - متشکرم -
We're kind of happy about that.
ما بابتش خيلي خوشحاليم
I just have to get this one more thing and then we can go.
فقط بايد يه يز ديه رو بردارم و بعدش مي تونيم بريم
Shit! Fuck!
Shit! Fuck!
Shit! God!
Shit! God!
Oh, that pisses me off! Don't worry about it.
اه، اين منو عصبي ميکنه ناراحت نباش
And it would be great...
... و خيلي خوب ميشه اه
if you guys could just follow me out of here...
شما آقايون همراه من تا بيرون از اينجا بيايد
because he's been threatening me!
!براي اينکه اون منو تهديد کرده
Take care. Thank you.
مواظب باش. متشکرم
I can't believe this.
نمي تونم باور کنم
I just need to pick up a little cash inside. Could you come with me?
فقط احتياج به مقداري ول نقد دارم ميتونيد با من بيايد داخل؟
- Charlie, you've got to stop her. You've got to stop her. - I'm sorry, Sam.
ارلي، بايد جلوش رو بيري، ميتوني جلوش رو بيري - متاسفم سام
- What can I do? - She's a fuckin' junkie. She's out of her fucking mind!
يکار ميتونم بکنم؟ - اون يه معتاده، اون عقلشو از دست داده
She has the keys. It's still in both your names.
اون کليد رو داره هنوز به نام هر دوي شماست
- Oh! - There's nothing I can do. I'd like to help...
اوه - ... هي کاري نميتونم بکنم، دوست داشتم کمک کنم
- but I can't. - Legally, she can't take that stuff.
ولي نميتونم - قانونا، اون نميتونه اونا رو با خودش ببره
Legally, she can't take that stuff. Half of everything is mine. Ace, listen to me.
قانونا نميتونه اونا رو با خودش ببره نصف اون يزها مال منه، آيس بهم وش کن
- There's nothing I can do. - Half... I'm coming down.
کاري نميتونم بکنم - همين الان ميام اونجا
Shit! Goddamn it!
Shit! Goddamn it!
Um, I'm gonna need a bag. If you could just ask the guy for the big bag.
ام، يه کيف احتياج دارم، اه ميتوني از اين آقايون سوال کن ببين يه کيف بزر دارن
- Go get a bag, man. - Here, here.
برو يه کيف بيار، مرد - بير، بير -
- Lady, I can't take it. - No, you can, you can. You've been so nice to me.
خانم، نميتونم قبول کنم - نه، ميتوني، ميتوني، تو خيلي با من خوب بودي -
- Yes, just hold the top open. All right? And I can...
آره، فقط باز نهش دار باشه؟ ... و من ميتونم
Oh, God, it's him. You have to stop him.
اوه، خدا، خودشه بايد جلوش رو بيرين
He said he was gonna kill me. You should just stop him.
اون فته که من رو ميکشه فقط بايد جلوش رو بيرين
Mr. Roth... Mr. Roth... Mr. Rothstein, wait a minute.
... آقاي راس... آقاي راس آقاي راستين، ند لحظه صبر کنين
Hold on a second. Hey.
يه دقيقه صبر کنين
- She's driving away. There's nothing we can do.
اون رفته نميتونيم کاري کنيم
- There's nothing we can do. - Look, look, look.
کاري نميتونيم بکنيم - ببين، ببين، ببين -
You can't stop her for speeding? Look what she's doing.
نميتوني براي سرعت زياد متوقفش کني؟ ببين يکار کرده
- There's nothing we can do. She had the keys. - She's on the account.
ديه نميتونيم کاري کنيم، اون کليدها رو داره - حساب به اسمشه
- Let's pull her over at that Citgo station. - Okay. Let's do it.
بياين تو ايستاه سيتو متوقفش کنيم - باشه، بريم انجامش بديم -
- We're placing you under arrest for... - For what?
... ما شما رو بازداشت ميکنيم براي - براي ي؟ -
- We're placing you under arrest for aiding and abetting...
ما شما رو بازداشت ميکنيم براي کمک و مشارکت در جرم -
- But I'm just trying to leave.
... شما رو بازداشت ميکنيم براي کمک و مشارکت در جرم ولي من دارم تلاش ميکنم ترکشون کنم
After all the threats and all the bullshit...
بعد از همه اون تهديدها و مزخرفات
it turned out Ginger didn't tell them anything.
جينجر هي ي به اونها نفت
- But, by then, the Feds didn't need her anyway. - But it was mine.
ولي، بعدش، فدرالي ها بهش احتياجي نداشتن - ولي اونها مال منه -
- They had all the pieces they needed. - But I didn't do anything.
اونها هر ي مي خواستن يدا کرده بودن - ولي من هي کاري نکردم -
- Everybody began to tumble, one after the other, like dominoes. - F.B.I.! We have a warrant!
همه شروع به افتادن کردن، يکي بعد از ديري، درست مثل دومينو
Between Piscano complaining on the wire...
... به خاطر ناله کردن هاي يسکانو از طريق شنود مکالمات
between Nicky, Ginger, me and my license...
... بين نيکي، جينجر، من، و جوازم
- Paradise. We managed to really fuck it all up.
مديريت بهشتمون واقعا نابود شد
- Mom. - Yeah, someone's at the fuckin' door now.
مامان - بله، يکي الان جلوي دره
F.B.I. We have a federal search warrant.
اف بي آي، ما اجازه تفتيش داريم
I got wind of the pinches coming down, so I took off.
فهميدم که دوران سختي در راهه واسه همين قايم شدم
Who needs to hang around for that bullshit?
ه کسي احتياج به اين مزخرفات داره
- My name is Mark Casper. Special Agent F.B.I. - Yeah?
اسم من مارک کاسره، مامور ويژه اف بي آي - آره -
- Can I make a fuckin' phone call? - Hey, hold it a minute.
ميتونم يه تلفن کنم - هي،ند لحظه صبر کن -
You can make a phone call, but you don't have to talk to us like that.
ميتوني تلفن کني ولي تو نبايد اينطوري با ما صحبت کني
Everybody, out of the room. Over to the alarm.
همه، بيرون از اتاق آژير رو قطع کن
They got almost everybody else. - This area is seized!
اونها تقريبا همه رو رفتن - !اين محل در اختيار ماست
- Get the master account list. - I want all those papers seized regardless of what they are.
صورت حساب هاي اصلي رو بير - ميخوام همه ي درمورد اون کاغذها معلوم بشه
Put every box on the table.
همه جعبه ها روي ميز
Ah, yes. Here we are. Little craps figures.
آره، اينجاست آمار و ارقام قمارهاي کويک
Green? Don't even ask.
رين؟ حتي سوال هم نکرد
- $30,000 of yours. - No, he didn't. That's why it wasn't valid.
سيصد هزار دلار از شما - نه، مال اون نيست، براي همينه که ارزش نداره
I was being extorted. I'm willing to tell you whatever you want to know.
از من مصادره شد ميخوام هر ي که ميخواي بدوني بهت بم
- I've got nothing to hide here. - Now for the best.
اينجا يزي براي مخفي کردن ندارم
I couldn't believe this shit. Piscano's expense reports took the cake.
نمي تونم باور کنم زارشهاي مالي يسکانو کار دست همه داد
- Oh, this is good. Bingo. - He might as well have given them a fuckin' blueprint.
اوه، اين عاليه - اون حتما بايد کي شو به اونها داده باشه
Everybody's names, addresses, dates, everything.
اسامي همه، آدرس ها تاريخ ها، همه ي
Look at this. Thank you so much, Mr. Piscano. How considerate of you.
اينو ناه، خيلي متشکرم آقاي يسکانو، قدر آينده نريد
- Those are my mother's books. - You're under arrest.
اونا کتاب هاي مادرم هستن - شما بازداشتين -
What a fuckin' balloon-head. - What are you guys doing?
ه کله وکي - شما آقايون يکار ميکنين؟ -
- Take it easy. - Wait!
آروم باش - صبر کن -
- Wait a minute! He's sick! Oh, God! - Move back.
!يه لحظه صبر کن! اوه، خدايا برين عقب -
- I think it's his heart! Oh, God! Is he breathing? - C.P.R. Now!
فکر کنم قلبشه! اوه، خدايا، نفس ميکشه؟ - کمک هاي اوليه -
Poor Artie. He got so upset, he had a heart attack...
بياره آرتي، اونقدر ناراحت شده بود که جلوي زنش سکته قلبي کرد
and dropped dead right in front of his wife.
و درست جلوي زنش مُرد
- Calm down! - Artie! No, I won't calm down!
آروم باش - آرتي، نه، نميخوام آروم باشم -
- He's my husband! Artie! Artie! - We can't help him if...
!اون شوهرمه! آرتي! آرتي ... نمي تونيم کمکش کنيم
And at the end of the day...
... و درايان روز
they finally came to see me with the pictures.
اونا بالاخره با عکس ها اومدن و منو ديدن
Why protect a friend who betrayed you like that?
را از دوستي که اونطوري بهت خيانت کرده حمايت مي کني؟
But I didn't want to look at them.
ولي من نمي خواستم به اونا ناه کنم
I didn't want to look at the guys who brought them either.
حتي نمي خواستم به کسي که اونا رو آورده ناه کنم
Your Honor, as you can see, my clients are elderly and infirm.
عاليجناب، همانطور که مي بينيد موکلان من ير و ناتوان هستن
Any incarceration could pose a serious health risk.
هر ونه زندان ميتونه باعث صدمه جدي به سلامتي اونها بشه .
When the bosses were arrested, some of them were so old...
وقتي رئيس ها دستير شدن ... بعضي از اونها اونقدر ير بودن
they needed doctors at their arraignment.
که براي حضور در داداه به دکتر احتياج داشتن
Pre-trial Services recommends that bail remain as presently set.
خدمات يش از محاکمه توصيه کرد که به قيد ضمانت آزاد باشن
- We're going to take a recess. - When it looked like they could get...
تنفس اعلام ميشه
25 years to life in prison just for skimmin' a casino...
بيست و نج سال زندان فقط براي ارتباط با کازينو
sick or no fuckin' sick, you knew people were going to get clipped.
بيمار يا غيره بيمار، ميدوني که مردم کجا ميرن
So, the day of the arraignment, they had this meeting right in the back of the courthouse.
بنابراين، روز حضور در داداه، اونا اين جلسه رو درست شت داداه ترتيب دادن
See, when something like this happens, you know how things are gonna work out.
مي بيني، وقتي اتفاقي مثل اين رخ ميده ميفهمي که بعضي از يزها طور اتفاق ميفته
It's always better with no witnesses. So what about Andy?
هميشه بدون مدرک بهتره س اندي ي؟
He won't talk. Stone is a good kid.
اون حرفي نميزنه استون به خوبيه
Stand-up guy just like his old man.
فقط مثل يه يرمرده
That's the way I see it.
من اوضاعو اين طور مي بينم
I agree. He's solid. He's a fuckin' Marine.
قبول دارم، اون سرسخته اون يه ملوانه
He's okay. He always was. Remo, what do you think?
اون خوبه، هميشه همينطور بوده ريمو تو ي فکر ميکني؟
Look... why take a chance?
ببين... را يه امتحاني نکنيم؟
At least, that's the way I feel about it.
حداقل اين تنها راهيه که احساسش مي کنم
Call Artie. Tell him, I don't care what...
با آرتي تماس بيريد، بهش بين ... من اهميتي نميدم
- he's got to be in my office Thursday morning before 11:00. - It's done.
اون قبل ازساعت 11 صبح نج شنبه تو دفتر من خواهد بود قضيه تموم شده ست
It's terribly important. I gotta have a conversation with that guy...
خيلي مهمه من بايد صحبتي با اون داشته باشم
As much as they liked him, I mean, he wasn't one of us.
هر ند که دوستش داشتم بازم اون يکي از ما نبود
He wasn't Italian. As far as they knew, he could have talked.
اون ايتاليايي نبود، تا اونجا که خبر داشتم ميتونست صحبت کنه
Otherwise, Stoney might still be alive.
ورنه استوني هنوزم زنده بود
The first one to skip was John Nance.
اولين کسي که در رفت جان نانس بود
He found a nice, warm, secluded place in Costa Rica.
اون يه جاي قشن و رم تو کاستاريکا يدا کرد
- He thought nobody would find him there.
فکر ميکرد هي کس اونجا يداش نميکنه
But then his kid got nabbed by the Feds for drugs.
ولي بعد به اش دستير شد به وسيله ماموران مواد مخدر
So, naturally, the bosses were afraid he'd come out of hiding...
بنابراين، طبيعي بود که، رئيس ها مي ترسيدن که اون از مخفياش بياد بيرون
just to save his kid and give them all up.
فقط به اش رو نجات دادن و بقيه اش رو ول کردن
So...
... س
Where you goin', jag-off?
کجا ميري، کثافت؟
But, anyway, they all had to follow.
ولي به هر صورت همه اونا بايد تعقيب بشن
Everybody went down.
همه از بين رفتن
Fuck you.
Fuck you.
Before you knew it...
... قبل از اينکه بدوني
anybody who knew anything wound up gettin' whacked.
هر کسي ميدونست هر يزي که ضربه بخوره از بين ميره
Oh, no! No! No!
!اوه، نه! نه! نه
After Ginger took off, she wasn't much help to anybody.
بعد از مدتي جينجرخاموش شد اون کمکي براي هي کس نبود
She found some pimps, lowlifes, druggies and bikers in L.A.
اون تعدادي از ولردها رو يدا کرد فروشندان مواد و دورخه سواران لس آنجلس
In a few months, they went through all the money and all the jewels.
در عرض ند ماه، اونها تمام ول و جواهراتش رو از نش در آوردن
After they found her body...
... بعد از اينکه بدنش يدا شد
I had a private doctor do another autopsy.
از يه دکتر خصوصي خواستم يه کالبد شکافي ديه انجام بده
He said they gave her a hot dose.
اون فت، اونا بيش از حد مواد بهش داده بودن
In the end, all she had left was 3,600 in mint condition coins.
و در آخر، همه يزي که براش موند 3600 تا بود در حد ول خرد
No matter what the Feds or the papers might have said about my car bombing...
مهم نيست ماموران فدرال يا روزنامه ها ... در مورد بمب ذاري ماشين من فته باشن
it was amateur night, you could tell.
ميتوني بي کار يه آماتور شب بوده
Whoever it was, they put the dynamite under the passenger side.
هر کسي که بوده ديناميت رو سمت کمک راننده ذاشته بود
But what they didn't know, what nobody outside the factory knew...
ولي اونا و هي کس ديه اي ... به جز کارخونه سازنده اش نميدونست که
was that that model car was made with a metal plate under the driver's seat.
اين مدل ماشين داراي ورقه فولادي در قسمت زيرين راننده ست
It's the only thing that saved my life.
تنها اون باعث نجات زندي من شد
The bombing was never authorized, but I suspect I know who lit the fuse.
بمب ذاري هرز به عهده رفته نشد ولي ميدونم ه کسي فيوز رو زده
- Hey, Nicky. And so did the powers that be.
هي، نيکي - بنابراين قدرت خودش رو نشون داد
- How are you? - How you doin'?
حالت طوره؟ - طوري؟ -
It took months for everything to calm down.
ماهها طول کشيد تا همه ي آروم بشه
But, finally, my guys got out on bail...
ولي در آخر ... افرادم به قيد وثيقه آزاد شدن
and the bosses wanted me to send my brother Dominick out to Vegas.
و رئيس ها ازم خواستن که برادرم دامينيک رو به واس بفرستم
Always the dollars. Always the fuckin' dollars.
هميشه دلار مهمه هميشه دلار لعنتي مهمه
I mean, it was still way too hot for me to even go near Vegas.
منظورم اينه که، هنوز هم لاس واس برام جذابه
So I set up a meeting with the guys way out in the sticks.
س ملاقاتي ترتيب دادم تا بتونم راه حلي براي خروج از بحران يدا کنم
I didn't want my brother to get fucked around. I mean, what's right is right.
نميخوام برادرم اين اطراف بلايي سرش بياد منظورم اينه که، يزي که درسته، درسته
They don't give a fuck about...
... اونا اهميتي به اين موضوع نميدن
Holy fuckin'!
!لعنتي
What the fuck...
ه خبره؟
Come on, motherfucker!
بيا جلو، مادرجنده
- Tough guys! You and your fuckin' brother!
سن دل ها تو و اون برادر کونيت
- You fuckin' scumbags! No more!
شما يه سري احمقين نه بيشتر
- Frankie! - No more! You see? Watch!
!فرانکي !نکن، ببين، ناه کن
- Frankie! Frankie! You piece of shit! - Fuck you, you motherfucker!
فرانکي! فرانکي! تو يه تکه وهي - لعنت بهت، مادرجنده -
Fuckin' punk, motherfucker! Piece of shit!
کوني بي ارزش مادرجنده آشغال
No, no, no, no!
!نه! نه! نه! نه
Take this motherfucker out!
!اين مادرجنده رو بنداز بيرون
Frankie, leave the kid alone. He's still breathing.
فرانکي، اون به رو تنها بذار هنوز داره نفس ميکشه
Leave him alone. Frankie.
تنهاش بذار، فرانکي
All right. Strip him.
خب، لختش کن
No balls. You got no fuckin' balls.
تخمشو نداري تخم لعنتيش رو نداري
Ah, Dominick. Ah, Dom.
اه، دامنيک، اه، دامنيک
Dominick. Dominick.
دامنيک، دامنيک
Dominick.
دامنيک
Oh, Dominick.
اه، دامنيک
Come on, come on.
بيا، بيا
- Bury them? - Bury them.
دفنشون کنم؟ - دفنشون کن -
The word was out.
داستان تموم شد
The bosses had enough of Nicky. They had enough.
رئيس ها به اندازه کافي از نيکي سير شده بودن اونا بسشون بود
How much were they gonna take? So they made an example of him and his brother.
قدر مي خوان بردارن؟ بنابراين اونها از اون و برادرش سرمشقي ساختن
- They buried them while they were still breathing.
اونها دفن شدن در حالي که هنوز نفس ميکشيدن
Mister, you all right? Watch out!
آقا حالتون خوبه؟ مواظب باش
- Mister, you all right? - Yeah.
آقا، حالتون خوبه؟ - آره -
They had other ideas for me.
اونها نقشه هاي ديه اي براي من داشتن
We need some help over here!
!اينجا به کمک احتياج داريم
You sure are lucky, mister.
شما خيلي خوش شانسين آقا
The town will never be the same.
شهر ديه هرز اينجور نموند
After the Tangiers, the big corporations took it all over.
بعد از تنجير شرکت هاي بزر همه جا رو رفتن
Today it looks like Disneyland.
امروز مثل ديزني لند شده
And while the kids play cardboard pirates...
و وقتي به ها بازي دزد دريايي ميکنن
Mommy and Daddy drop the house payments and Junior's college money...
مادرها و درها، هزينه رداختي هاي خونه ... و ول هاي کالج رو
on the poker slots.
سر وکر مي بازن
In the old days, dealers knew your name, what you drank, what you played.
در روزهاي قديم، مديرها اسم شما رو ميدونستن اينکه ي مي نوشيد، ي بازي ميکنين
Today, it's like checkin' into an airport.
امروز مثل ذيرش فروداه ها شده
And if you order room service, you're lucky if you get it by Thursday.
و اه سرويس اتاق رو درخواست کني اه خيلي شانس بياري نج شنبه اين کارو ميکنن
Today it's all gone. You got a whale show up with four million in a suitcase...
امروز همه اون يزها رفته، اه ميخواي يه نهن باشي بايد 4 ميليون تو مدانت داشته باشي
and some 25-year-old hotel school kid is gonna want his social security number.
و بعضي از به مدرسه اي هاي هتل 25 ساله قديمي تازه ميخوان کد ملي مخصوصشون رو بيرن
After the Teamsters got knocked out of the box...
... بعد از اينکه بزران از صفحه خارج شدن
the corporations tore down practically every one of the old casinos.
شرکتها تمام کازينو هاي قديمي رو ند کليده کردن
And where did the money come from to rebuild the Pyramids?
ول ها از کجا براي ساختن اهرام تامين شدن؟
Junk bonds.
باندهاي بنجل
Still not sure?
هنوز مطمئن نيستي؟
Probable. Maybe questionable.
احتمالا، شايد، قابل رسش باشه
Let me know as soon as you can find out.
هر موقع فهميدين به من هم بين
But in the end, I wound up right back where I started.
ولي در ايان به همون جا که شروع کردم برشتم
I could still pick winners...
... هنوز هم برنده ها رو حدس ميزنم
and I could still make money for all kinds of people back home.
و هنوزم دارم ول ميسازم براي مردمي که اونجان
And why mess up a good thing?
و را همين يز خوبي رو از دست بدم؟
And that's that.
و همينه که هست
# Sometimes I wonder why I spend the lonely nights #
# Sometimes I wonder why I spend the lonely nights #
# Dreaming of a song #
# Dreaming of a song #
# The melody haunts my memory #
# The melody haunts my memory #
# And I am once again with you #
# And I am once again with you #
# When our love was new #
# When our love was new #
# And each kiss an inspiration #
# And each kiss an inspiration #
# Ah, but that was long ago #
# Ah, but that was long ago #
# And now my consolation #
# And now my consolation #
# Is in the stardust of a song #
# Is in the stardust of a song #
# Beside a garden wall #
# Beside a garden wall #
# When stars were bright #
# When stars were bright #
# And you were in my arms #
# And you were in my arms #
# The nightingale told his fairy tale #
# The nightingale told his fairy tale #
# Of paradise #
# Of paradise #
# Where roses grew #
# Where roses grew #
# Though I dream in vain #
# Though I dream in vain #
# In my heart #
# In my heart #
# It will remain #
# It will remain #
# My stardust melody #
# My stardust melody #
# The memory #
# The memory #
# Of love's refrain ##
# Of love's refrain ##